So, it's basically us UPloaders getting together.
Shared an internal experience exchange
and I took some photos around the venue
Let's take a look at the hotel.
Everyone can check out the previous episode on my page.
In this episode, we'll continue discussing social persuasion.
What exactly is social persuasion?
This is another new term brought to you by Brother Rong.
It means shaping individuals according to societal norms.
Look at the mental attitudes of us Gen X and Millennials,
compared to Gen Z,
the attitudes of Gen Z are completely different.
It's clear that people from the 80s
carried a sense of endurance and resilience from the old era
humility
and a deep understanding of etiquette and manners
What I'm saying isn't a commendatory term.
What I'm talking about are actually derogatory words.
because in our time
how can I put it
nowadays, people can actually speak their minds
It's like this
The 1980s were actually more open than the 1990s
In terms of ideology
Many aspects of culture and humanities
This was due to the complex international situation
We won't delve into it
Why the 1980s were more open
But this openness in the 1980s had a bit of a backfire
A backfire
That was when people's thoughts
Sometimes it doesn't keep up with the current productive force levels
Many people became extremely infatuated with foreign things.
That's why I went all out back then.
People born in the sixties and seventies
People of that era
Those from the sixties and seventies
They went through the 1980s
Reform and Opening up
The initial period after the Reform and Opening up was one of prosperity and vitality.
There was a more comprehensive trend towards Westernization.
People of that era,
generally speaking, were not convinced by the 1990s.
But for those born in the 1980s,
like me, who started school in 1990,
or those who started in 1991,
the education of the 1990s,
for us, felt like a process of looking back.
When it comes to our education,
the focus on ideology is still quite tight,
which, of course, has its positive aspects,
but it also has negative impacts.
As a result, many of the people who are educated this way tend to be,
very obedient,
very rule-abiding,
very, how should I put it,
attentive to honor and disgrace.
But this matter has its pros and cons.
You need to understand that people survive in society,
and they face different societies,
they adopt different mental states.
Now we live in an urban commercial society,
so some things that showcase individuality,
and the initiative of the individual,
are appropriate.
In ancient collective agricultural societies,
Some things are just too unique.
They don't fit in.
So this concept is about how things change over time.
This is a social convention among people
including moral values,
what is considered just in society,
what should be done,
the public's understanding of moral standards,
are constantly shifting and evolving.
Given that the urbanization rate is now very high
in many cases
from the clan-based rural society
to the current rural society
many people have completed
and through the college entrance exam, they have achieved urbanization
many aspects of their lives have transformed
gradually transforming into nuclear families
like my family, which comes from a rural area in Yunnan, right
Then, after entering the city,
everyone has their own profession,
their own division of labor,
and their own distinct residences.
Production is no longer centralized,
so each household has become an atomic family.
In an atomic family, there’s no need to talk about feudal nonsense,
or the hierarchical relationships like ruler and subject, father and son.
So the level of productive force in the new era has improved.
So it's different
But in the 80s, there were many materials
When we talk about those things
In the 90s, there were a lot of social elements left
Actually, there were quite a few
It makes you feel, how should I put it
Compliant with the rules
At the same time, it restricts some of your freedoms
Freedoms of thought
Freedom of action
makes you particularly obedient
Often, it will restrict the development of your personal thoughts
Many things are like this
He said slowly
To be honest
Whenever he wants to establish a so-called noble virtue
He has to take something away
So people often say
If someone has never been fully influenced by this education system,
then they might not have been affected by it at all.
Let me explain.
Of course, they might be somewhat lacking culturally,
they might be homeschooled,
learning from what their parents teach them,
but they wouldn't be influenced by these social norms.
However, they would be lacking in socialization.
They might be less adept in social situations.
So, what exactly makes something natural?
That's hard to say.
But as Generation 80s, we were essentially the guinea pigs.
The truly outstanding generation is the 90s kids.
And the 00s kids.
Why do we say the 90s and 00s generations are more excellent?
Because their parents' generation is quite different from ours.
They are different from our grandparents' generation.
Most of the 80s generation's grandparents had experienced war, right?
Well, our parents' generation, some of them even fought in wars.
In the 80s, going to war in Vietnam was quite common.
So, in many cases,
for people from the 60s and 70s,
after getting an education,
they went into business,
and they seized the benefits of their era.
By the 90s,
it was when they were in their twenties and thirties that they made their money.
But for the parents from the post-50s generation,
they were already quite old by then,
with fewer opportunities available.
They also had children to take care of.
So,
those born in the 90s,
or after the 90s,
especially the post-95s and the 00s generation,
many have achieved considerable economic success.
Someone with a wealth of knowledge
Because he was born after 1978
High school students who emerged after the restoration of the national unified examination for admissions to general universities and colleges in 1978.
So compared to people from the 1950s
Like my dad, who was born in 1954
And my mom, who was born in 1955, and many others
He actually went through things like being sent to the countryside
Or serving in the military
Or started working in a factory quite early
You see, my dad has 40 years of work experience
He started at the factory when he was 15
My mom joined the military at 16
So in terms of education
To put it bluntly, he didn’t even finish high school
He didn’t go to high school
He left after junior high to start learning a trade
And that’s how he started working
So his ability to learn
is related to economic status
and when you consider the older generation
who were involved in wars
their level of education was relatively lower
which affects their cognition and thinking
making it more challenging
unlike people from the 90s
when it comes to certain aspects
How could he put it?
We need to speak from our perspective.
A bit more advanced.
A bit more free-spirited, you know.
Not to mention the Gen Zers.
Many of the parents of Gen Zers might be from the Gen X cohort.
For example, my peers
They had Gen Z kids in their twenties.
But those from the seventies were different.
So, to talk about it
you're saying you were born in 09
I could very well be your dad
right?
That's how it is
You were born in 05
I was already 18 in 02
By 09, I was already 25
So if you were born between 05 and 09
Bro Rong might really be your dad.
Hehe, I don't just go around saying things like that to people.
Calling someone my son or something like that.
Because what you say might just come true, you know.
It could become reality, right?
It’s possible, isn’t it?
Who knows, right?
You get the point.
My moral standards aren’t that high either.
This person has a wide circle of friends.
In fact, during that active era,
Who knows what peculiar stories might unfold?
So the key point is,
A Generation has its own Shangganling
A generation has its own way of thinking
How to put it,
the general trend is like this.
So each generation surpasses the last.
Firstly, I believe each generation is stronger than the last.
To surpass the limitations of your time,
you must understand that people from other generations have different experiences in society,
and their experiences are entirely different from your subjective feelings.
When we talk about Gen Z,
or the iGen,
let's not even compare with others.
Just take military enthusiasts for example,
compared to the military enthusiasts from the 80s.
Can the feeling be the same?
Right?
With all this advanced equipment now
So to speak
It's not expensive, to put it bluntly
No, not that
But there were so many things we had to endure in the past
The Chinese embassy in the Federal Republic of Yugoslavia was bombed
Often, it refers to the Yinhe Incident.
This all brings back memories of our childhood.
So, for us,
he has this sense of enduring hardship and bearing a heavy burden.
For people of our generation,
there wasn't such a strong emphasis on individual development.
Except for someone like Han Han,
everyone thought they were defying conventions.
they were already quite something,
but looking at it now,
Look at what Han Han does
There's nothing particularly suspicious about it.
Right, those are things everyone would do
But speaking of our generation and after
Speaking of our generation,
When it comes to certain aspects
They are a generation that bridges the past and the future
They serve as the connecting link between generations
He bears the shadow of the previous generation.
There's also the dawn for the next generation.
So these things are completely different
So when we talk about social persuasion
You need to understand your era
So you need to know the characteristics of your era
What the burdens of the times are
This is an inevitable thing
But speaking of our generation
We've encountered something very good, and that is
When we were young
When we grew up
We were exposed to games
We were exposed to computers
We were exposed to many advanced cultural models
So we have a good understanding of culture
Of creativity
Of the aspiration for this kind of art
It's really great
So you see, I write books.
Some of my friends play in bands
They make music.
This is a kind of cultural expression,
a longing for freedom,
and a yearning for art.
People can't exist without these spiritual nourishments.
But for our generation, there are many constraints in various aspects,
especially when it comes to personalization.
There's no doubt that the post-90s and post-00s are stronger.
Let's not talk about our generation then.
Just take cosplay for example.
Back then, when we played cosplay, it was a lot more socially challenging.
How can I put it?
The lack of understanding from parents,
and the lack of understanding from society.
Now, it's not really an issue at all.
Is it even an issue now?
Now I'm going out in my cosplay outfit
Taking the subway is no big deal
Everyone finds it quite normal
No one stares at you
No one is constantly accusing you of taking secret photos or anything
Back in 2003 and 2004
Can you give it a try?
I attended my first comic convention in 2003
It felt like we had to do everything secretly
It’s not easy for everyone to gather like this
Wow, there’s actually a gathering
And there’s even an opportunity
For everyone to interact
That’s right
It’s quite unusual
The sense of stealth is particularly strong
Unlike now, where almost anyone can just put on a costume
And consider themselves a cosplayer
Let's not comment on that.
But overall, society is changing.
Society is constantly innovating.
Society is becoming more open.
Society is moving forward.
So the feeling is completely different.
So when we talk about a lot of people today,
they tend to impose more restrictions on themselves.
This is the mark of the times.
So we say a lot of things in this context
Due to the existence of the education system
Because of these things
For the majority of people
It involves going through various social systems
To become a part of society
How should I put it
In a functional state
In a state of being the workforce
This is the overarching trend in society.
But if you have the willpower,
and the intention to take the initiative in this society,
you need to go against the social trends that influence you,
against the advice,
against the influences,
you need to be a rebel,
you need to make choices different from the era,
different from others.
It's important to find a path that suits you.
This is crucial.
And I feel that
More and more parents nowadays are unwilling to push their children into the rat race of academics.
Instead, they encourage them to find a path that suits them.
When we talk about the world at large,
Becoming a scientist,
Becoming an engineer,
Becoming a doctor
Being a lawyer is a very honorable profession.
But that doesn't mean becoming an artist
or a businessman
or a young actor
or a small craftsman
or an individual entrepreneur is something to be ashamed of.
So this was the attitude of that era.
For college students
and for intellectuals
An aspiration for the cadre status
A romanticization
A tribute
A choice made by many
Because cadres and college graduates earn more money
But in today's context
A college degree might not be as valuable
From the perspective of labor surplus
We need to delve into this issue further
What should I contribute to this socio-economic environment?
This is the mindset of the new era.
It's already 2025 now.
A quarter of the 21st century has passed.
So many people's lives and moods are still stuck in the 1990s.
Still stuck in the 2000s.
But in reality, 40 years have gone by.
Yes, 40 years have passed.
Right?
So, from a physiological standpoint
As someone from the 80s
I feel that sometimes my mindset is more open than those from the 90s
Maybe even more so
Let's be honest
The specific reasons
We won't delve into further
It's not really worth discussing
Because it's all in the past
So discussing these things today
The dynamics of cultural and international relations
Have a lasting impact on an era
And on individuals
They all have an influence
This is the most interesting part
So many times, people need to learn to reflect
Not the kind of reflection that blames
But to learn to see the small things in oneself
When it comes to me, don't be so fixated.
I shouldn't be so fixated on what I believe is right as being absolutely right
I shouldn't be so fixated on what my generation believes is right as being absolutely right
This is something that can be debated
Each generation should be stronger than the last
Each generation should be better than the previous one
So in many ways
The times are moving forward relentlessly
Let me tell you
I really envy today's young people
And I will always envy the young people of my time
I never think any generation of young people is weaker than the previous one
But to be honest, each generation has its own sacrifices
But to be honest, every generation has its own spirit of sacrifice.
We were the guinea pigs
We were a generation of experiments
So it's normal that many from the 80s faced more hardships
That's quite natural
But for our generation
We need to learn from the new generation
We need to learn from the various qualities of the new generation
Not being burdened by outdated thoughts is crucial
You should grow younger as you live
So don't carry the burden of old thoughts
Don't conform to societal norms
There are many pieces of advice for you
There are many of these things
If you don't want to become that kind of person
Then don't make that choice
This is what I feel today