left these Yage Hotel tissues behind.
Then, for these 17 minutes, they also gave me a high-speed train meal.
Thanks to Fuzhou Railway Bureau.
This is my backpack.
Inside are two books I wrote
for two UPloaders in Hangzhou and Shanghai
and one has already been given away
to the Bilibili staff
and this is the toothbrush from the previous hotel
as expected, the new hotel here didn't provide a toothbrush
but it's all good
and they told us there weren't enough king rooms available
so we ended up in a standard room
But this standard room is quite spacious.
It’s more like a suite.
Not exactly a suite, though.
Anyway, there’s also a sofa.
It’s pretty good.
You can sit here to eat or something.
That’s how it looks.
This is me leaving the hotel.
The hotel is really great.
a resort or summer retreat
there's a river nearby
the entire city is like a huge park
tomorrow's venue is close by
I'll take a little stroll around
the environment is really great
how about the overall
atmosphere is particularly comfortable
this is also my participation in a Bilibili event
How many times has this been now?
There was one time in Xiamen before.
That was in the Streamer Zone.
And it was back in 2024.
This year, there was a fan meet-up that was a key event.
It was organized really well for me.
I also came to Bilibili to say hello and introduce myself.
I’ve come twice on my own expense to pay respects.
I forgot the reason for those visits.
Well, I volunteered to come over.
It’s a business meeting, after all.
I need to be proactive.
This place is actually like many ancient towns.
Yes.
But the crowd here is pretty good.
There are a lot of tourists.
It feels different from other ancient towns.
Wuzhen, after all, has the Opera Festival.
There are all sorts of activities.
So the overall experience is pretty good.
But after getting off the high-speed train,
it takes about a 40-minute drive to get there.
Forty minutes is quite a while.
But our travel expenses are reimbursed.
Hehe, not bad.
Still, it’s Bilibili covering the cost for second-class seats.
I really can’t stand second-class seats.
I said forget it.
I'll just buy it myself.
But the Didi expenses were still reimbursed, though.
But it doesn't really matter.
A hundred or two is not much.
The CCTV channel has been very helpful to me.
It's also a significant source of revenue for many Bilibili creators.
And it's the main source of income for UPloaders.
So it's actually quite powerful.
We all agreed to come.
Let's check out the others tomorrow.
Of course, the internal meeting can't be shared.
But we can still take a look before and after the meeting.
I'll take some shots of the bridge station for everyone.
Don't go too far.
It doesn't feel safe.
The scenery here is so beautiful with the water.
Coming here alone is quite something.
I have no idea where the hell we are
Whatever, just take a look
This is an ancient Greek theater
An open-air theater
Pretty interesting
Let me take some photos for everyone
Look, there are a bunch of girls in Hanfu behind us
What the hell is worth taking photos of this thing
There's no performance right now
Now it's just this pool of water
I'm still wondering who made it so
I feel like I look pretty ugly in photos taken on the street
It might be due to the people, not the machine
I'm sure I wouldn't see other UPs here otherwise
I'm just wandering around by myself
Actually, the event starts tomorrow
But I can already check in today
But I'm the only one here right now
I think there are a few people who follow me, whether we're close or not.
But they're all big names, so they might not bother to respond to me.
But I'm the kind of person who likes to make friends with others.
I've added many other UPs on WeChat.
But even if you add someone on WeChat,
you don't always chat with them,
so you don't really have much to talk about.
Like, you need to have something in common.
I think it's the boss's experience.
I'm not sure when there will be a performance.
Let's just treat it like a park visit.
Which way should we go?
You suggest we check this one out.
The surroundings are pretty nice.
Catch a bit of the breeze.
We've also visited the hotel.
It doesn't really matter.
Don't rush, let's wait a bit.
I'll call someone later
Have a few people come over for me
There are also many people shooting
Most of them are in full makeup
I'll go check it out; all the ancient towns across the country are pretty much the same
Hmm, not bad at all
How did it fall over again?
But let's move on to the next scene
Hehe, I feel like having a proper coffee
I have no idea if there are any chain stores or not
I’m not sure if the coffee is any good
It should be fine
We can take a boat
It seems a bit awkward
There are quite a few people
There’s a hotel here too
There are some bars inside the hotel as well
But this area seems a bit more something
I feel like we're in Houhai, um
There’s no one around, no friends
Who could this be with?
If one person comes again, what illness might they get?
Hmm hmm hmm
It doesn’t matter
Such a nice hotel
It’s fine not to use it either
Isn’t it about this person?
I’m thinking of going back, you know.
There are quite a few elderly people here.
Most of them are seniors.
Young people, yeah.
It’s all good.
What if you fall into the river while hiding there?
What would you do then?
Older folks really enjoy taking photos.
Young people like us in this profession.
I can't help but take photos
but to be honest, I find it quite annoying
taking photos wherever I go
really
I won't venture further in
this street seems to go on endlessly
wow
I want to get back to the hotel as soon as possible
let me just take a quick look
There seems to be a station over here
Alright, I'll just walk then
I'm out of energy
I'm getting ready to head back to the hotel
Hmph, just bored
It's crowded everywhere
There are quite a few elderly people
I didn't see many pretty girls either
Well
Alright, back to the hotel
Once back at the hotel, I'll start recording today's show
I don't use silicone sealant very often
I sold my Pocket 3
Now I have the Action 5 Pro
It's cheaper and waterproof
It performs well in various conditions
And it's mainly more discreet
The DJI Osmo feels quite big when you're holding it
When going out, it's better to bring a sports camera
This spot is pretty good
The scenery is absolutely beautiful
Yeah, it's nice