I bought such a small car with this range.
I used to think I could get a BYD Qin L.
Is this range from a hybrid system?
Is this called an extended-range or a hybrid?
I don't really know either.
It has a range of over 2200km, which is great.
But later, I was pleasantly surprised to learn that
in Beijing,
only pure electric vehicles are considered new energy vehicles here.
I'm not sure how it works in other provinces and cities.
but the probability of winning a regular fuel car license plate in Beijing is
only 0.1%.
Everyone knows that using condoms
still leaves a 3% chance of pregnancy.
That means the probability of unexpectedly becoming a father is 30 times higher than winning the Beijing license plate lottery.
It's such a magical process.
I've been on the waiting list for a family license plate for 5 years.
Finally, I got a new energy vehicle license plate.
And I was lucky enough to win the draw on May 28th this year.
That's how it went.
Actually, I could have bought a car next year, around the Spring Festival.
My parents and I had already discussed it.
We planned to buy the car next Spring Festival.
Next Spring Festival, if I buy a car, I definitely won't buy it from a gold shop.
But I ended up buying a motorcycle.
I was really excited.
I think buying a motorcycle is a pretty good idea.
So, I decided to go ahead and buy a car as well.
And the Geely Panda Knight is just perfect.
The 210km range is really great.
During the drive back today,
I noticed something interesting about the drive.
This is at least 40 kilometers, right?
Hehe, but we're not dissing the car.
I have the air conditioning set pretty high.
Because it's particularly hot today.
So, the range has dropped by 70 kilometers.
It's down by 37%.
There's still 63% left.
It was fully charged when we started.
And now it's dropped by 37%.
It really breaks my heart
I mean, during the summer
the actual range of this car
is probably between 135km and 149km
and the car kindly reminds us that using the heater in winter will significantly increase energy consumption
which means the energy consumption can reach 30%
it’s only 10% in the summer
so we need to factor that in
so I think the range will drop a bit more in winter
This is the downside of small batteries.
But there is an upside, though.
Because now we can understand the rankings on CarDi.
This Beijing Geely's Xinyuan model,
the Xinyuan car,
if I use my car, how much of its value would it be worth?
since they all fall under the Geely Galaxy and Geely Geometry series.
Right?
from the same manufacturer.
If you buy it again,
it would be cheaper, wouldn't it?
You might even save two or three thousand dollars.
So, it’s a bit of a catch-22 now.
The car has already been bought,
right?
It has already cost 33,600 dollars.
The insurance is also sorted out,
and the plates are registered.
I've also arrived home.
The parking fee is paid too.
All the way until June 30th next year.
I'm currently parked at this place.
Just parked by the roadside.
If you happen to pass by,
you can take a group photo.
Now I'm in a bit of a dilemma.
You're talking about over 100 kilometers.
What's the difference between this and my electric scooter number 9?
My number 9 isn’t even lithium-powered.
It’s still using a lead-acid battery.
This one with the lead-acid battery.
Since it’s the mz mix, you know.
It’s the same, yeah.
It goes further in the summer.
But in winter, the range is shorter.
Plus, there’s also the issue of air conditioning in cars.
So it's basically turned into a practice car.
It doesn't even serve as a reliable mode of transportation.
But I mentioned,
this is just a number-holding car.
It's quite normal for a number-holding car.
I use this car to hold onto the number.
Because every time you sell a car,
the validity period of this quota gets extended.
It becomes 12 months again.
Sell this car.
Then you’ll have 12 months without needing to buy a new one.
But you always get stuck.
Those 12 months could be inconvenient.
I’m worried that next year,
right?
if I suddenly need to go on an international trip,
for three or four months,
I can’t let the quota issue hold me back.
I’ll come back for the car thing.
Right?
The round-trip ticket costs over ten thousand yuan.
So, I guess I bought it in advance.
Just got the discomfort early.
So, the more you have,
the more you suffer.
But let’s talk about it.
Life is all about experiences.
You need to try and fail quickly
You have to experiment and make mistakes
Only then will you know if your choices are right
To reiterate
Don’t punish your past self
In the time frame of your past
What you did seemed right at the time
Because my goal is to secure a parking spot
My aim is to spend as little money as possible
This car actually has fast charging.
If it didn’t have fast charging,
I’d definitely still go for the high-end BYD Seagull.
Of course, whether it’s 300km or 400km,
My initial choice was the high-spec BYD Seagull,
The high-spec BYD Dolphin,
They all have ranges of 400 to 500 kilometers,
Because I think there will be some loss,
But you can actually get a car like this.
This car only takes up half a parking space.
It's a very easy-to-drive small car.
But to be honest, it's more suitable for smaller cities and towns.
It's particularly fitting for small counties.
The road conditions aren't complicated either.
But the car does have great power.
The Wuling Hongguang Mini now also has fast charging.
So this Wuling Hongguang Mini and the Geely Geometry Panda Knight Panda kart.
Actually, they can also be recommended to you.
But still, the same thing
Big cities aren't suitable
Hehe, in big cities, you're always traveling tens of kilometers
If you're in Beijing
It's often over 30 kilometers
Or even 40 kilometers
You have to recharge every time you go out
That's quite a hassle
So it's become my practice car
So, to be honest,
I have nothing better to do,
I wouldn’t drive more than a few laps, maybe seven or eight,
which is about 78 kilometers,
or a dozen kilometers,
I wouldn’t drive too far, you know,
so this has become my practice car,
Let’s add one more thing,
all the things in life
Actually, you can see why you play games the same way.
Look, I'm playing zombies now.
The Last Stand is just for fun.
I've probably completed it about ten times.
But in reality, I play on easy mode.
Sandbox mode.
Adjusted the difficulty so food doesn't spoil.
There's an abundance of it.
A ton of weapons too.
So I just play for the fun of it
I always cheat when I play games
Cheating allows me to play at the lowest difficulty
I always do it this way
As long as I have a good time
Don't challenge yourself
But this game is just like that
Take the Total War series for example
Every time you lose
Every time you make a mistake moving forward
your growth rate will accelerate
like learning a language, each mistake you make
stumbling once
helps you move faster
so humans constantly learn and progress through mistakes
you can't be afraid of making mistakes
if you fear making mistakes
you have a tendency to make them
It's easy not to start
It's easy to procrastinate
Did you know?
But once you start doing something, as long as you get started
Even if it's not perfect
As long as you begin, that's what matters
Just like I force myself to get on the road
I dare to ride my motorcycle on the road
But I can also ride an electric scooter
I'm really a bit hesitant to drive a car on the road.
Because the accident video from the fourth subject exam really gave me a scare.
And I always think that with every press of the pedal, it could be someone's life at stake.
Someone else's child,
an elderly person's life is in my hands.
So I can't afford to be relaxed at all.
I absolutely can't overlook these things.
That's why I take a lot of responsibility for it.
I get really nervous.
I think this thing is just a tear for every driver
like family members sharing a toast
it's just something that can't happen to me
so I'm extremely nervous
I was planning to be quite preoccupied today
intending to drive back 30km
but there was a truck in the middle
it suddenly slammed on the brakes
which made me have to brake hard too
A sudden brake
My water bottle flew from the back seat to the front
It made me super nervous
I thought, this is just from a quick brake
Either I would hit someone from behind
Or someone would hit me from behind
What a terrifying situation
So I thought, oh well, forget it
I’ll just call a driver
I drove about 56 kilometers
before I found a place to park and dared to call a driver
and then drove back
all the way back to my starting point
there was a sharp turn in the middle
and my water bottle got thrown under the brake and accelerator pedals
fortunately, it got stuck under the accelerator
it didn’t get stuck under the brake
if it had gotten stuck under the brake
So I had to use the handbrake to stop the car.
How dangerous that was.
That's what I had anticipated.
For example, my car needs an additional installation.
A partition in the middle.
And the water can't be placed in the front passenger seat.
It must be placed in the back.
Or in the cup holder.
That's much safer.
Nothing should reach under this brake pedal.
That's extremely dangerous.
And I will absolutely never drive in flip-flops again.
When riding a motorcycle or similar.
You need to wear protective gear.
It's not enough to just have insurance.
You also need to wear protective gear.
Wear a helmet.
I always wear my helmet.
But I bought this protective gear and never wore it.
For people like those who offer riding services,
You're just riding a scooter.
Is it really necessary?
I should at least wear proper hiking shoes,
Or sports shoes.
Instead of wearing those flip-flops all the time.
So when you think about my entrepreneurial journey,
To be honest,
Some of you may already be familiar with this.
And some are new to our audience.
Let me tell you all,
in my entrepreneurial journey,
I changed projects several times,
even shifted industries,
because if I hadn't pursued certain projects,
if I hadn't ventured into certain industries,
I would have felt unsatisfied.
This person would say that they won't give up until they hit a brick wall.
If you feel unwilling to let go,
you might think it’s an unfinished business in your life.
If you decide not to do it,
you'll feel really bad about it.
But if you really go for it,
you’ll wonder why it can’t work out.
Often, it’s a process of trial and error.
So I often tell people
A company wants to make money
From the first year to the third year, everything was pretty normal
I've already surpassed the average for most people
I only really started making big money in the fourth year
Before that, it was a struggle just to keep going
Earning a little to keep going
So I tell everyone
It's about the process of starting a business
It's just like playing a game.
When you start a new game, you're not familiar with it.
You think you are familiar with it.
Total War is the same; every new release requires me to get used to it again.
History of the Three Kingdoms,
Nobunaga's Ambition,
for all these games,
every new release requires you to adapt again.
with every new generation.
The gameplay will change.
You're bound to hit some bumps.
We often say that in RPG games, the first time you clear the game,
it might be with the first character,
you end up wasting them.
The story gets wasted,
and then you have to go back,
spending another two hours replaying,
the first character might get overleveled and become useless.
Or you might miss the plot
Your first attempt always involves a remake
A process of rebirth, if you will
Actually, these things are quite common
From a life perspective
You often have to start several times
And think about starting a business
When we talk about being the boss
It’s a process of accumulating experience
You used to be an employee
even if you were a supervisor
you were still an employee
you didn't have to think like a boss
you need to gain the boss's experience
you have to quickly experiment and learn from mistakes
keep making mistakes
only through mistakes can you gain experience
and grow
So, just like when I bought my car,
Why do I have to bring up the car purchase?
If I don't actually take it for a drive,
I won't really be able to reduce the energy consumption,
I won't really understand the actual energy usage,
I won't really know the hassle of charging back and forth,
I wouldn't know how crucial the range is for this car in the summer,
how important it is to have the air conditioning on,
because for me,
While affordability is crucial,
I’m just afraid of the heat,
so this is my actual need.
So your first car should have some issues to teach you a lesson.
I went all out from the start.
Who doesn’t know a good car when they see one?
If I had gone all out from the start,
I wouldn’t have learned about the various data on different cars later on.
Why is it so hard to come by?
You might end up buying a car with more power than you need
I'll start with the cheapest car
To put it bluntly, just for gaming
Start with the easiest difficulty
Very easy
Choose the easiest starting monarch
Right?
Pick the cheapest and smallest car
After driving for a while
Then I realized that my battery range needs to be at least 450 miles.
It would be more appropriate if it could reach 570 miles.
Right?
Otherwise, I would have range anxiety that could affect my motivation to drive.
But this issue isn't particularly severe for me.
Why?
Because I don't drive fast.
I don't use the highway.
I rarely go to places that require the highway.
I actually shuttle between the urban and suburban areas of Beijing.
And there's also the issue of finding parking being difficult.
But parking this small car isn't hard.
Right?
Moreover, insurance for a smaller car is also cheaper.
So it's important to leave room for mistakes.
Don't be afraid to make mistakes.
Your first car is bound to be a less ideal purchase.
My first motorcycle
I was pretty happy with the UI.
But I also carefully selected several motorcycles.
In the past, I've ridden more than just the UI5.
I've ridden other bikes as well.
Like the Wangjiang Suzuki,
various replicas of tombs,
and Haojue, among others.
But let's not get into that now.
As for electric scooters, this is my sixth one.
Right?
Was it the sixth or the seventh? I forgot.
Anyway, let me count.
The first one.
The second one.
The third one.
The fourth one.
The fifth one.
The sixth one, right.
This is the sixth car.
For the sixth car, I bought number 9.
Next time, I'll definitely go for the set.
Because I'm not a big fan of the calf.
That's why I chose number 9.
I think the calf is too expensive.
But number 9 isn't cheap either.
But now, looking at the set,
it does seem more suitable.
It suits my taste
But when I bought it, it was already the new national standard
I might not be able to find such a good bike
But I realized what I need most from a motorcycle
It's not the engine size
It's not the price
It's the range
My UY125 with an extra fuel tank can run 700km
What I care about the most is the range
Because I don't drive as fast as others
so when I consider a car, the last thing I pay attention to is the range
so when I buy a car
I didn't focus on the range
but cars with a high range are usually quite expensive
so in the future when I consider a car
I'll try to maximize its range
the power
the interior and such, I can be more flexible with
So I know what car to switch to in the future.
But you're bound to make mistakes the first time.
It's your first marriage, after all.
Your first time dating a girlfriend.
The first time looking for a job, you'll make mistakes.
You need to give yourself room to make mistakes.
Like how Brother Rong got married in a hurry.
Even though I've dated so many times,
But in the end, I ended up with a rushed marriage too.
This means no lessons have been learned.
You can't just marry someone after two months.
You should take at least a year or two to get to know them.
Right?
Because a lot of a person's dark sides,
many of their issues won't be revealed quickly.
So that's how it is.
Including yourself, you also need time to reveal yourself.
Right?
Without you
You get annoyed with others
Others will get annoyed with you too
Right?
Others lose their patience with you
People want to say goodbye
Is it that getting married becomes quite troublesome?
Things would be better if not in a married state
So these matters can't be decided quickly
But it's important to test and learn quickly
Because quick decision-making, like what Brother Rong did this time
He bought a motorcycle and then immediately bought a car
Putting two happy families together doesn't necessarily make them happier
Right?
The joy of riding a motorcycle
The joy of driving a car is a different story
Buddy
So it's still better to think things through carefully
Let's think about it in the long term.
But this time, since it's bought, it's bought.
It's no big deal.
I'm not short of money.
Right?
I bought this car for 33,600.
I gave him a discount.
Should we cancel the insurance?
I gave it a discounted price.
You can still buy more expensive cars.
Right?
I might switch my car in winter.
Yeah, it’s really possible to drive it for five or six months.
I might change my car after a year.
So, there’s no need to worry too much.
Cars don’t have an expiration date for being on the road anyway.
In reality, I don’t get many opportunities to drive.
I also find parking to be a hassle.
I might just call a ride-hailing car.
Isn't it that I can't possibly avoid drinking when I go out for dinner?
Right?
So many times, it ends up like this.
In the end, I have to call a designated driver.
It’s much more expensive than calling a ride-hailing car.
So, we still stand by our saying.
Today, we’ve had a casual chat with everyone.
This has already been 16 minutes.
A practical tip for everyone is to avoid the mindset of being bound to make mistakes.
Don't let the student mentality dominate your mind.
Be brave enough to make mistakes.
Be bold enough to start.
Even if the initial situation isn't ideal.
Believe that you will mess up the first time, and that's okay.
Give yourself the space to fail the first time.
Speaking practically,
regardless of how much my car depreciates in the end.
Negotiate
20,000 yuan can always be negotiated
So for my first attempt, I used 30,000 yuan to quickly test and learn from mistakes
That’s when I realized how much I care about the range
The most important thing I like about my motorcycle is its range
Right?
Because I suffer from range anxiety
I always want it to be at 100%
I guess I have a bit of an OCD
So I've been riding the motorcycle for a long time without thinking about refueling.
The fuel gauge doesn't even drop.
Right?
It uses the 10 liters in the reserve tank before it starts using the main tank.
What about the 6 liters?
To be honest,
I might keep the main tank full most of the time,
and only refill the reserve tank after a while.
That's how it usually goes.
Because he has a fuel gauge to show
Or every time I finish the reserve tank
I immediately refill the reserve tank
I don’t really care about the main tank
It could be like that
Because you have to fill the main tank first
Then the reserve tank
I won’t go into the specifics
Anyway, I feel that the car, to me
You've only done this once.
But both times you went to power up.
Why is it that one time you drove all the way to the eastern fifth ring?
From Shunyi to Chaoyang,
and then back from Chaoyang to Shunyi,
you charged once.
This time, you drove from Shunyi to Haidian,
and used up the battery again,
using it up in one go.
But this time I've gained some experience.
As long as you cross districts and it's over 30km.
It might consume 50 or even 70 kilometers of range.
You can only gain true knowledge through practice.
To be honest.
Including having insurance.
Don't be afraid of minor incidents.
As long as it's not a serious accident.
We should talk about minor scratches.
That's all perfectly normal.
Is it true that you can only solve these problems when you encounter them?
Just like our great War of Resistance against Japan.
Learning from combat and from the enemy.
What tactics do they have?
Regarding their tactics,
What tactics should we use to counter them?
The 80th anniversary of the victory in the great War of Resistance against Japan.
The grand military parade is about to begin.
All citizens of Beijing will be very excited.
A passionate heart awaits this grand parade.
Let's talk about this.
Exactly.
You need to learn from mistakes.
You need to learn from collisions,
In the process of exchange,
Learn from these collisions,
Learn from confrontation.
Why do I always tell everyone to engage in competitive sports?
Especially when you're young.
One is to release hormones,
Release your violent tendencies,
And the other is to cultivate your competitive spirit.
So,
Don't be afraid of making mistakes.
Even if it's a simple and silly thing,
Like Brother Rong driving a small, old car and showing off,
It's embarrassing and not very dignified,
But you won't always drive such a car.
This is just my first car.
For my second car,
Third car,
Fourth car,
Fifth car,
I might own 20 cars in my lifetime.
It's also a knowledge reserve,
A skill reserve.
It's easy to go from frugality to luxury,
But hard to go from luxury to frugality.
Don't be afraid of making mistakes.
Don't have an aversion to making mistakes in the initial stages.
Quickly try and make mistakes.
Continuously challenge yourself,
Continuously push yourself to make mistakes,
Then you'll understand the system, just like when I play games,
I might discover a game mechanism on the 20th try,
Or some shortcuts,
That I've never tried before,
Turns out they're so convenient.
There are many ways to beat the game,
That I haven't tried,
Haven't fully explored the system.
So you need to fully understand something,
For example, flying,
Or sailing,
Or driving—
You will certainly make many mistakes.
You need to allow yourself to grow gradually.
The more you drive, the better you'll get.
The more you play, the better you'll get.
Life is the same,
The more mistakes you make,
The more you'll naturally understand everything.
It all makes sense now.