The story of the Tortoise and the Hare
From when we were kids
Teachers from our generation, like us Gen Xers, used to tell us
Stories like the slow bird that flies early
Waiting by the stump for a rabbit
Diligence can make up for lack of ability
It’s telling you not to be lazy
To be hardworking
But let me tell you
Actually, the U.S. promotes joyful learning while we promote diligent education
The core characteristics are actually quite similar
Why do I say they’re similar?
Because the end result is the same
Many people always think, how should I put it,
when it comes to diligence,
it ultimately does pay off.
But I've said before,
when we talk about diligence,
we mean the diligence of a genius.
If you're not a genius,
your hard work actually doesn't make much difference.
That 1% of talent is still very important.
For example, the story of the Tortoise and the Hare
Did the hare lose in the end?
The hare only lost one race
This race seemed to be won by the tortoise
But from any perspective
The tortoise always runs
It can never outrun the hare
Even if you start earlier
Even if you find 100 clones
Your innate abilities still fall short of the rabbit's.
Everyone should look for a courier in a large forest.
Wouldn't you all still choose the rabbit?
If you need to burn something,
you'd also pick the rabbit for the job.
So, we're talking about your weaknesses.
Even if you try to make up for them through hard work,
when you compete with others,
you still wouldn't stand a chance.
This is how we achieve a class leap.
You know, I'm 41 now.
I've started to dive deep into nuclear physics.
Do you think I can become a nuclear physics expert?
Obviously, that's not possible.
So, if you could have done it when you were young,
why didn't you do it back then?
Why would it be possible now that you're older?
Right?
The senior university is actually meant to comfort people’s hearts.
The so-called talents are actually just selected.
A turtle is a turtle.
A rabbit is a rabbit.
What should the turtle compete with humans?
It should compete in longevity.
It should compete in having a hard shell.
It shouldn’t compete in speed.
The fast rabbit is indeed fast.
In the end, it turned out to be a rabbit's head.
Right?
What about the turtle? What should the turtle be like?
The turtle should leverage its own strengths.
So many of us, when we were young,
liked our teachers,
and would often say,
Look at this student; his family is wealthy,
but he doesn’t do well in studies.
What kind of job will he be able to find in the future, right?
He doesn't even need to look for a job.
So, in many cases,
the differences in family background and talent,
as the saying goes, 'dragons give birth to dragons,]
and phoenixes give birth to phoenixes',
these differences cannot be made up for by hard work later in life.
He puts it to you like this,
look, you're doing better in studies than those classmates from wealthy families.
At its core, it's a way to comfort you.
After all, people have already accumulated wealth or resources over two or three generations.
Why should they be considered less hardworking than your single generation?
And everyone needs to understand,
defying the odds and changing one's fate is only suitable for a select few.
Some people talk about those at the top,
who got into C9 universities like Tsinghua or Peking University,
and then went abroad to pursue a Ph.D.,
and ended up working in Silicon Valley.
He made a leap from a small village to this social class.
But speaking of him personally,
even though he was born into a humble background,
his intelligence level was sufficient.
That’s because his genes were good.
So, fundamentally speaking,
we say one's origin determines everything.
One's origin determines everything.
Does that mean we don’t need to strive in our later years?
It's not about competing in a race with others the day after tomorrow
but rather analyzing your own characteristics
What exactly are my unique traits?
What unique qualities does my species possess?
What value can be derived from them?
Where should I be making my contribution?
From a national perspective, talent
is selected through a process
we need to ensure we have the most outstanding talent
We don’t care if his name is Zhang San or Li Si
It doesn’t matter
As long as we, from a societal perspective
Maintain a certain number of top talents
Who can contribute to scientific research
Contribute to engineering
Contribute to finance
And contribute to military and other fields
Our talent pool just needs to be large enough
He can pick out any kind of talent.
But when it comes to ourselves,
we can't just believe blindly.
Hard work makes up for lack of talent.
The early bird catches the worm.
You can never outdo a genius no matter how hard you try.
When you were in middle school,
you couldn't outdo the math prodigy,
or the physics prodigy.
an English prodigy
right or wrong
well, to be honest
each province has its own natural disasters
each county has its own natural disasters
every school and every class has its own top student
so don’t try to compete with the top student
even if he’s well-known in your area
he might not necessarily stand out at the national level
So we say that talent selection is a very harsh process.
But for a populous country,
being able to select the best talent
is of utmost importance to the nation.
As long as we have a large enough population base,
we can always select the best individuals.
But what should we, the people at the back, do?
You shouldn't try to follow the path of a genius.
This is what you should do.
I'm not saying you're not a genius
but that's the problem
you just might not be a sprinting genius
you're just not a rabbit
you can't compete with a rabbit in math
or in physics
but you might be better than a rabbit in English
you might be better in literature
you might be better at business
You might have better stamina
You might live longer
These are all advantages
So don't act like in the story of Tian Ji's horse racing
Don’t compare your weaknesses with others’ strengths
Comparing your weaknesses with others’ strengths will surely lead to failure
That’s why the saying 'diligence can make up for clumsiness' means
It refers to some weaknesses
What you need to do is focus on how to leverage your efforts
You can reach an average level compared to others
but that’s only reaching an average level
what truly sets you apart from others is your strength
so when it comes to the story itself
the direction it leads us is problematic
it means that we Chinese believe in hard work
that it can solve all problems
but hard work is often another term for
being overworked
Just focusing on the effort without considering the direction of development is meaningless.
Just comparing your strengths with others’ is not going to work.
That’s also pointless.
It’s like chasing a car with a tricycle.
Right?
It’s like comparing the resources of one province with those of an entire country.
There’s no way that would work out.
So, in many cases,
we emphasize the importance of first identifying the right direction for our efforts.
Is that right?
And we've said,
What a business should really be like
It's not about how hard you work
There's this person who opened a KFC coffee shop
But the business isn't doing well
Does sitting there every day really help?
Sitting there every day
Recite the Heart Sutra twice
Copy it twice
Is this Sutra of the Earth Store effective?
This is about putting in effort
Is this the right direction?
Should you be doing this at this time?
Business is about running a business
So often, we say it’s because your effort is misdirected
How exactly should a business be run?
We’ve talked about a very simple concept
It's the human needs that give rise to products and services.
For example, the ongoing trade war between China and the U.S.
This trade war
creates a significant demand gap.
So, platforms like DHgate step in to fill this gap.
Of course,
if DHgate didn't exist or ceased operations daily,
the massive demand would still be there,
and countless middlemen, new apps, and new methods would emerge.
This allows American customers to access products from China.
So, this represents a huge demand and a huge supply.
That's what it generates.
A service and a product.
So, it’s either a product,
or a service.
The app itself is a product,
and also a service.
So, to delve deeper into it,
We need to think about the world today
Where changes are constant and unpredictable
There's a new conflict between India and Pakistan
This will create new demands
A place has been hit by a major blizzard
It will generate new needs
A sudden trade embargo emerges in a region
It will also create new demands
No matter what happens
Human needs remain constant
Because humans need to live every day
Survival is a daily necessity
And survival requires the consumption of resources
Water, electricity, oil, and food
So in many aspects
From our perspective
There are numerous opportunities in life to seize
Never chase after what others excel at
Others have already studied better than you.
Others have already been admitted to Tsinghua or Peking University.
Even if you were to start over several times in this life,
you wouldn't be able to catch up.
So, when it comes to many things,
it's not about how many times you roll for talent,
but rather, no matter what talent you roll for,
being able to live a good life in this game is what matters.
So, in many cases,
We talk about competing
about outdoing each other
but it really doesn’t make sense
because your gains are different from others’
Let me repeat that
I’m 40 years old now
You will eventually reach 40, even 50
or 60
Your English might never surpass mine.
Even if you study really hard
You can at most match my level.
and I don’t even need English to make money
but you insist on making money through English
that’s the root of your miserable life
I am the rabbit
you are the turtle
you insist on running as fast as the rabbit
I believe with the current advanced technology
You might be able to run as fast as a rabbit
but at what cost?
How much time are you willing to invest?
How much energy are you willing to expend?
So in many aspects of our lives
we believe in hard work
and that diligence can make up for shortcomings
but often we put in effort
where we shouldn’t be exerting ourselves
Struggling in vain to impress yourself
For example, like copying scriptures as a mere formality
If you memorize the content of the scriptures in your heart
Put it into practice
Be a good person
Be a kind person
That might be more useful than copying it a hundred times
In many cases
This copying includes reciting it with others
What we do in front of others is just for show
Often, that's how it is
You work hard to impress others
or to impress yourself?
You try to prove to others
Look, I've copied it 100 times
So I'm a hardworking person
So I'm a highly cultivated person
No, you're just good at copying
If you can truly put it into practice
it makes a difference
it's a different story
The purpose of these things is to help you gain insight
to enable you to effectively manage your emotions
really, how to put it
to act from the heart
so often we say it's not about you
to truly engage in this hands-on activity
And the act of handwriting itself
This kind of thing
This behavior can be inspiring
You are merely a tool for transmission
So you must understand your role as a tool
Therefore, we often need to be aware
From an individual's perspective
Society, in general, has expectations of you
But heaven has different expectations for women
We have different standards for ourselves.
Many things that appear to be right on the surface,
things that seem like they should be done,
things that look good,
can actually lead to your downfall.
Why do I say it leads to downfall?
Because wasting time is akin to murdering life.
If you waste a bit more time,
and do something unworthy.
Putting effort into an unworthy relationship
can only move yourself
that's why it's called the 'licking dog effect'
So, in many cases
the ultimate outcome is to satisfy oneself
to move oneself
to the point of shedding tears
like a damn fool
and then
You've spent your entire life.
When you grow old,
you won't be as significant to society anymore.
You won't have as much influence.
You won't make as big a splash.
So it's easiest to comfort you now.
We can even enroll you in a senior university.
So you need to understand,
you have to accept the advice society gives you.
It's also important to understand that society's expectations of us are actually quite low.
As ordinary people,
Or, speaking of being an NPC,
unless you stand out in some significant way,
society’s expectations of you are actually rather low.
Just don’t break the law,
and pay your taxes, and that’s enough.
Most of the time,
what you want to do in your daily life is up to you.
What do you feel like eating?
What do you feel like playing?
In fact, most people don't give much advice.
They don't have many demands.
Unless society assigns you a special role.
Otherwise, you might have a bit of a moral flaw.
But you don't really care.
In many cases,
it's the opposite of what we were taught as children.
Because the essence of education is to soothe
The essence of education is to make most people feel that their lives
The essence of education is to help most people find themselves
in a suitable position
aligned with societal expectations
But how do we talk about human society?
after so many years of development
It's not about societal expectations for you
being the happiest moments of your life
What does society expect from you?
To exhaust all your capabilities when you're young
Work hard
Create plenty of value
Ideally, have children
And then
Spend every penny you've earned on yourself
And become part of the economic cycle
Don't save a dime when you're old
Try to die as early as possible
Don't bother collecting a pension
This is what society truly needs from you
But would society ever say these things out loud?
No, it wouldn't
But in the choices you make in life
In many aspects
You can resist
You can balance the scales
You can engage in strategic games.
But when it comes to a smart person,
they would make such plans early on.
On the surface, they appear compliant,
but in reality, they have their own ideas.
That’s what a smart person looks like in modern society,
not just following the conventional paths of society.
Remember, society often encourages these paths,
these morals.
These roads
all these things
these confusing elements are meant to frame the majority of people
to keep the majority of people stable
this is also a fundamental need of society
if everyone were like you
with a restless heart every day
always thinking about changing their fate
society would also become unstable
So when you have the determination to change your destiny
When you have
the unconventional idea of social mobility
you need to understand
that you have to do unconventional things to achieve unconventional goals
So often we say
we can't just think about how our lives are now
we need to think about the kind of life we want in the future
we can't use the same logic we use now
Because this logic is designed to pacify the majority.
To endure and submit.
Right?
Many things that we take for granted aren't actually as they seem on the surface.
They aren't what we superficially believe them to be.
So you need to absorb new perspectives.
To understand how these perspectives truly work.
To grasp the rules that govern society.
Ultimately, this leads to personal liberation.
Liberation for the masses is unrealistic
It's more of a slogan
Often, it's about individuals finding redemption
An individual achieving a leap forward
An individual attaining true freedom
An individual gaining complete freedom is achievable
So this is what we strive for in sociology
The meaning of a perfect life
That is, you were supposed to follow a tortoise's path
But you took the path of, say, the phoenix.
But you must have the resilience to forge ahead.
Speaking of turtles, there are also alligator snapping turtles.
And sea turtles.
And various other types of turtles.
What kind of turtle could you become?
Could you become a thousand-year-old turtle?
This would be your best possible outcome.
After all, people should know their own limits.
It's better not to use it.
This tricycle chasing vehicles
Don't compare your E-class skills with others' S-class skills.
It's meaningless.
Others can survive with just a bit of effort.
A slight advantage at 20 points.
But you, with the same effort, can only achieve a two-point effect.
That's just a waste of time.
In terms of efficiency,
Use a hammer to drive in nails
Use this pickaxe to mine the ore
It's also a pretty efficient way to do things
So in this new era
You need to first understand what kind of tool you are
First and foremost, you are a tool
You have your place in society
So to speak
You need to remove the premise of being a tool
It's important to understand the essence of why one becomes a tool for others.
And you need to realize
Society actually doesn't expect much from you
You can transform into a role in society
That meets the expectations of others
So our careers and our states of being
Are all free to change
They're not as fixed as others might say
But whether you can take on another role is another story
It depends on you
rather than the advice from other members of society
or their recognition of you
So, when we talk about this, we come to our second core point
If you want to accept the roles others assign to you
the most important thing is to learn how to perform
That is, your identity outside is given by yourself
Many times
it's about how you present yourself
More often than not
life is more about performance skills
Performance doesn't just mean going on stage
or performing for others in a simple way
Performance is the ability to get others to accept you in a short time
as a certain role
That is, in a short time, others judge who you are through your attire
and your behavior
They perceive what kind of person you are
And sometimes, this projection
whether it's an admiring projection or a fearful one
is necessary
That is, at critical moments
some people's jobs require them to be various kinds of people
For example, if you're serving your country
Many times
you need to be all sorts of people
You might be in one state at one moment
and another state the next
Just like Yu Zecheng
So, many times, you need to be versatile
This is also why acting is important
Similarly
many times, you need to have acting skills
You need to have the ability to say one thing and do another
Because true Machiavellians are like this
They deeply understand the principles of governance
They deeply understand the true, dark principles of society
Society has its own way of operating
But it also has a set of grand narratives
But you need to know what the underlying rules are
Only then can you live more confidently
more confidently
more freely
This is a prerequisite
That is, as you grow up
you need to see through these children's stories
the fables like the Tortoise and the Hare
what they want you to do
They want you to be a tortoise that works hard and steadily
But do you want to be a tortoise?
You don't
Otherwise, you'd be a 'tortoise man', right?