so I didn't update yesterday
so today we're back with an update
today I'm going to talk about a very simple issue
which is whether it's the poor kids who spend more money
Kids from wealthy families do spend more money.
We tend to use extreme examples each time.
My college classmates also say I study computer science
That was a second-tier university.
Many of my college classmates
90% of them,
were from rural areas around Beijing.
What do we mean by rural areas?
We're talking about the outskirts, like Shunyi.
Pinggu
Huairou
Yanqing
Daxing
places like these
and Tongzhou as well
back then, when our classmates spoke
they were all quite down-to-earth
how should I put it
Well, you can't exactly call it crude.
But it's truly very simple and honest.
But the tactics in the countryside are different from those in the city.
My classmates left a deep impression on me.
Because from elementary school to junior high school,
and even high school,
I mostly interacted with people from Beijing,
kids from the city,
and rarely with those from the suburbs.
Kids from the so-called outskirts
Rarely interact with children from rural areas
So back then, I realized that between people
These thought patterns and habits were actually quite
Very different
Was it 2004 or 2005? Everyone remember
I can't recall exactly
But it wasn't during our freshman year
Our whole class rented a car to go to Shidu for a trip
Why did the school suddenly organize a spring outing?
At that time, our school
was concerned about the collision incident between the Chinese and Japanese ships
You know, the ship captain, what was his name again?
That captain collided with a Japanese Coast Guard vessel
During that period
there were many mass movements
You know?
So the school was worried about these college students
Not that particularly restless
So they arranged for each class to go out and play
You know, back then there were a lot of guys in the Computer Science department
We were worried about you getting into trouble
So they arranged for you to visit places around Beijing
We went to Shidu
Shidu, the Du in Shidu means ferry
Shidu is a really beautiful place
It has mountains and rivers
There's something to do
When we went there that time
I'm talking about those famous ghost stories
I suddenly flipped my car on the highway
That was one of them
It went like this on the road
What left a deep impression on me was
We had a great time that day
But it made me realize the differences among children from different backgrounds
The concept of money is completely different.
Of course, everyone has been taught about it.
Money for fun.
And because they spend without much restraint,
without much thought,
when everyone’s money is pooled together,
it seems like a lot of money,
so they go all out spending it.
On the first day, I ordered a whole roasted lamb.
We had three whole roasted lambs.
You know, a whole roasted lamb is quite expensive.
Even if you're really happy,
once you start drinking, things get pricey.
They have their own little circle, you see.
They're all classmates.
But every class definitely has its own little circle, right?
Those few people are especially close.
So these people are good friends with the class president.
He took care of everything.
How much are we spending?
It's up to us.
But I can understand that.
Every village has its bully.
It's quite normal.
But then a problem arose.
When we went out to play the next day,
we found that the money wasn't enough.
We're short on cash.
In fact, it's not even enough.
We couldn't even afford lunch.
But at that time,
Well, everyone is unsure about what to do.
We were all sitting under the sun,
on a stone bench,
and we sat there for about two hours,
I'm not exaggerating.
I sat there for two hours
and I was really puzzled
I said, what have you been waiting for these two hours?
What have you been waiting for?
No solution was proposed either
Then I figured it out
The remaining money was clearly not enough
It wasn’t enough for everyone to spend
But if only half the people were allowed to
Leaving this group,
then the remaining people can not only eat but also have fun.
You know?
Later, I became more cautious.
I said to their leader,
I said, if it really doesn't work,
Who's hungry?
I'll take them to get some food first.
Oh, sorry.
If everyone still has some money, they can spend it themselves.
But if we spend more, might the class fund run short?
They also showed signs of discomfort.
But they don’t communicate with you either.
It’s just so funny.
That’s just how it is.
You can see his face changing colors.
But these people are just so funny.
It’s like, how do you even explain it?
They're bullies who pretend to be polite
Yeah, they act tough but aren't really righteous
On the surface, they seem very loyal
They talk nicely most of the time
But when it counts, they have their own little schemes
You know what I mean
So later, I brought a few people along
No, no
Actually, they're not from our class
I took those who had strong opinions out for a meal.
We chatted casually about the restaurant and such.
After all, the money wasn't really enough.
So I talked to the owner of the restaurant.
It was around one or two in the afternoon, you see.
By then, we were past the point of being hungry.
And the restaurant was about to close.
I specifically chose a place that wasn't doing too well in terms of business.
Then they brought out a lot of food.
stuff like vegetables
made us devour the food like wolves
we hadn’t had breakfast
or lunch either
since we had been hiking as well
and were completely exhausted
so we all gobbled up the food
finally, we were full
there were probably seven or eight of us
The rest of them were really happy
I took this group away
The remaining folks
We had enough money
Rushed off to go rafting
After rafting, we had a meal
Everyone was in high spirits that day
And we took the hard-seat train back to Beijing
That experience left a profound impression on me
We're talking about kids from poor families.
We shouldn't generalize about the poor and the rich.
To be honest,
Let's be frank,
Most of the people affected by urban redevelopment are farmers from the outskirts of Beijing.
We can't absolutely categorize people as poor or rich.
But being poor or rich is more about mindset.
It's all about the mindset.
Like when I was six years old,
Since I grew up in Zhongguancun
When I found Zhongguancun
As you all know
If you've been to the northeast of Peking University
That's the side with the subway station
Then head to the east side of this road
You'll reach Zhongguancun No. 2 Primary School
Then walk a bit further north
Isn't there a bakery?
Head a bit further north
and you'll find a small road leading into the Keyuan community
where my grandparents live
This Keyuan community actually has a particularly rough road
but this particularly rough road
was the site of the first New Oriental campus back in the day
This site was located here in the early 1990s
and there was a rural credit cooperative here
I'm not sure if it was a city or rural credit cooperative
It was just a tiny savings office.
I remember going to this savings office.
It left a particularly strong impression on me.
My mom opened a passbook account for me.
I was in fourth or fifth grade back then.
I deposited 60 yuan.
I got my first bank card when I was in the first year of junior high school.
My first credit card
I received when I was in my first year of high school.
Don't think this is weird.
You need to understand this.
Exactly.
Of course, it's a supplementary credit card.
It was for playing games across borders back then.
I had my mom apply for a dual-currency card.
Then I got a supplementary card.
Don't think this is strange.
Now, what do you need a bank card for?
Going back to my time,
My first year of junior high was in 1997.
In 1997, we only had magnetic stripe cards.
The first card I got was from the Construction Bank.
Later on, I got a card from China Merchants Bank.
A credit card from China Merchants Bank.
Back then, in 1997 and 1999,
that was quite a while ago.
At that time, there wasn't much of an internet concept like we have now.
The internet was just getting started
At the beginning, there was 163
169 dial-up, 263, and those kinds of services
So it was a very, very early period
That is to say, it only started from that time
Actually, every time my mom and dad talk to me, they say this
They started giving me money right from the beginning
Many parents handle things differently with their kids
It's about what expenses students should have
Kids ask for money whenever they want something.
And when they can't afford something,
they get upset if their parents don't buy it for them.
But my parents were never like that.
Instead, they encouraged me to save money.
They encouraged me to save.
And every month, they would give me a fixed amount of about six or seven hundred yuan.
They would give me about six or seven hundred yuan.
Back then, that was quite a lot of money.
Back in high school, they would give around six or seven hundred yuan.
So, you see,
two people would get 1,400 yuan.
Then, we would keep this money,
if you saved it,
if you saved 5,000 to 10,000 yuan,
they would give you an extra 1,000 yuan.
My parents often encouraged me,
you know.
So, you should try to spend less.
You should try to minimize your expenses.
So, by the time I went to college or university,
before studying abroad,
I had saved up about 100,000 yuan.
I worked part-time jobs,
sold items,
and collected red envelopes,
and saved my pocket money.
Many parents don't give their kids money
They only start giving money once the kids go to college
Or they might give a little if the kids are boarding
Or they just don't want you to worry about money
This makes you wonder why
Because the parents don't earn much
They're afraid the kids might feel inferior
But in reality, the parents' income
My parents, for instance, don't earn a lot either
There really isn't much.
But they still allocate a portion from their limited company to me.
It's to help me develop a savings habit.
Not to encourage me to spend money.
The money is actually not for me to spend.
Only if you save it up.
You shouldn't spend it.
That's when you truly feel the power of money.
Because back then, Liu Xun said that the money in the first year was really all mine.
It was all saved up by myself.
Only later did I receive financial support from my family.
Money from my parents and such.
The money spent in the first year was mostly what I had saved up myself.
In other words, for my studies abroad,
I used all the 100,000 yuan I had saved from childhood.
It was all spent in one go.
But think about what 100,000 yuan means.
It's 100,000 yuan from 2005.
If you had 300,000 yuan in 2005,
you could have bought a house.
In Beijing.
100,000 yuan in 2005 was actually a lot of money.
And I've been saving it
since I was young,
living frugally and sparingly.
I have to tighten my belt
After all, I
But I still play games, though
Didn't I also buy the PS1 and PS2?
Right?
Write 'is Game Boy Advance'
Didn't I also buy it?
But in reality, I managed to save quite a bit of money
Actually, it formed a very effective savings mindset
Plus, I basically stay away from online loans
or those messy and shady nude photo loans and such
Because quite early on
I mean, when I was around 15 or 16
I got my first credit card
I knew all about overdue payments and installment plans
When I got my first savings card
That's when I set a rule for myself
If I had more than 1,000 yuan in my pocket
Whenever I have more than a thousand bucks in my hands,
I deposit it.
So, I always have a few hundred dollars on me.
I don't mind making multiple trips to the bank.
That's how it is.
When I have more than a thousand bucks in my hands,
I deposit the amount over a thousand bucks.
I deposit the amount over a thousand bucks and don't spend it.
I don't break the bill.
Then you always have a few hundred bucks in your pocket
A few hundred bucks are enough for food and drinks
For you to go out and date
Enough for you to go out and have a good time
You can even afford a hotel room
No problem, right?
But it’s just not enough
For you to make big purchases
Like buying a phone
Buy a gaming console
Definitely not when you're abroad
But I can ensure you won't starve
I'm currently following this principle
So I haven't really been keeping up
I have many times more money now than back then
But I'm still very frugal when it comes to saving
It's a concept
That is, anything over 1000 yuan
As long as there's over a thousand yuan in my WeChat or Alipay
I always transfer it to my bank account
So my bank account always has
various amounts in the thousands
but never in the hundreds
just amounts in the thousands, right
So my savings mindset has always been there.
Actually, I noticed this when I talked to friends who are entrepreneurs
later on
Kids from poor families really like to open stores
They are particularly keen on starting businesses
They are very fond of taking out loans
Borrowing money to partner up
They are willing to do all these things
But once they suffer a loss
When you ask them
How much did you lose?
I now owe 300,000
Hehe, what are you laughing at? What’s so funny?
Dude, what are you laughing at?
Don't you think you're in your thirties now?
Or even forties?
You owe thirty or forty thousand in debt now.
What about your parents?
Aren't they going to get sick?
What about your wife and child?
What are you going to do if you get divorced?
Have you ever thought about what you'll rely on in the future?
Are you planning to find another job?
When it comes to starting your own business,
why can't you take the time to think it through?
why not give it some serious thought?
whether you're really cut out for entrepreneurship,
which industry you should be in,
where you should start from,
you just jump right into opening a coffee shop.
Then I teamed up with a friend
And brought along about 20 more
Around 30 in total
And you start feeling like you’re loaded
But when things go wrong, they just laugh it off
That’s what I’ve seen
My college buddies are like that
They have no sense of money
They end up collecting a lot of cash
Oops
The class fund should be around five or six thousand yuan
Let’s have roasted whole lamb
A roasted whole lamb costs 1800, and then we’re out of money
So he doesn’t have a sense of it
The farm stay owner knew that from the start
Hmm
It’s always like this, no matter how much money you have
I’ll just get the one for 1800
But if he says he only has a thousand bucks in his hand
then 1800 might not be for one
it could be for 610
right?
You pay 1800 for one
and then you get three
they've already calculated it for you
just to use up the five or six thousand you have
so that's how it is for kids from the countryside
This is how you might say it
A common trait among kids from poor families
is that once they get a large sum of money
like if I saved up 600,000
I'd want to buy the Xiaomi 47 Ultra
I really like Xiaomi
I admire Lei Jun
I like his products
I like Dong Ge too
I like Pang Donglai
I'll spend money there
I feel like that way I'm supporting a national entrepreneur
Is that really the case?
Dude, your social status hasn't changed
You still have the same income
Right?
So in many cases
We say that actually, children from poor families tend to waste money
and borrow money
and take out loans
and this is why
because they haven't been taught financial literacy from a young age
Most importantly, they need to be given money
given money
to learn how to save
Give him the credit card
Let him spend it
Let him experience what it feels like to be in debt
Don’t do it for him
He should also understand what debt is from a young age
What a loan is
What savings are
What it means to live within one's means
These concepts must be explained
Not to mention five or six years old
Not to mention ten years old
Eight or nine years old
You should at least teach them by the time they're 12 to 16
So when many parents talk about it
Regarding their children's sexual education
Financial matters
Issues of power, lying, and such
Including some of the unwritten rules in society
You're completely unprepared.
Just focus on your studies, that's all.
Don't worry about other things; your parents will take care of them.
Can your parents really think about arranging such matters for him, like going out to mate with others?
You've never let him date.
Not even in college.
So you want him to start mating right after graduation?
Just mating with strangers one by one, like blind dates.
And then they go straight into the bedroom together.
Isn't that for a fool?
Does that person understand?
Does he understand these things?
He might have understood.
But his understanding comes from those pornographic materials.
He hasn't had proper education.
Why would your parents drop the ball like this?
Your parents keep giving him this stuff.
They're driving him to the point where his mental health is suffering.
Pushing him to study all the time
Forcing him to be healthy
Oh, I think you don't understand
You don't know how tough the future society will be
Do you know how your family will survive in society in the future?
You haven't even taught him financial literacy
So, when it comes to you, these parents
What kind of background do parents really have
They bring that background with them
Your parents' generation was like that.
Your children won't be much better off than your parents.
Your parents' generation was quite backward.
From the perspective of a low-level labor force's mentality.
I'm not saying I look down on any workers.
Nor am I looking down on any poor people.
When it comes to people.
We are a country where the people are in charge.
But you need to understand.
This society is competitive.
Some people live in luxury.
And some face hardships.
You don't think that's fair, do you?
The purpose of your studies,
Isn't it to avoid living like this today?
To make tomorrow better?
What's the prerequisite for a better tomorrow?
To ensure your children don't suffer like you do,
What's the prerequisite for them not to endure so much hardship?
If you struggle with learning yourself,
And you push them to study every day,
Isn't that a dead-end problem?
Because you're not smart,
They might not be either.
So why not cultivate them in other areas?
You need to understand,
It's not just about academic learning.
You can't replace their financial awareness with these things.
The less money you have,
The earlier you should give them some.
You need to instill in them the awareness,
That the family isn't wealthy.
That the family isn't well-off.
So they think about earning money,
And saving money.
If they don't know how much the family has,
They won't understand the value of money.
Once they have a bit more money,
They might spend it with friends,
Or worse, turn to crime when they run out.
This mindset can lead people astray.
It's crucial,
To instill a proper concept of money.
The concept of money is truly very important.
Many parents fail to instill this awareness from a young age.
So when they grow up,
They face all sorts of problems,
Debt,
Bankruptcy,
These are very real issues.
No matter what you say about morals and values,
Personal pursuits and beliefs,
All these things are important,
But if you make mistakes with money,
If you can't make ends meet,
Your family could fall apart.
No amount of insurance can fix that.
These lessons must be taught to children from a young age.
So if there are any parents here,
Remember to get your child a credit card early,
Even a supplementary card,
Give them their own money early,
Teach them to save,
Instill in them a sense of financial literacy.
Because poor children tend to spend freely,
Being extravagant,
While rich children tend to be modest and cautious,
Not arrogant or restless.