This is also the last day of the Qingming holiday.
But for this episode, let's talk about
a fundamental aspiration of the Chinese people: to honor and glorify their ancestors.
The idea of honoring and glorifying one's ancestors is quite understandable.
For many years, society has been this way.
The relationship between sovereign and subject, father and son, you know.
But let's talk about the idea of bringing glory to one's ancestors; it's actually a false notion.
How should I put it?
You might think your ancestors were very powerful,
but in fact, all of your ancestors had already surrendered during the Qing Dynasty.
Right?
Because those who were stubborn were mostly killed, you see.
So, when you talk about who your ancestors were,
it's actually not that important.
You just want to say who the most impressive person in your ancestry is.
Someone as remarkable as you.
That's what you want to say.
But in reality, who your ancestors really are
you don't really care about.
So who was your great-grandfather?
What was his name?
What did he do in his life?
You have no idea at all.
So we say that creating a family tree is a task worth dedicating a night to.
This is what truly deserves our pursuit.
It means you admire your ancestors.
But it’s not very practical.
What we call glorifying the family name,
is essentially about saving face,
but it’s not really that useful either.
The most important happiness in life is making yourself feel good.
It’s all about making yourself happy.
Then it brings glory to the ancestors.
What I mean is, these two things are actually the same.
It’s one and the same thing.
It's about realizing one's own value.
So, realizing one's own value is the most crucial thing.
Many years ago, my grandfather wanted to change our surname back to Tian.
But we all opposed it.
Because we thought the name Xinrong was really cool.
We don’t care whether it’s the maternal or paternal surname.
It doesn’t really matter.
So when my child was born,
it came down to what the surname would be,
I wasn’t particularly concerned about it.
After all, many years ago,
people placed a lot of importance on family lineage,
on the continuation of bloodlines,
and this is closely tied to inheritance,
to the division of assets.
What we call the son taking over the father's business
the son carrying on the father's legacy
is quite common
and then there's also the issue of buying and selling land and property
so in an agrarian society
we see the situation where men are esteemed and women are devalued
but now we're in a stage of urbanization in major cities
if we talk about this phase
in the post-commercial era
It was also the age of industry and commerce.
In this era,
the connection to land ownership has become largely irrelevant,
forming no direct link anymore.
Moreover, both men and women are considered heirs.
So, in many cases,
this logic,
this notion of passing down from father to son,
no longer applies.
The feudal land order in ancient times
The feudal order was passed down from father to son
It extended from father-son relationships to those between ruler and minister, husband and wife
So, we're talking about the traditional culture of China.
Many aspects are worth preserving
But it’s important to know where they come from
Understanding why they exist is key
For example, ancient people said not to bathe at night
And not to wash your hair at night either
Back then, there were no hair dryers, right?
In those days, there was no lighting at night.
A lot of things were different.
So the logic behind it is different as well.
You don't have to worry about all the taboos of your ancestors.
What's most important is achieving self-actualization.
Once you achieve self-actualization,
your ancestors will be proud of you.
Like me
Sometimes when I feel really drained,
I encourage myself,
I tell myself I was 12
when I started the Long March.
Right?
Being from Ruijin,
I was an orphan from a young age,
and my grandfather raised an army at a young age.
Then they went to fight against the Japanese.
At that time, the Eighth Route Army hadn't arrived yet.
So in many cases,
these people used real-life examples to motivate themselves.
I must be the strongest child born from both families.
This is the strongest kid.
I usually encourage myself like this.
But sometimes when you encounter setbacks,
you don't have to use these things to discourage yourself.
At any point in time,
when we evaluate a person's life,
we talk about their lifetime achievements and faults.
For most people,
my ancestors,
whether they are distant ancestors,
or more recent ones like great-grandfathers,
are actually quite distant lives to me.
What truly gets passed down is some of the genes.
All the right things these people have done
and the failures they've experienced
are ingrained in their DNA
passed down from generation to generation
so this is quite interesting
this is truly something worth commemorating
but sometimes
when we talk about achieving something
it's important to align with human nature
Sometimes it goes against human nature
When it comes to things that align with human nature
It's about other people
It's about understanding how others are
You need to respect their human nature
You need to respect the objective laws of human behavior
For example, if someone is cold-hearted
Being harsh and unkind is quite normal
You have to accept them
For myself
it often requires going against human nature
for example, when we are the laziest
the time we least want to work is precisely when we should work
like right now, I'm comfortably lying in the hotel
I really don't want to record a video
But I'm going to record a video right now.
because it's the Qingming Festival holiday
since this is when there's a lot of traffic
Because this is when everyone is watching
So this is the right time to record
So you shouldn’t be talking about not working
This is when you should be working the most
Like yesterday when I went to a comic convention
Basically, we've got ten followers.
Having ten followers is quite a lot already.
Having ten followers is already quite a lot.
Despite having over 600,000 followers
But actually, it's already great to have so many people here.
Then we had a 30-minute session.
On stage.
Actually, not many people spoke on the stage.
The guest spoke for 30 minutes.
But I was given this opportunity.
I talked about a lot of topics.
But to be honest, in terms of the audience here,
Most of them came to see the young cosplayers.
So during my teens and early twenties
people weren't particularly interested in what I had to say
but this is when you get a chance
an opportunity to hone your skills
not everything is a grand moment with thunderous applause
you don't wait for the perfect audience to speak
often, you have to play the lute to the ox
you might find yourself speaking to people who aren't your ideal audience
but you still need to speak up
What are you going to do about it?
Right?
Don't even mention it.
It's on April 19th this month.
The book's launch signing
will take place at the Shandong Book City in Jinan, Shandong.
It starts at two o'clock in the afternoon.
I hope you can join us.
Well, this is my first book, so there might be some pitfalls.
This is the first book of my three major life strategy books.
The second book is titled 'Perspective'.
The third book is called 'Winner'.
Actually, two of these books have already been completed.
The third one is still in the planning stage.
But the two have already been finished.
The first one has already been published.
And I welcome everyone to place your orders in a timely manner.
Attending my book signing event is really a great experience.
In life, there are many times when we can't control things.
When we can't control the situation,
we should learn to adapt and be content.
And when we can control things,
we shouldn't put too much pressure on ourselves.
We often say we need to strive,
but when it comes to striving,
striving is about going with the flow of fate.
Striving doesn't change our destiny.
You can't change your destiny
Who are you
Whose memories do your genes carry
Where will you go in this life
Major trends can't really be altered
But minor issues
How many points do you think you'll score this time
How do you think you'll perform this time
Will you perform above or below your potential
This is something you can control yourself.
So, when it comes to these things,
Speaking of life in this world,
Sometimes you need to take a risk.
Of course, when taking a risk,
It usually means giving it 80%,
Or going all the way to 120%.
But more often, when it comes to the gifts of fate,
You can't avoid them.
So, as a gift of fate, you know,
no matter what,
If you dislike this gift of fate
you can change your destiny,
right?
You can change your destiny,
and there are many ways to do it,
we’ve mentioned,
in the course of a lifetime,
In my view,
my destiny hasn't changed,
Because my destiny has always been in tune with this main theme
Always in my main theme
which is the thing I most want to do, hovering around it,
so when I move further away from this main theme,
fate pulls me back,
and when I get closer to the main theme,
fate gives me a nudge,
encouraging me to focus on it,
so to sum up,
I believe that in terms of my destiny,
it has always played a protective role for me,
so it hasn't prevented me from achieving my goals,
but rather helped me achieve them,
this relies more on willpower,
This thing relies more on willpower.
so when people talk about destiny being clear and evident,
well,
Emperor Zhuge Liang,
with his clear and noble spirit,
and his bold and resolute actions,
so often it's about realizing self-worth,
it's a psychological suggestion to yourself,
realizing self-worth leads to honoring your ancestors,
so I hope everyone has a happy Qingming Festival,
while paying respects to your ancestors,
you should also encourage yourself,
truly honoring your ancestors means,
in simple terms, achieving your life's aspirations.