and their personal life experiences.
That's why I often say, someone like Lü Bu,
why is he known as the Righteous Marquis?
It's because he never betrayed the Han Dynasty.
The so-called killing of Ding Yuan,
and the killing of Dong Zhuo,
It was all the emperor's doing.
So, to speak.
The historical Lu Bu,
in fact, was never referred to as a traitor to three lords.
As for who the villains are in the Romance of the Three Kingdoms,
it's actually quite simple.
The Yellow Turban Rebellion was just.
All the others were villains.
Why did Luo Guanzhong hold Liu Bei in such high regard?
Because Luo Guanzhong also participated in the peasant uprisings at the end of the Yuan dynasty.
So he should respect Liu Bei
In fact, he compares himself to Zhuge Liang
So the rest of the people, like Cao Cao
And Sun Quan
And all sorts of other people
Chen Shou's History of the Three Kingdoms follows the orthodox narrative of the Wei, Jin, and Southern and Northern Dynasties, which regards Cao Cao as the legitimate ruler.
So he couldn’t possibly speak ill of Cao Cao
Therefore, when it comes to it
These authors tend to criticize Lu Bu
But actually, Lu Bu was a good person
History, they say, is like a young girl who can be dressed up by anyone.
Speaking of which,
we can't help but think about
why so many Chinese films and TV shows
we're not talking about a sequel to Nezha here,
because these are entirely different concepts.
why even the films and TV shows are hard to watch,
it's really frustrating,
it's because these are the things that people deal with in their daily lives,
they are the children of mistresses.
So in TV shows, it's all about mistresses getting the upper hand
or the legal wife fighting with the mistress
stuff like that
because even in those campus romance dramas, it's the same
mostly about
one moment, some delinquent hanging out at a club
the next, some rich kid
and then
bickering and jealousy over them
and then, the campus romance isn't all that great either
You just feel it's so strange.
Was it like this when we were in high school?
No, these people never went to high school.
So when these people think about the schools they attended,
it was just like this.
They were always fighting and falling in love.
No one cared about the college entrance exam.
Because these people scored 100 on the college entrance exam,
200 points,
or 300 points to get into college.
So, it's hard for people from different backgrounds to empathize with each other.
Yeah, I've got a sense of what's been going on these past couple of days.
I have a particular fondness for the 'commoner princess' genre.
But many of my female followers are commoner princesses
It's my female followers
often have to deal with some creepy guys who say things like
I can get you a job
I can take care of you
What do you think about that
They often make all sorts of job offers as an excuse to promise the girls things.
I just think it’s really fun.
Basically, men love to do two things,
one is to persuade decent women to enter the sex industry,
and the other is to persuade people to reform.
They earn money with their own abilities,
what’s wrong with that?
And do you think women in this line of work
would be swayed by your sweet talk?
They hear nonsense from people like you every day,
making all sorts of empty promises.
But you're talking to them like that
I'll take you to prepare for the postgraduate exam
I'll get you a stable job
Don't mess around with this and that
In reality, this is all a form of condescension
He just wants to freeload
He just wants to play with you for free
So once the novelty wears off
What else will he come up with
Another plan will emerge
So this person is always packaging their true intentions.
People can never fully empathize with each other.
That's why anyone with a different background can't...
can't completely relate to you.
Because they can only imagine.
By projecting their own thoughts...
to imagine what your life is like.
So it's really hard for people to empathize with each other.
Speaking of all the different backgrounds in China...
I think among all these backgrounds...
The ones who have it the hardest are the left-behind children and those from small towns who work odd jobs.
Some are even left-behind children plus small-town Dijia fans.
It's these people who have driven China's urbanization process.
They have also propelled China's economy.
These people have had it incredibly tough.
Let's talk about the food delivery riders you see every day.
They might have been left-behind children 10 or 20 years ago.
Left-behind children form a distinct social class.
A very tragic product of an era.
To be honest
Parents moved to the city for work
There was no other choice
The children stayed with their grandparents
They learned to manage the household from a young age
Managing a poor household
It means taking care of the housework
Not being the master of the world
And many people are also known as diligent students
They came from a very remote mountain village to the city
He became lost when he arrived in this new place
It was not an easy start.
Because the foundation of all material wealth had to be earned through hard work.
It all depended on myself.
It was extremely challenging.
So I've been consistently recommending to everyone in this video
If you come from a very humble background,
You might consider going abroad.
That could be a good path.
But if you are fortunate and strong, like a high-ranking official,
And if you are from a weak family, you should seek opportunities elsewhere.
If you really don't have much material wealth,
I suggest you start a business early.
Because some paths are not meant for you to climb.
You won't be able to climb them.
I especially don't recommend not finding locals,
When you go to a city, it's best to find locals.
Preferably city dwellers,
Locals are the best choice.
In that case,
it won't be a double no.
Families without a local hukou in the city
face the greatest economic burden
which is the most painful
and often, even marrying a local comes with its own challenges
you still have to deal with various issues
how to handle them
but at least you don't have to worry about
which family to visit during the Spring Festival
this is a very practical concern
so I recommend that you consider carefully
Actually, there are deeper layers behind everything.
The foundation of sociology is deeply rooted in existence.
So, when it comes to many things,
I can't really experience the life of ordinary people in China,
that kind of hardship,
and that sense of where they come from.
You'll find that in the real world, many who do cosplay,
how should I put it,
those who end up in borderline roles,
whether on Douyin or our Bilibili platform,
You see, a lot of people
I'm not saying everyone
I mean, a lot of them come from relatively humble beginnings
often from rural families
and they themselves are not given much attention
and in their families, there's a preference for boys over girls
and they are treated very, very unfairly
so they mature really early
and come to the city
starting to work and struggle in society at a very young age
Especially when it comes to romantic relationships
These things have long been commonplace
He has seen through everything long ago
When you were in your teens, you were still in middle school
Still preparing for the high school and college entrance exams
He might have already entered society
So the intrigue and backstabbing he has witnessed
The warmth and coldness of human relationships he has seen
Far exceed what you have experienced
So many times
People shouldn't judge others just because they look about the same age.
Or because they look similar in appearance.
Just because someone else seems to be living a certain way,
don't easily judge their life.
We tend to think others should be just like us.
Why aren't you being compassionate?
Why don't you have time to be vegetarian?
Many things are like this.
People's experiences can't be fully empathized with by others.
So it's best not to judge each other.
On Bilibili,
most of the time,
Most of us belong to the intelligentsia.
the majority of people on Bilibili,
are capable of taking the college entrance exam,
have participated in the college entrance exam,
whether you attended a first-tier, second-tier, third-tier, or a 211, C9 university,
or are a graduate student or a doctoral student,
or an international student abroad,
or any other educational background
Whether you're a student from a domestic vocational college or a student who has upgraded from a junior college to a bachelor's program
you are all products of higher education
I've mentioned this population ratio several times
the data might not be entirely accurate
but this time I'm giving you the highest estimate
6.2%
which means the proportion in the total population
is actually not that high
there aren't many people in China with a general scientific literacy
That's why my slice has that vibe on Douyin.
It's completely different from what's on Bilibili
Because on Douyin, people's attention spans are very short
If you make things too complicated, they won't understand
But on Bilibili, you can explain complex ideas
And people on Bilibili, they even criticize others
What do they say about me?
They say I spread false information
What else do they say about me?
They say this disrespects the people's historical perspective
Or they wonder if I've been paid by foreign entities
Otherwise, it's all about your inaccurate expressions
This is all about the disputes among literati
This is all part of the intelligentsia's.
Why don't you have that kind of ancestral greeting
It's rare for 18 generations
Very rare
Most people are just saying
You're spreading heresies
Such things are somewhat
Because what the literati argue over is the truth
What we're debating is your logic.
Your logic is flawed, isn't it?
Your argument is not valid.
The sample space you provided is incorrect.
You haven't set up this group.
So everything you're saying is like this.
So it proves that...
The cultural level of Bilibili users is relatively high.
They are people with basic scientific literacy.
They have at least completed high school.
So, in most cases, this is different
One situation stands out as unique
Why do we need to discuss this today?
When it comes to the many aspects of human interaction
The empathy gap between you and others can't be bridged
Because your backgrounds are different
Our origins compared to those of ancient people
The social environments of life and death were different
Ancient people also varied among themselves
So when we try to understand others today
Make sure you think it through.
Consider the actual audience's genuine acceptance level.
So sometimes when you do something,
Why should crosstalk be vulgar?
Because the people who listen to crosstalk are vulgar.
Why do talk shows often focus on stories about students?
Because people who study and listen to talk shows, relatively speaking,
have a slightly higher level of education.
Really, just slightly higher.
Because ethical jokes might be less common.
It's more of a vivid reenactment of personal experiences.
So this inherently determines that, of course,
Let's talk about the talk show.
Stand-up comedy,
In foreign countries,
It's a very down-to-earth art form.
But in China, it's different.
Those who do talk shows are also highly educated.
So when it comes to crosstalk performers,
They are typically college graduates.
There might not be a very high level of academic degree
Perhaps just a junior college or an art school
Graduating from a drama school is already considered a high level
So this is a matter of cultural attainment
That's why we often don't understand
Why these old folks watch these short dramas
Oh, all sorts of domineering CEOs and such
The things written in web novels are so exaggerated
How can they still enjoy watching them
Because the audience isn't you
Why do you like me?
Because when I talk to you,
we are in the same social class,
we are in the same knowledge class.
Why is it that when it comes to my things
Why does it not get out there as much?
Why does the authority allow me to keep saying this?
It’s because the people who actually hear me out,
aren’t the ones who cause trouble,
aren’t the ones who don’t listen.
Those people can't understand such profound things.
And only someone like you would come to the city.
One choice is whether to start a business.
Whether to continue on a professional path.
So let me tell you,
This isn't casting pearls before swine.
This is like high mountains and flowing water.
This is something that truly makes a difference in your life.
Is it the same when I talk to someone who has been a chef since childhood?
Right?
But I'm not saying we have a top chef.
But let me tell you.
Often, people from different backgrounds.
Talking to them is pointless.
You can't change their destiny.
That destiny is hard to alter.
It might just be their lot in life.
That's why some people like my stuff
Some people dislike my stuff
It's because they might not need it in their lives.
Maybe he'll need it in his next life.
Maybe their life is very happy.
They don't need these things.
So when it comes to these things,
It means the stories are specifically told to those who are willing to listen.
Those who think about such matters.
So these things don't include the books I write.
They are written for a select few.
But most people can read them.
Most people can read them for entertainment.
But only a few people really listened.
He serves as a kind of executor.
This logic was put into action.
This is different.
So many things are like this.
People cannot accurately empathize with each other.
The people you can empathize with are those who share your background.
Or have a similar background.
That's what I said.
urban intelligentsia
This is something most people can share a common theory about with me.
So, a lot of times when you say,
I'm not part of the urban class,
I come from a remote rural area.
But now you're in the city, right?
You didn't stay in the countryside all the time,
If you stayed in the countryside all the time,
You won't be looking at my stuff either.
He asked why you would say that.
I mean, our content is tailored for who we're addressing.
Because the people at a lower level
can't break through their labor class
they are now thinking about basic sustenance
they are now thinking about how to survive
which is very crucial
so in our theory
for anyone
it's not lacking in universality
it only applies to a very narrow range
a very small group of people
So, these people on Bilibili truly have a promising future
as entrepreneurs
because your level of knowledge will match your level of assets
if you manage to save and earn normally
it can also be achieved
but as we've mentioned
I often say
don't engage in high-end consumption
but the country is encouraging consumption
why is that
Right?
Why is that?
Because consumption can boost the economy.
It's quite normal.
I've said that before.
Buying a house is a strategic decision.
Some areas are on the rise.
While others are declining.
Let's adjust our asset allocation.
We just need to make sure the places we buy in are on the rise.
We'll sell when it drops.
So these are all strategic statements.
It's not like you've been co-opted, Rongzhen.
Now you only dare to say these things.
No problem at all.
Actually, they can coexist without contradiction.
Because for someone about to start a business,
you obviously need to save money.
Right?
Of course.
If I could just be happy all my life,
then it's a matter of where to spend the money,
right?
So if you're not going to spend it here,
you could travel abroad every day,
and you wouldn't spend it domestically.
So, to put it simply,
a lot of things come down to who earns whose money,
so the logic for ordinary people is naturally production,
labor and consumption.
This is a very common thing.
But the question is whether you can take in what I say.
Proving that you're not just an ordinary person.
The books written by Luo Guanzhong weren't for the common folk, after all.
Right?
In ancient times, who could afford to buy books?
Can you spare a few dozen minutes?
In this video of mine,
It's almost reached a thousand views,
With 50 million plays.
These things have taken hundreds of hours of effort from many people
those who truly delve into it
those who really watch it
some who don’t miss a single episode
and some who wonder why
it’s because you are different
don’t underestimate yourself
never think you’re not good enough
or that you lack skill
you are among the elite in China
Perhaps you are not a scientific elite
Perhaps you are not an economic elite
Perhaps you are not a sports star
But among the vast population of China
Can you hear what I'm saying?
You can grasp the meaning of these words
You can delve deeper to identify logical flaws
This proves you are a well-learned person
You would at least be qualified to participate in the imperial examinations in ancient times
That is quite significant
That's because you are unique.
So don't feel that way.
You mean me?
I might not have the financial strength right now.
I don't have much.
I can't change my fate.
I didn't do well on my postgraduate exam.
I'm a failure.
That's absolutely not true, you are not a failure.
After going through the gauntlet of the college entrance exam,
You're not a failure anymore.
You're no longer a failure.
You've moved up from the ranks of the failures.
We're talking about those who are truly struggling.
The common folks who have a tough time.
People who have it really hard.
You haven't reached that level yet.
You haven't reached the level of a master in Sanhe.
Look at the master in Sanhe.
You look down from above.
You're not one to look up to.
There are many who aren't even as good as Mr. Sanhe.
Those who actually do daily jobs.
Those who actually work in electronics factories.
The real factory girls.
You're not at that level.
If you were at that level.
And you watch Bilibili every day.
You'd quickly rise above that level.
Because Bilibili is a reflection of all walks of life.
He presents to most people a middle-to-upper-level
the middle to upper-middle class intelligentsia
in their daily life
in big cities
their dining, entertainment, and leisure
their indulgences and where they go for fun
like many videos on Bilibili that show trips to Japan
trips to North America, or taking all kinds of exams
and how to participate in interviews
or how to live their lives
How to decorate?
It portrays China's intelligentsia.
and the daily life of the petite bourgeoisie
You are an intellectual
an urban youth and a member of the petite bourgeoisie
No matter what you were before
you are now
That's why you can appreciate these things
So let me tell you
Let me use the example of horse prices
You're always saying, look at you.
Selfish and greedy.
Selfish to the core.
Because you know who Machiavelli is.
You know that words ending in a vowel like Machiavelli’s name
are definitely Italian.
Or at least from a Latin-based culture, right?
Like Domino Mario, for example.
Words ending in a vowel are Latin.
They are Italian.
He's from the Roman lineage
These people
He's Italian
You wouldn't ask that
This Ma
This person is from which province in the northwest
You wouldn't phrase it like that
You wouldn't ask if he's from Gansu or Ningxia
Because you're someone who has received general scientific education
You're the hope of China's quality education
You have benefited from nine years of compulsory education
enjoyed the nine-year compulsory education system and participated in twelve years of education
and have even reached fifteen years of education
which makes you different from the average person
truly different
you don't know what real life at the bottom is like
you're not from the bottom
and don't think that being poor and being destitute are the same
being poor means having no hope of earning money
absolutely no hope at all
This is called poverty
So the government needs to help the poor
Being poor means having no money
Having no money
It's quite common
People are often just broke
What a good time to make money
But it’s not always like that
So you need to figure out how to make money even when times are tough
So you can still earn a living
So this is quite normal
That's why the government is promoting consumption
And boosting consumer spending
To stimulate the economy
This is a common thing
I would say you need to increase income and cut expenses
You need to prioritize things
It's not about not spending
But about when to do it
When to spend and when to save
When will we soar to new heights?
To elevate our spending level
To a higher economic class
You look just like Brother Rong
When we go out now, right?
This can stimulate more economic activity
It can boost our consumption level
Didn't we used to spend a few hundred a day?
Now we spend thousands or even tens of thousands a day
Isn't that so?
So this has benefits for the economy.
So what we're talking about is...
It's a form of delayed gratification, or how should I put it...
Now that we've taken you up a step...
It's even more beneficial for the national economy.
There are many entrepreneurs.
We can't rely on state-owned enterprises for everything.
Or solely on state-owned companies.
Government funding alone isn't enough.
You need to boost the private sector.
There need to be such people in the community
to drive these industries forward
you can't just hand over these industries to foreign capital
You can't say that all money-making industries are controlled by the Brahman caste in the county town.
controlled by foreign capital
you need to have national entrepreneurs
right?
you can't rely on the state for everything, especially major undertakings
like railway transportation, aerospace, and national defense
you leave the smaller, detailed tasks to the state
Some items
A coffee shop
Like, is it a massage parlor or something?
A laundry
These are things that individuals can run
You can't let foreign conglomerates swallow everything up
So this is normal
When it comes to many of our things
Don't say I don't encourage spending
It's that I don't encourage you, someone who might become a boss in the future, to do so
Now you're depleting your initial capital
Isn't that right?
I'm not talking about just any ordinary factory girl
We're not spending on these anymore
We're not even buying formula
Not having kids is an option, right?
I'm talking about you, you're different
You deserve my encouragement
You deserve my support
Because you have the potential to move up in the future