we first developed certain traits
and then later on, we developed others
which might seem useless at first glance
In fact, people are constantly adapting to their environment.
And also changing the environment.
Throughout human history,
the time spent on hunting and gathering has been much longer,
while the period of agricultural cultivation is relatively recent.
It’s a settled way of life.
People used to migrate in large groups.
The hunting lifestyle was similar to the migration patterns of animals.
However, the modern industrial and commercial society has given rise to new professions.
The merchant
earns from arbitrage
the true merchant, from the earliest traders to those skilled in emotional intelligence
to today's international merchants
which means wherever there's an arbitrage opportunity
there will be merchants
but the difference between the hunter's mindset and the farmer's mindset
what is the biggest distinction?
is that the hunter needs to make a catch every day
Otherwise, they would go hungry.
But farmers, however,
they can endure a period of hunger and poverty.
They can prepare in advance for the harvest of the year.
So, what evolved first in humans?
What came later?
There would be different traits.
Some people, for instance, are naturally prone to anxiety.
They might feel they haven’t accomplished much today.
He will feel upset
So you need large-scale self-deception
When it comes to many things in life
The reason I keep telling everyone
This large-scale, high-intensity self-deception is crucial
Is because in modern society
Many things due to a lack of resources
Due to the dynamics of interpersonal relationships and social status
Often you can't mobilize a lot of resources
At this point
you need to remind yourself
what is abundant
and what can be postponed
If you adopt a hunter’s mindset
you’ll start worrying about what you can’t get today
I want to mate
I need to find someone quickly
I want to eat
I have to hunt a lion.
How can we put that?
This has a probability of success.
From a hunter's perspective,
it's more about something found in the search process.
Many psychologists would advise you to
think like a farmer,
to know when to store seeds like a farmer,
and to know when to sow and reap like a farmer.
After the clouds clear, the moon will shine.
But at this point, you need to think the other way around.
Why can't I act like a hunter and leave after a single job?
In many cases,
thieves and bandits essentially emerge in the same way.
But when it comes to merchants,
it's a more modern concept.
With the advent of currency,
markets came into being.
You'll find in this crowd
which professions have evolved more recently
are better adapted to modern society
just like blood types A, B, AB, and O
AB being the most recently evolved
so a lot of things you have to look at the development of humanity
daily activities
and how they gradually transformed
so I'm telling you
The business books written by Jews
you must read them
The reason Jews are disliked
is because, well
the things they do poorly
you don’t need to learn
since you don’t have their flaws
but the good things they do
you can learn from them
To put it bluntly, in today's world,
what truly controls the world are these financial systems,
and when it comes to these financial systems,
it's the tangible merchants who hold the power,
for example, if you can handle the abstract side of things,
then go for the abstract side,
if you can't do the abstract,
then focus on the concrete side,
this is always an option.
In this era,
all the smartest or the most cunning people,
they are concentrated in the financial sector.
You have to believe this.
They are the ones who can quickly seize arbitrage opportunities.
But what about ordinary people?
Ordinary people tend to follow a principle of merchants,
which is to look at things from a distance and up close.
The farther away something is, the more it tends to be considered.
The more you rely on the internet,
when it comes to things nearby,
you can depend on opening a store,
all sorts of things,
so to speak,
modern people need to have a competitive edge,
merchants don’t get up early unless there’s profit to be made,
merchants adjust their strategies based on others' needs,
that is to say, the skills you possess
The industry you're in
don't pigeonhole yourself
always maintain a learning mindset
constantly explore new fields
observe how demands evolve
and take action accordingly
like many people now are starting deep tech ventures
writing books on these topics
or launching these training camps
What specific great use is there?
There isn't really any significant use.
He noticed this growing demand.
And he suddenly stepped forward.
So all of this,
is a response to the changing market needs.
This is the greatest quality of a businessman.
He will constantly adapt.
While a farmer will work towards a fixed goal.
So once his goals are set
others can predict him easily
he’s better off assessing and then shorting him
or taking advantage of his predictable moves
So for a farmer
in the context of modern society
this mindset works
it means setting long-term goals
unlike a hunter who tends to be more short-sighted
But from many strategic perspectives
we need to go back and forth
we need to be flexible
if you're going to take drastic measures, you need to think like it
the most important aspect of a businessman's mindset is that
let it go
don't mention it
many people will tell you to value integrity
to pay attention to all sorts of unnecessary things
When integrity no longer satisfies you,
When the contract you've set doesn't quite fit your needs,
You should go ahead and break it if necessary,
There are various ways,
To help you make changes,
To retract your decision,
Often things work out this way,
Because business is always evolving,
Once you see the benefit,
It no longer belongs to you.
The benefits from this thing are no longer on your side.
You need to adapt when it's necessary.
You can't cling to outdated methods.
In this case, it's crucial to cut your losses in time.
So, the evolution of modern human society,
from hunters millions of years ago to farmers tens of thousands of years ago,
and finally to merchants,
you must understand how this should be done.
The longer a person stays in a particular position on the evolutionary chain,
the longer they stay,
the deeper they go,
the higher their status in human society becomes.
That's why we often say,
sometimes it's a matter of mindset,
a mentality issue.
When your cognitive level rises,
naturally, other things will follow suit.
This is just one way to solve the problem.
Most Chinese parents teach you the mindset of an employee,
which is also the mindset of a farmer.
Endure hardship upon hardship,
and you'll stand out among the few.
So they keep giving you more hardships to endure,
right?
Who asked you to enjoy it?