What I'm trying to say is,
if you have 600,000 or even less than that,
don't spend it all on a car.
But many people clearly missed the point I was trying to make.
Some even called me a Huawei lackey.
Some people say I'm uh
because I didn't get the Xiaomi ad
I indeed didn't get the Xiaomi ad
but am I Huawei's pet?
Well, I am indeed Huawei's pet
because Huawei keeps sending me new phones
I've been using several phones that Huawei sent me
This is because I'm an internet celebrity
So how should I put it
Let's cut to the chase.
I've made up my mind.
Because on May 26th, I'll be getting a new Beijing license plate.
I finally got lucky in the lottery.
I've decided to buy a Xiaomi S7.
A lot of people say it's because you can't afford it.
That's why they bash Xiaomi.
They say Xiaomi isn't good.
So, let's do this.
It's because I can really afford it.
So, I'll get one then.
This way, you know, right?
I'll also join the Xiaomi camp.
It's a good thing to eat my own words.
I think it's a really great thing.
I can really afford the fuel.
Actually, I could buy several.
Right?
But I'll just get one; one is enough for me.