how should I put it
can speak smoothly and persuasively
can be considerate
especially perceptive and tactful
This person is actually quite submissive.
They are more suited for a career in public service.
They are more suited for pursuing a master’s degree.
People like this in East Asian societies,
make up a very large proportion of the population.
You might be this type of person.
Especially in Japanese society,
there are a lot of people like this.
Superiors often bully their subordinates.
The lifelong employment system is all about seniority and hierarchy.
Well, how can I put it?
It's utterly boring.
This kind of hierarchical system
it's holding East Asian societies back from moving forward.
Many people say to me, Brother Rong,
you're just a libertarian.
What's wrong with libertarianism?
In today's society, we talk about
You see everything as a form of commercial exchange
a form of communication
a form of negotiation
In the era of internet finance
This is the age we live in now
Finance dominates everything, right?
Commodification
After urbanization
Industrialization
In fact, all these things are involved in production and exchange.
Why is the United States at the height of its power?
It's not a matter of its political system.
The key lies in its core social norms.
I'm not just praising the U.S.
But when we talk about East Asian societies, China, Japan, and South Korea,
When we look at China, Japan, and South Korea,
Japan and South Korea are at the level of vassal states.
Isn't that right?
But why does it also have this kind of issue in its development?
What causes this kind of internal competition in East Asian societies?
It's our obsession with hierarchical systems.
The tendency to use any bit of power to the fullest extent.
There's a particular reverence for such things.
Admiration for power.
Respect for authority.
Desire for power.
Obsession with power.
I just want you to take the civil service exam
I just want you to gain power in the future
to bully others
That's the kind of mindset
That's not acceptable
In the modern business world
it's all about fairness
it's all about contract spirit
it's about following the rules
A society governed by law
We have never said we want to create a hierarchical society
But in reality, there are many people
Who want to revive the Confucian system
And restore the rituals of the sovereign and his ministers
And the practices of the scholar-officials and nobles
To the real society
I am a Brahman
You have to listen to me
It's not okay if it doesn't work.
This kind of thing actually hinders social progress.
But when it comes to the people around you,
many of them have a stronger tendency to be submissive.
So, this person's traits only have two extremes.
Only two extremes.
It is constantly evolving.
We say that things are always what?
One gives rise to two, two gives rise to three.
Out of three, myriad things come to be
I've mentioned this thing has two extremes
This thing goes from zero to one hundred percent, right
Actually, it's always just from 0 to 1
Or from 1 to 0
It all starts with an initial thought
This thing begins to exist
And then it falls back from this state
To nothingness
It's always in a state of ascending or descending.
Because binary can represent everything in the universe.
So why is there a three in the universe?
Three comes from having two bits.
With combinations like 1001 or 11.
That's how you get three.
Three is a combination of the two extremes.
Either one-zero,
or zero-one.
It's either one
or it's zero
Many people might not understand this concept
This is derived from the Daodejing
So, all twos represent a kind of opposition
a give-and-take relationship
The more obedient you are
the stronger your servility becomes
the more rebellious you are, the stronger your individuality becomes
When comparing East Asian societies to Western ones,
in Western societies,
individual personality stands out,
I'm not saying that this is necessarily better in Western societies,
I'm just saying they effectively utilize it for commercialization,
in the pursuit of personal freedom,
it proves to be very useful.
East Asian societies, on the other hand, emphasize commonality,
and emphasize conformity.
Respect for hierarchy and seniority is important
That's right
Hierarchy and seniority are like that
That's why there's a distinction between men and women
That's why there's patriarchy
That's why these things exist
And there's also hierarchy
It's all about these concepts
Even though you want to break free from these constraints
You need to be a person of the new era.
You should have a revolutionary spirit.
To always maintain a youthful revolutionary spirit,
you must have the courage
to break down these outdated feudal and corrupt ideas.
This spirit
Many people say
is about traditional Chinese learning.
This is our cultural treasure.
What do you mean by cultural treasure?
If culture turns you into a turtle,
then you really treat it as a treasure.
Isn't that right?
So often, you are this thing,
it doesn't align with our interests in reality,
it doesn't fit our evolutionary path,
we should decisively abandon it.
It's evolution
Isn't it about discarding the old
and embracing the new?
Right?
So, Eastern and Western societies
each have their own flaws
if you can bridge these gaps
fill in the blanks
it will lead to Eastern learning and Western construction
Why not make it complementary?
Whoever masters the advanced productive force in the future,
whoever can push society forward,
that's who will be right.
Always talking about those outdated things,
those feudal bureaucratic things.
As I said, some places are really like that.
Brother Rong likes to criticize,
and sometimes likes to talk about it.
Don't try to be like me
because I'm getting up there in years
and what I say doesn't carry much weight anymore
since I'm already old
I can't cause much of a stir anymore
unlike the young folks
when young people get upset
everyone gets scared
you know, us old folks
It's fine to chat a bit
No one really cares
So it's all good
I can say whatever I want
You young folks shouldn't jump to conclusions
Most importantly, many companies
Let's not name any specific ones
But a lot of companies are addicted to meetings
However, they don't generate profits
Losing money every day
But they insist on using this bureaucratic system
To buy a ballpoint pen
You have to file seven reports
This kind of thing is taken to the extreme
And then your parents tell you
You should join this kind of company
You should apply to work for this kind of company
You need to have a position.
So, this kind of thing really drags down social efficiency.
Thus, we end up with a bloated organization.
Once there is such a place,
it constantly acts in its own interest,
consuming social resources.
That’s how it is.
So, I suggest that those who are capable,
start private businesses.
It's important to develop these aspects well in a private business.
To boost the economy.
Pang Donglai is a private enterprise, after all.
Imagine if Pang Donglai were to undergo restructuring and become something else.
Would that be the case?
So, a lot of times, you need to understand these things.
When certain types of people come together,
they create a particular kind of living atmosphere.
Many people often say,
Bro Rong, I took the civil service exam.
But later on, I couldn't adapt.
You couldn't adapt?
No one could really adapt to that.
If you don't have such strong servility,
how could you adapt?
Morning briefings every day,
and evening reports,
what's the point of all that?
To be honest
in today's society, we should generate value
they say the economy is in a downturn
if you lack the ability to create economic value
you're just burning through money every day
how can that be acceptable
right
so in many cases, we need to conduct a thorough self-reflection
often it's because your innovative spirit isn't strong enough
You've also fallen out of step with the times.
In that case, you're lagging behind others.
That's why we often wonder why you're in the red.
Why you run into issues.
It's because you're too submissive.
You don't have that.
How do you say it?
The ability to gauge the direction of the wind.
Everything is about seeking guidance early on.
Evening report
Everything requires compliance
This isn't the military
The military is different
The army has combat effectiveness
There must be strict adherence to orders
Some people try to run their businesses this way
Using feudal and bureaucratic methods
Those methods belong to the 263 years of the Qing Dynasty
The things that are ruined
You need to pick them up
Those things
So in many cases
I think this is the driving force for progress
A country
The most tragic thing for a nation is not having these things
It's a feudal inertia
It doesn't matter
But the most tragic thing is that in many places,
I won’t specify which places,
people treat these things like treasures.
Even young people fall for it,
which is really concerning.
I’ve seen a lot of stuff on Douyin,
teaching people how to read between the lines,
how to gauge others’ intentions,
and how to set up schemes.
Teaching people how to do harmful things
Teaching people how to do what
I really hate all of this
Why I introduced Machiavellianism
It's necessary to break all of this
To break the notion that power should be prioritized
Everything is about flattering power
Is this the state a person should be in in modern society
I'm asking you
So, let's talk about it.
For a society to move forward, it must develop in a positive direction.
We are now, in my view,
already a moderately developed country.
We should have a normal business culture.
We can't still prioritize agriculture over commerce.
Are you a farmer?
You don't even farm.
Right?
You just be yourself
cultivate your own bit of authority
so this is extremely terrifying
I say people need to change their servile nature
and must stop fawning and kowtowing to power
that kind of fear is incredibly terrifying
don't think I'm always criticizing the people of Jing-Jin-Ji
of course
this time we can't include Hebei
What makes the people of Beijing and Tianjin so strong
You know what
It's that they're not afraid of officials
Why should they be afraid of officials?
I have a classmate who came from another place to study
I'm not saying anything about him
One time, we were walking down the street
Suddenly, his legs went weak
Oh, he said, 'That's the county seat back home'
The local big official
The top leader
Oh
My legs are shaking
Really shaking, they are
Then he said
That person is incredibly wealthy
And has immense power
Really formidable
I thought he was coming to Beijing.
What’s so great about him?
Right?
Then he would have to come over too, wouldn’t he?
When he comes over, he’s just an ordinary person.
I’m a native of the capital city.
I damn well don’t care about you.
Right?
So, it’s this spirit of not fearing authority that we’re talking about.
People in Beijing and Tianjin don’t buy that.
Don’t try to intimidate me with your power.
For 300 or 400 years in Beijing,
there have been plenty of princes and nobles.
What kind of act are you putting on with me?
Are you kidding, using a Ming dynasty sword to execute officials of this dynasty?
Are you holding a rotten fish or what?
Do you really think you’re something special?
That’s why I’m asking you.
What's most crucial for us young people is to break this culture of being obsessed with officialdom.
The worship of power.
No, that's not it.
Having no respect for the law in one's heart.
That's not what it's about.
It's about not bowing down to authority,
Not blindly fawning over individuals.
It's meaningless.
We should have ideals in our hearts.
Be ethical
have a spirit of the rule of law
don't engage in those feudal practices for no reason
everything should be about seeking approval and reporting first
a lot of the time, these things are incredibly boring
these things really slow down the pace of societal progress
we say that people should keep moving forward
keep developing
keep evolving
constantly seeking true knowledge
constantly verifying
constantly falsifying
that is the spirit of science
the spirit of science
rather than certain things
spending the whole day, how to put it
once you're on the royal payroll, you start doing things against your conscience
that's not serving the people either
Right?
You're serving yourself, right?
So often we say
If you want to break out of this mindset
First, don't just assume
Everything is right because parents say so
Everything is right because teachers and schools say so
Question more things
Doubt everything around you
That's when things get interesting
Otherwise, you'll live
In your twenties like a sixty-year-old
What's the point of that?
Brother Rong was also very restless in his youth
But now he's much more peaceful
Why, when we have more now
We should always maintain a youthful state
Always engage in self-criticism
Always adjust to societal norms
This is something that should always be done
My ideal is to promote the development of commercial culture
To promote the exchange of ideas between the East and West
A combination
Mutual complementation
You can't say we've entered the 21st century
And now we're bringing back feudal practices
Things that have been rotten for thousands of years
Things that have made us weak and impoverished are being revived
Is this called maintaining revolutionary youth?
What is this?
Right?
This is a kind of
To put it bluntly, you don't have that genuine concern for others
You don't have a pure heart to serve
You're just serving your own power
You're doing this
You're just making a show
So this is what we call class solidification
This is what we call the revival of feudal forces
These are the things that should be prevented first
We talk about a young person
If he also kneels and licks
If he also shows up with no dignity
With a servile attitude
If this is the case
Then this society is truly pitiful
That would make this society too pitiful.