I'll start packing tomorrow,
and of course, there are some bank matters to take care of,
plus the broadband bill to pay,
a whole bunch of things to do.
Anyway,
Now I've reached a pivotal moment in my life
Let me move on to the next point
I'm not sure if the choice I'm making now is the right one
But in the future, I'll understand many things in life
If I had to do it all over again
I might do a better job
But do I really want to start over?
When I think about it carefully
For instance, before I had my son
Over the years, if just one wrong choice was made
or rather, a different choice
he wouldn't have been born
So I think we should just let the past be
It doesn't matter, because he is such a wonderful presence
That is to say, if you really went back in time on any path
you could actually change yourself
They say a person has six chances to change their fate each day
and you might just miss one
Or the timing of doing something can make all the difference
Its outcome can be entirely different
So we say there aren't too many regrets in life
But what is my regret in life?
There are a few things that really stick with me
What are they?
One is the choice of my major in college
Another is the timing of when I started in the media industry
The choice of my major in college
Let me think about everything
Everything that can be controlled
Makes me feel that the choice of my major in college
Was not a good one
First, I didn’t really understand what broadcasting and hosting entailed
I didn’t have a clear understanding of it
I tend to think in a habitual way
Because when I was in high school
I had always been a host in elementary school
So I wanted to study broadcasting.
But broadcasting is for announcers, after all.
Whether it's English or Chinese.
I got accepted into both.
Getting into a media university is the hardest.
But if I were to apply for an acting program,
Not the acting programs at the Central Academy of Drama or the Beijing Film Academy,
Even the acting programs at less prestigious schools,
We're talking about acting programs in Chinese universities.
There are 12345 levels
Even for the performance major at the fifth level
It’s almost certain that you will pass
And once you pass
Generally speaking, the cultural course will suffice
But it’s different for the broadcasting major
Over 560 points
That’s not something everyone can achieve
This was my first regret in life
It was because I chose the wrong major in college
and then I went abroad to study
to make up for that mistake from my youth
taking a big detour
but this detour gave me a lot of valuable experiences
costing me a lot of money
and a lot of time
basically my entire twenties were spent on education
so this is one of the major regrets I have
The second thing I regret is also related to studying abroad.
I didn't seize the opportunity with YouTube.
Some people say, isn't YouTube for the international web?
Actually, it's not like that.
Back then, I spent most of my time overseas.
So when I was in France,
and in Canada,
I could have been doing these things.
And if I had started from 2008,
I started doing it from 2009
and continued all the way through to 2010 and 2011
In 2014
even from 2014 to 2015, doing it this way
I definitely have at least 100,000 followers on YouTube now
maybe even 300,000
this has formed a very stable source of income for me
it might have influenced all the paths of my life since then
that's why I'm now trying to get things going again
Including our Bilibili
When it comes to Bilibili
For me
This is now my core area of focus
But these things are far from enough
Looking to the future
As you all know, I plan to live in seclusion
Continuously traveling to different countries
It's best to have a channel on YouTube.
Followers need to grow gradually.
No one becomes an overnight sensation.
So, it's essential to build up your presence over time.
That's why it's crucial to plan ahead.
Today, I've talked about this with everyone.
Actually, my long-time followers are well aware of my situation.
But many of my new followers don't know about it.
Including the choices I made when I was younger.
This means the place you're in right now
No matter what you're doing
I often have this feeling
That no matter what you're doing
There's always a better choice than the one you're making now
It's just that you don't know it
If you could look back
At what you're doing now
It might not be what you should be doing right now
So often we say that people should make more friends
listen to advice more
because listening to advice and making friends, right?
when you gain insights from others
for example, when you watch my videos
you might reflect on yourself
you might choose some new and different people
you need to meet new people
and then you need to read books
Why do we read books?
Reading is not just about acquiring knowledge.
It's about understanding what other paths are available in this world.
That's why I highly recommend everyone to read works by economists.
Especially modern ones from Japan.
And writings by economists from the United States.
Including those from earlier times.
American economists
Including those early statements
Including books by philosophers and the like
He can help steer your life in the right direction
This is crucial
So often, we shouldn't just keep reading these kinds of things
Novels by authors and such
I think novels by authors can certainly refine one's sensibilities
But their role in guiding life is not significant
That's why I especially recommend reading some philosophy
And economics
Some reference works in political science
including materials on sociology
because these topics are more closely related to your life
especially books on economics
which cover broad overviews of economic concepts
they can be quite instructive for you personally
particularly books on financial management
they don't have to be overly formal
but they can hit the nail on the head
But he can also tell you
about other people's lifestyles
how many different kinds of people there are in this world
You can share these insights
So reading and getting to know people are relatively quick ways
Most other things are just a waste of our lives
like eating
like sleeping
like interacting with others
This pursuit of a great harmony in life
All these things are merely the cycle of fulfilling desires
Eating and sleeping
Breathing and drinking water
But what truly elevates you
Or helps you on your life's journey
Is reading
Reading and watching videos
And making friends with people
Making friends with people is actually a more convenient method.
Of course, some people might not be good at socializing.
But I think learning from people is faster than learning from books.
And people can spark your interest much earlier and more effectively.
Once you've spent some time deeply connecting with someone,
you can extract a lot of their life experiences.
And the convenience that comes with their choices.
For example, if you and I become close friends,
I would share with you some of my life experiences.
So this is my video
Sometimes the reason why people like it so much
It's also because of the videos
That's how everyone gets the chance to connect with me on a deeper level
The opportunity for deep interaction
So more often than not
If you can spend some time on mentors and good friends
It can be very beneficial
Another thing is buying books
But what kind of books should you buy?
After all, there are countless books out there.
So, you might need recommendations from others.
Because the recommendations in other people's videos,
due to others' influences,
you end up reading certain books,
which might be ones you'd never normally consider buying.
That's why some people will share what's on their reading list,
and then recommend mine in the comments section.
The reading lists I've been looking at
I think these reading lists are quite introductory
They're fairly basic stuff
But they can guide you into a broader
Spectrum of exploration
So I think most of the time, if you're someone who's motivated
Don't just use your time scrolling through short videos
Of course, you should still watch short videos
But also explore the more diverse content on our platform like Bilibili
Don't keep staring at the big swing swaying back and forth.
All kinds of BGM can really stimulate your hormones.
They trigger the release of dopamine and endorphins.
But in reality, this is an activation of primitive desires.
It's about you gaining more territory,
getting more food,
and attracting more mating partners,
to complete mating,
and raising offspring—these are biological instincts.
As a human being
you have spiritual needs
you have cultural needs
these are the things that set you apart from others
the dividing line between humans and animals
so if you want to achieve more freedom in society
a higher position
you need to continuously enrich your knowledge
because compared to someone with shallow knowledge
and lower cognitive abilities
you will recognize the depth of your own knowledge
so many times
I still recommend spending more time buying and reading books
going to the library to read
even e-books
you might have downloaded so many
but downloading them doesn't mean you've read them
try to flip through them when you have free time
reading is always beneficial
and try to
before you accumulate your first pot of gold
spend less money
reduce indulging in food and drink
you're young
don't compare yourself to a 40-year-old
young people are often susceptible to excessive spending
don't work just to consume
normal spending
to maintain a decent lifestyle is fine
but don't work
for your consumption
or desires
that's the worst thing, as it traps you in a vicious economic cycle