some say we should listen to others’ advice
because listening to others can make you humble
and help you embrace good things
while others say we should trust in ourselves
Because only you know your own affairs
You have the intuition
You can know for sure
Well, how should I put it
We should analyze specific issues on a case-by-case basis
A couple of days ago
I attended the gathering of the Power Up department at Bilibili
We had a great time touring Wuzhen
I felt really good in Wuzhen
After all, I'm someone who enjoys lively environments
Actually, Brother Rong is the kind of person who
loves to participate in all sorts of exhibitions and events.
If you have any events,
I'd be more than happy to be a guest.
I'd go even if you didn't pay me,
just cover my travel expenses, that's all.
I don't eat much anyway.
I really enjoy being a guest for people.
But speaking of the content at the Power Up conference this time,
I can't really disclose it.
But it did give me a lot of
Really fresh perspectives and feelings
But this year, there was a bit of a backlash
There was also a downside
And that is
Your anxiety starts to build up
Oh, so many people are doing such a great job
Actually, they are motivating us to do better
But I noticed
The operations team gave us a lot of valuable suggestions
These suggestions have been compiled into a booklet.
Sometimes I flip through it to take a look.
All the Power Up areas,
along with various fan-growth strategies in the general sections,
and operational tactics like these,
are now gathered into PDFs.
We can go through them ourselves.
Based on these PDFs,
I made adjustments to the show myself.
After making these adjustments,
The effect is evident.
The revenue dropped by 50%.
More than 50%.
It had an immediate impact.
Because I mainly changed the cover design.
After changing the cover, everyone started using some AI-generated images.
And used larger fonts.
This is the result of other UPloaders' successful practices.
I also changed the preview duration.
From one minute.
Some changed to 10 minutes
Some changed to 3 minutes
Then I also changed the strategy
I stopped doing the series that were previously successful
I no longer categorized my series
I stopped dividing them into different categories
I just broke them down
These were halfway through when I just gave them titles
In this regard, I'm like most UPloaders
Right?
Compared to those big UPs,
they have more people powering them up,
they have a larger audience overall,
and they produce higher quality content as well.
So, I learn from them.
But let me tell you,
blindly copying them won’t do any good.
Blind imitation,
changing your tags,
will make people not recognize your videos anymore.
Often, people will click in
to watch my videos
not for the text
but to see my big face
and the red and green text on my face
and then they click in
just because it's on the Home page
and they click in
I change the cover
and people feel it's not the same bold content anymore
And changing the preview duration didn’t help either.
After changing the preview duration,
sometimes it fails to spark people’s interest.
Once they see it too much, they think,
Oh, it’s just the same old thing.
They won’t bother to click in anymore.
But I do have good content to share.
I have a loyal following,
who regularly check in to watch.
In a way, I’ve let down my long-time followers.
Always wanting to get
to gain some new followers
is actually not very likely
for someone to actually become your follower
it takes a long time
not just watching one or two episodes
sometimes watching ten episodes
twenty episodes
and suddenly one day, an inspiration hits
and it passes
Director Rong's stuff is really great
I'm willing to pay for Director Rong
It's been a long journey for him
So often it ends up being like pulling up seedlings to help them grow
Because I want to catch up with others
I want what others have
I have 30,000 Power Up
Others have 60,000 Power Up
Oh, others have 200,000 Power Up
Right?
I have 600,000 followers.
Someone else has a million.
They have 3 million followers.
First, you need to understand that the gap between people is quite common.
You can also look for subjective differences.
And objective differences as well.
Objective differences are straightforward.
It means they have a team.
Many people are just the faces in front of the camera.
They are the boss.
Many people have teams.
Some have over a dozen members.
Some have over a hundred.
Some have more than 200 members.
Teams with over 300 members are not uncommon.
So, they're not just running one account.
The boss is just the face of the operation.
That's why they all have teams.
But I'm flying solo on this short video thing.
Right?
And quite often, you know,
you have so many followers,
you really should have that many followers,
the limit of your Bilibili audience is those who like your content,
it's roughly that many people.
You keep thinking about gaining more followers, more followers, more followers,
constantly trying to take shortcuts,
to stand out,
but in fact, it’s more likely to lose followers,
and you might end up alienating your core audience.
Because your core audience expects you to consistently produce content.
And everything we talk about is trending.
It all has its moment in the spotlight.
After you've had your peak, it's natural that you won't be as popular.
That's a very normal thing.
But people just can't accept this fact.
In many cases, it's exactly like this.
Sometimes when I talk about others,
I myself also face similar issues.
It's about your physical functions.
Your appearance
all these energies of yours
will eventually decline over time
not just your account
your health
all your abilities
your reputation
your wealth will gradually diminish
think about some things
if I were a 95-year-old now
In a nursing home,
right?
Many families might no longer be around,
It’s uncertain whether anyone will come to visit me.
Isn’t that so?
Your own wealth,
You might even forget your bank PIN.
If you want to live a long life,
In terms of your life,
In the end, it will be reduced to a fraction of what it was.
You might find yourself unable to control everything about you.
In fact, that's often the case.
When people reach their later years,
the reality can be quite sad.
So, live your best life while you're young.
While you still have the energy and ability.
Though I, Brother Rong, have always been the type who,
doesn't recommend you to spend money recklessly,
if you want to travel,
go ahead and explore the world.
It's okay
Don't let the money you spent make you not want to go
Money spent is gone, don't be upset
We can always earn more
If we don't have much money
We can go on a motorcycle trip
If that doesn't work out
We can go on a budget trip by bicycle
It's all good
A budget trip doesn't mean you have to take a business class seat
Second-class seat
is just like hard seat for people
So, to talk about it
you should take advantage of your good health and travel soon
Bro Rong is currently dealing with something
so I can't apply for that
visa to certain places
So, to put it simply
because the immigration issue you're handling here
you need to apply for a tourist visa again
People will doubt you, though.
How did you end up in the second quadrant?
You have two aspects of thought.
Are you planning to go dark?
They won’t let you go.
But I really want to travel to many places.
However, there aren’t many opportunities right now.
Just go for it.
So life is full of regrets.
Like when I was in my twenties,
Back then, I wanted to go out
I visited many places
but I didn’t have money
so I couldn’t travel to more places
In my thirties
I was tied down by family
Actually, in my forties, I really wanted to go out
but now I’m still tied down by family
By the time I’m in my fifties, my health might not be as good
And at sixty, it’s even more unrealistic
Right or wrong
So, to talk about it
Take advantage of your youth
Make more friends
Go out more
Get out more
This can't really be called reckless, can it
On the contrary, go out more
It's about bringing harmony to your life
Isn't it about doing more activities that benefit your mind and body
It's really great.
Many things are just like that.
It's about your subjective feeling.
It doesn't match your objective circumstances.
The advice others give you,
well, it's not going to help much.
What have you done subjectively?
Actually, it doesn't work either.
It's a matter of timing, fate, and luck.
Often, you shouldn't take action at all.
Often, you need to follow the natural course of things.
It’s not always going to be an upward journey.
Sometimes, it involves going downhill.
When you’re on the decline,
try to enjoy the gradual descent.
It can actually be quite fun.
Right?
You’ll find that life has its ways of surprising you,
and as you grow older, new joys will emerge.
As you age,
You can delve into all sorts of mysterious events from ancient times
Can you just stay inside and read books?
When you're young, do more physically demanding activities
Look at me now, I'm in great shape
I sleep 14 to 16 hours a day
I'm so exhausted
I'm not sure if it's because I'm overweight
or if it's due to my blood oxygen levels
or if there's something else wrong with my body
But anyway, I just want to sleep this much every day
Of course, comparing ourselves to others can be really discouraging.
After all, comparison is the thief of joy.
So, don't go around comparing yourself to others for no reason.
As long as you don't compare yourself to others,
you're doing just fine.
The core reason for me is that
I always want to gain more followers,
I always want to earn more income,
I always want to maintain a high-income status,
I always want to keep this going.
But how can everything always move upwards?
Towards a better direction?
Sometimes you might just be at the end of your rope.
Or you might be out of tricks.
That's just how it is.
So you need to accept it all.
But if you force changes,
Force reforms,
Force alterations,
Some things might end up worse than before.
a state of slowly descending
so when we talk about life
of course, you should be proactive and strive forward
how should we put it
all sorts of challenges and struggles
you should move forward
keep moving forward
if you need to hustle, then hustle
but more importantly
you need to understand that a person's energy has its limits
Don't go by yourself
Don't force yourself to go against the tide
Wanting to change something
Sometimes, in fact
Going with the flow is the best approach
Go with the flow
Let it fall naturally
Let it rise naturally
If you grasp the pulse of the times
There's still a chance for it to rise
And some things just accumulate more slowly.
The economy might not be doing well right now.
So everyone finds it hard to make money.
So sometimes a drop in revenue is quite normal.
You can't say that because revenue has dropped,
there must be something wrong with your content.
You can't think he's cheating just because your wife is giving you less pocket money.
Just because your wife is giving you less money doesn't mean she's cheating.
That's how it is.
In many cases,
Subjective suspicions and speculations are unrealistic.
And objectively, others observing you is also impractical.
So, from both subjective and objective perspectives,
it's impossible to know the true reality.
The true reality remains a mystery.
Only heaven knows.
Therefore, in many situations, no matter what,
subjectively, don't make foolish mistakes,
and objectively, respect the facts.
That's all there is to it.