We're doing a second update today.
Why do we have to do a second update today?
Actually, the last two episodes have received a strong response from the audience.
Today, we're going to discuss one topic,
which is, what if we don't succeed?
Right?
You'll notice that many people in this world force you to study hard when you're in school
Don't play around
And then work hard when you start working
Don't indulge yourself
You'll find that many people who advise you to do so
It's because they can benefit from the value of your labor
It's that simple
Whether it's the value of your work or the taxes you pay
No matter what
you've made contributions to society
and to your boss, right?
but the more you contribute
the harder you work
so in many ways
we talk about what success is
Mr. Wang Shuo put it well
it's about outdoing others
Make some money
Then let everyone know
Then you'll find that this is a bottomless pit
Take Bill Gates, for example
Elon Musk
He could, with his eyes closed
In an instant
Millions or even tens of millions of dollars appear
Because they have tens or even hundreds of billions
At that moment
it was the interest he earned back then
he could make so much money
but you might not earn as much in your entire life as he does in a day
does that mean your life is meaningless?
besides, who says the meaning of life is about making money?
right?
why do many people feel that making money is so important?
why does it make you feel this kind of pressure?
It's because he can take the money you earn
and transfer it to others
who then engage in spending activities
and make a profit
for example, your partner
wants you to earn more money
because they hope to spend the money you earn
if you don't give them the money
they won't expect you to earn more
You're like Brother Rong
I never spend money on people around me
Who would wish for me to become wealthy?
If I keep giving money to others all the time
Always spending money on others
Everyone would wish me to get rich
But is wishing me to get rich necessarily a good thing?
Because they could benefit from me
So you should be a person who doesn't part with a penny
I wouldn't pluck a single hair to benefit the world, ha
I'll pull out one spear
I let others benefit
but I wouldn't do that
So, to put it simply
it means you shouldn't strive to be useful to others
or to society
or to the world, right
isn't that so
Why do you have to be that kind of person?
You only need 2200 calories a day.
You need a warm room.
Having a bed to sleep in is enough.
This is not hard to achieve.
Getting food itself isn't difficult.
It doesn't cost much.
So, in reality, a lot of extra income is unnecessary.
You have a few thousand now.
As a college student
or even a high school student
you've learned to ride a motorcycle
and then bought a second-hand motorcycle for around four to five thousand yuan
motorcycle training can range from a few hundred to over a thousand yuan
and then you start motorcycle touring
when you reach a destination
if you run out of money
you can do a few days of food delivery
That's just perfect.
Just be a master of three harmonies.
Bro Rong isn't speaking sarcastically.
Bro Rong is telling you again.
It's because society sets such high expectations for people.
That's often the case.
If you haven't made a name for yourself by 30,
it feels like a crime.
The other day, a young guy told me
Bro Rong, I've been watching your videos for two years.
But I haven't made much money.
I feel really ashamed.
What's going on, buddy?
What's so strange about that?
Besides,
how old are you now?
You're only in your twenties.
He thinks I'm already 25.
a complete failure
Hey buddy
Think about Brother Rong, at 37
He was still a complete failure at 36
But at 37, he suddenly took off
and then he made it
Does that mean my 37 years of life have been meaningless?
Man, back then, you can imagine how frustrated I was
I really want to start over too
I was really struggling with my thoughts back then
It was particularly tough
But I managed to keep a positive attitude
I believe there will be opportunities in the future
There will be a time when I can shine
Right now, I'm just building up my foundation
The opportunities will definitely come
I started at the age of 20
Back then, I was already in my second or third year of university
So we were really anxious back then
21 years old
22 years old
23 years old
24 years old
25 years old
26 years old
27 years old
28 years old
I hadn't succeeded by the time I was 29
I hadn't made much money at all
right?
by the time I hit 30
and 31
I started making some money by writing papers for others
at 32
and 34
Thirty-five years old
Thirty-six years old
Thirty-seven years old
By the time I was thirty-seven, my kids were six
I finally got it
You could say it was a significant economic success
Later on, things gradually progressed to the point where I didn't have to work anymore
That was only a few years ago, right?
Right?
It's just a matter of turning 41
It's just 34 years down the road
So, we're talking about the efforts made so many years ago
Things will turn for the better after hitting rock bottom
So, a lot of the time, people instill these ideas in you
You have to achieve certain things by the time you're 25
Then, during your graduate studies, you have to do this and that
You have to have accomplished certain things by 30
And men have to be good
You need to be making a million a year
And have savings in the tens of millions
And give you a few million for the dowry
And buy you some luxury car
Why should I?
Buddy
Why should I earn money for you to spend?
Who are you anyway?
Are you trying to trade your measly stuff with me?
I've earned this money.
What can't I trade for?
Right?
Why do you have to force me to work?
And many of my followers often chat with me on WeChat about their daily lives.
They sometimes feel really inadequate, or like failures.
Or they feel that way by the time they hit 30.
So what happens when you turn 30?
You haven't even hit 40 yet.
Actually, the typical life path is that things start to stabilize around 40.
It's usually around 45 or 46 when you can afford a house.
By the time you're 50,
your career is likely to have taken off.
At 60,
around 65,
entrepreneurs often start their ventures at 50.
Work until retirement at 70
That's the typical attitude of entrepreneurs
Look at any entrepreneur, they're all bosses
They become bosses because they've aged into the role
How many young bosses are there?
Right?
Not many
Most of the time, you see the rich second generations
Or through some other means
Made it big
That's not normal
Most people strike late
Most people only start making money when they're much older
Only start buying houses when they're much older
Why do so many people urge you to buy a house
Push you into a mortgage
Because he built houses
He built
Aren't you going to buy it?
Right?
He bought the house through you.
He took the money for himself.
So what are we going to do?
Isn't he planning to spend it overseas?
Isn't he planning to send his child abroad?
Isn't he planning to transfer the money overseas?
Right?
So, the taxation for the supporters
the national construction of the supporters, huh
So this logic is quite amusing
Why should I suffer so you can enjoy the benefits
That's how the logic goes
Why should I have to succeed
When I succeed
When my salary reaches a million
I've created so much value for this company and for society.
How many people have fattened themselves by sucking my blood?
When I seem to have succeeded, with a car and a house,
the local government is the happiest.
relying on land developers and banks,
and those car salespeople,
the car manufacturers,
they keep getting richer,
while I just drive the car.
I just wanted these bricks and tiles.
Then I want to live in this place.
Would those developers live in such a place?
They wouldn’t.
They’d live in Beverly Hills.
They’d live in Vancouver.
They’d live in Los Angeles.
People who wouldn’t live here,
nor would their children.
Nor will you receive an education here
So you think you’re living a life of luxury
You think your life is filled with cars and houses
Borrowing again wouldn’t be hard
You always resort to borrowing
To spend money
Is that what happiness looks like?
Why do you have to succeed?
Just for the sake of mating and reproduction?'
There are plenty of people out there
Let others mate
Let others reproduce
Can I just focus on living my own life well
I make myself happy
I just make myself happy, that's it
Happiness isn't hard to come by
I'll have some pickled food
And grill some barbecue
Have a beer
Have a sip
A few slices of cucumber and I'm happy
Right?
I'll take a stroll
If you're going on a motorcycle trip
I'm happy
I'll go to a concert or watch a stand-up show, right?
Check out some games adapted from manga, shall we?
Then watching live gaming streams is quite enjoyable.
Happiness isn't hard to come by.
Why shouldn't indulging in simple pleasures be okay?
Why can't I play games?
Brother Rong does two things every day,
one is watching videos on Bilibili,
and the other is playing games on the TV or computer.
Just these two things.
Of course, I also read books,
and I study too.
But the time I spend reading, studying, and working out combined doesn't exceed an hour.
Most of my time is spent watching videos,
and most of my time is spent playing games.
I'm just enjoying life,
it's that simple.
It's not that I only do this when I have money,
I do this even when I don't have money.
I've never thought that success is something you have to strive for.
I've never been someone who constantly pushes myself,
constantly pushing myself,
to achieve success.
And it wasn't until I was 37 that my luck turned around.
It's not that I wasn't working hard before 37,
I just didn't succeed.
When I was 36,
or 35, I started to not push myself as much.
I think you have to wait for opportunities,
I think that's just how it is.
When the opportunity comes, you seize it and that's it.
Right?
You can't always be like that,
when you don't want to sleep,
lying in bed won't help you fall asleep,
you won't be able to sleep anyway.
Right?
So a lot of times, it's just like that.
Don't let others' expectations sway you.
Remember what Brother Rong says, if you're not successful,
then that's just fine.