So the views weren’t particularly good.
But every time I make a video,
it’s really a test of fate.
You just see who resonates with what I’m saying at the time.
That information will find its way
to the person it's meant for
This is one of the principles that govern the world
When we talk about the breadth of life
your happiness is actually something you control subjectively
It’s just that you might not be aware of it
Until you fully awaken to how the world operates
your understanding is confined to a very narrow scope
which is shaped by the education you receive at home, school, and societal norms
He always tries to mold you into a certain type of person
guiding you towards the path of success
Bro Rong has told you
if you study French, you can break through
for ordinary people
it can help you overcome certain social limitations
we call it exploiting a glitch
but in the real world
there is a common misconception
Because this is different from your experiences in childhood
You might feel incredibly free
You're living a life of your own choosing
But you'll find that in many aspects of life, things are often arranged by fate
Many things are controlled by destiny
You can't control them
But we say the core of fate actually comes down to two things
One is random events
The other is interpersonal relationships
These two things are the most complex.
But they are also the easiest to understand.
When it comes to random events,
we are actually under the control of cause and effect throughout our lives.
Many people ask, Brother Rong, are you starting to talk about metaphysics now?
Actually, I've always been talking about metaphysics.
Sometimes I just put on the guise of the humanities to explain these concepts to you.
So you can understand.
Just like many people don't understand why I insist on talking about Marxist philosophy.
Why is it essential to discuss Adlerian psychology?
Why is it crucial to talk about task differentiation?
Why is it important to address narcissistic personality traits?
Because it helps protect you and break through various obstacles in your real life.
It serves as a shield and a breakthrough mechanism.
Young people in every cultural sphere are born with certain advantages.
And some disadvantages as well.
No matter the circumstances of your birth,
Regardless of the country you were born in.
What kind of social standing do you come from?
If you can challenge a future role with your current background and status,
you are essentially breaking through the limitations of your existence.
In other words, our minds are always free.
It’s just that our actions are not.
We just differ in our physical conditions.
Some people are physically stronger,
some are weaker,
and some have higher intelligence.
Some people have better looks
Everyone is given different basic conditions
But our consciousness
This combination of consciousness
In itself
This consciousness
It is the same
We are all the same in this regard
So when it comes to it
Actually, the differences between us are just in our intonation and speech.
Our skin tones,
our facial features,
and a variety of basic abilities
have different values.
As I mentioned, the concept of 'Three Begets All Things',
this concept represents the various basic values ranging from one to a hundred percent.
In other words, we are just in different states.
So, why am I explaining these fundamental principles?
Because I'm going to talk about some very complex and profound things
you need to understand this basic principle
which is why I encourage you to pursue a kind of spiritual freedom
and this is actually quite normal
you need to understand three things in life
who you are
where you come from
and where you are headed
some people say
We are who we are.
Then we come from our parents.
We head towards death.
That’s how it seems on the surface.
On the surface, we rush through this life.
But during this life,
Sometimes, in a fleeting moment while you’re dreaming,
Or when you’re traveling through majestic mountains and rivers,
You might experience a moment of enlightenment.
Suddenly, you'll feel incredibly joyful
Extremely refreshed
It's like, wow, just a moment of pure bliss
That's the feeling
It will happen a few times in your life
To be more precise
This is something you encounter, how to put it
Let's not try to explain it with mystical concepts
It's simply a profound experience of happiness
You will gradually get closer to understanding what you're meant to do in this life.
Everyone has a main mission in this regard.
It's not about some mundane significance.
In other words, in your lifetime,
you must figure out what you're here to do.
You need to think this through clearly.
Get it straight in your mind.
Why do I tell everyone to make money?
To control the use of money.
To gain power
wealth and prestige, these things
the core reason is to delve into research
to extend your lifespan
or to give you more time for spiritual exploration
which means freeing you from labor
so all of this is just a means
it’s not the end goal
and why you encounter various kinds of spiritual harm
A variety of mental aspects
Teach you how to resist them
It's because only by building a robust mental defense mechanism
Can you face more challenges in the future
That is to say
In our era
Many things appear on the surface
Nothing seems to happen
On the surface, we should all know how to handle it
living a life of mediocrity
and ultimately end it this way
but it's not like that
in fact, every day we brush past all sorts of opportunities
we constantly brush past death and good fortune
and what ultimately determines our lifespan is certainly not set in stone
for instance, this morning there was a sudden tsunami and earthquake in the Kamchatka Peninsula
so in this world, many things are like that
how should we put it
It was like the mask incident back then
Those were unforeseen events at the time
It can quickly alter the state of your life
In other words, we all have a survival instinct
But these are things that span multiple lifetimes
What we call past, present, and future lives
Regardless
You have something
A core pursuit or goal
That is to say, if this goal exists
you have found your mission and completed it
you wouldn't need to
go through the cycles of suffering and hardship in life after life
isn't it better to achieve the purpose?
This is actually the ultimate goal of our lives
But I believe everyone's understanding and insight are different
So not everyone might truly grasp the purpose behind what I'm saying
Perhaps there is no purpose at all
But let's put it in more down-to-earth terms
What Brother Rong is telling you
At the very least, after you've heard it
You should understand where your life should be heading
Or you need to figure out how to make money
How to earn and spend it
Not a penny should be left unspent
In many cases
You need to understand what the meaning of life really is
If you understand this meaning
or if you define this meaning yourself
either way
the uncertainties in your life
you won't live aimlessly
you won't live without a goal every day
like how I live each day now
I have a clear purpose
I live with a clear purpose
So, to explain,
your lifespan can be extended when you find purpose.
It will be prolonged.
Because lifespan can vary in length.
Many people don't understand this concept.
They think lifespan is influenced by health.
Or they believe it's determined by one's birth chart.
However, it's actually variable.
It really depends on how long you can stay in a place.
It depends on whether you can find your main quest.
When you manage to find your main quest,
and the more you do, the more tasks you'll have.
The tasks become increasingly complex.
As the variety and frequency of your services increase,
your lifespan will actually be extended.
When you are in a state of unawareness,
When you are in a state of deep contradiction,
Many people would say
What we call failing to make it nowadays
is a reset
Actually, it's a form of protection
It quickly propels you into a new life journey
To gain a better learning experience
So everything is for the sake of learning
Speaking of which, Elon Musk has said that the probability of our world being real is very low
When considering many worlds
In reality, their purpose isn't what it appears to be on the surface
Got it?
Understand the country
Understand how history works
These things are relatively simple, actually
Because when you look at some things
For example, like the game Go
Guild Two
Guild Three, this game
You'll find that playing this game is entirely in English
Basically, not many people play it in the country.
It's very niche.
You'll notice that one's career, financial accumulation,
and even political success,
are often related to the family,
or more broadly, the extended family.
So, wealth and nobility usually don't come from just one or two generations.
That's why many of you don't fully understand,
sociology or historiography.
Or political science
Why is sociology
Historiography
Political science
International relations and psychology
Economics and such are what I refer to as the six arts
Let's just focus on political science
When it comes to sociology and historiography
You're seeing the development of human society
The rise and fall of nations
you need to understand
the time when humans truly achieved equality is not long
to be precise
our world
our society has always been unfair
it's precisely because of this unfairness
that you can't expect others to be fair to you
different rules are in effect simultaneously
For instance, the survival of the fittest
the law of the jungle is like the robes of today
people are treated like livestock
casually slaughtered by Israel
this is truly a terrifying situation
but its existence serves as a wake-up call to everyone in the world
including the Russia-Ukraine conflict
it often plays out this way
it makes people in the real world realize
Life is so hard-won.
That's often the case.
So, when you look at the growth and response in global population's mindset, it becomes clear.
The sacrifices these people make can be very justified.
Or even great.
Selfless.
It's no easy feat.
But it's all about whether you can step out of your mental box to see these things.
Sometimes, I just unintentionally want to enlighten certain people.
Because it's impossible for everyone to go to work
I guess many people can understand what I'm talking about
Many people say, Brother Rong
How come you're getting more and more abstract?
Actually, I've never been abstract
I've always been speaking along this central axis
It's just that everyone understands their place in life
Or their position in the process of enlightenment
Differently
So some people need to address survival issues
Others have to deal with worldly problems
How to earn money
How to find a wife
How to buy a good car
They need to tackle these issues
Of course, once some people resolve these practical concerns
Their lives are dedicated to the pursuit of truth
To the quest for the meaning of life
My words might be more useful for that type of person.
But let's not get into such complicated matters.
What I really want to address is
why I'm introducing Adlerian psychology to everyone.
Why am I talking about Machiavelli as an example?
Actually, the reason Machiavelli's book came into being is
everyone has different perspectives, after all.
If he was only advising the king on 'The Prince',
there would have been no need for him to publish it.
Just among the Medici family
or circulated among a few high-ranking nobles as his manuscripts
or he could work as a private tutor
and that would be it
right?
or he might be recorded in history, it doesn’t matter
but as a public publication
he would be like all the common people
explaining the workings of politics
What kind of game are these so-called emperors and nobles playing?
In fact, society has always been stratified into three levels.
We talk about the middle class,
the lower class,
and the upper class.
But in reality,
society always has its kings,
its nobles,
and its commoners.
In any world
any country
it's just that now the nobility has turned into the intelligentsia
entrepreneurs
the middle class, they together form an interest group
the middle class is also an interest group
speaking of high productivity
the elite class at the top can have their own set of rules
for those at the bottom
we tend to want to move up
so this is like the Estates-General during the French Revolution
whenever we find ourselves in a certain class
it limits our actions
it limits our thinking
it limits our understanding
many things are like this
but these aren't the true essence of striving in society
because life is actually very finite
What you pursue at 20 is entirely different from what you seek after 30.
What you pursue at 20
it actually controls you
is more influenced by your instincts
but when you hit 30
some people enter family life
some don't enter family life
and still maintain that 20-year-old state
and that's actually quite alright too
If you remain unmarried
and don't settle down
you maintain a youthful state
which is actually quite good
but after 35, up to 40
your physical stamina declines
and your interest and hormone levels decrease
you might find that pursuing material things
is less stimulating for you
Your instinctual stimulation is not as strong
Your desire to procreate is not as intense
At this point, you'll notice that the social aspect of humans diminishes
The actual value you can contribute to society
As an ordinary person in a subordinate state
This condition of yours
Becomes less significant in terms of social value and function
Because you're no longer generating value
Your contribution to other members of society, how should I put it
What you can offer will diminish.
This is actually a rather terrifying reality.
Once you are in a society,
if you are not very useful to others,
the pace of your social relationships,
the rate at which you accumulate wealth,
the simpler your social connections become,
the higher the likelihood that you will be overlooked or cut off.
Generally speaking, we consider China to be a relationship-based society.
But the relational society in China is actually a good thing.
If you really go to Western societies or even to Japanese society,
where Japan is also considered part of the particularly cold capitalist societies,
a purely non-relation-based society, not built on blood ties or personal connections,
what is known as a contractual society,
you'll find everything is quite cold.
When it comes to this society,
if you don't have much of an impact,
if you don't participate in community activities,
Sometimes, you encounter people who are very polite to your face
but in reality, they keep their distance from you
This is the essence of Western society
In China
the distance between people
due to the population size
and cultural habits, is often closer
However, being close has its advantages
and its disadvantages
This emotional detachment has its benefits
but it also has its drawbacks
so it's all about personal experience
However, when people enter this age group
they tend to think a lot
about issues in the humanities
such as social development and reproduction
and the merits and demerits of history
from a political perspective
How can we maximize the utility of society?
How can a nation and its people thrive and prosper?
These are all his goals.
But from your personal perspective,
whether you contribute to society or not,
whether you make a contribution to history,
or whether you struggle to make ends meet,
none of these things matter.
Because you have a mission that is yours alone in this life.
There's also your lifelong mission
I don't understand this
I'm not sure if I can explain it in one sentence
or if it can be clarified through a few videos
The pursuit of pleasure and luxury is something everyone tends to seek
out of the instinct for survival
it's the pursuit
but once these things are attained, they are attained
and if they can't be attained, then don't pursue them
It's no problem.
It doesn't really affect our daily intake of 2200 calories.
Sunlight, air, and water,
things like sleep,
In modern society,
they are things that require consumption.
They provide you with something.
I need to have money.
I have money.
I can have good things
I can have a higher quality of life
But fundamentally
you are a part of society
you need to maintain the functions that keep society running
you need to provide energy to society
Do you understand?
So this is a state you are programmed to be in
So it means that if you understand the humanities
You can understand yourself
Society has expectations of you
You are a young man
You are a young woman
Your role in society is significant
You are rewarded with 3600 yuan
But are you truly happy?
Only you know the answer
So Brother Rong is here to talk about how to achieve personal happiness
That is, you can only achieve this after you've resolved your survival issues.
After addressing some philosophical questions,
some psychological needs,
and spiritual needs,
you will truly be happy.
In other words, there are certain tasks you must accomplish.
For example, who you are,
who you are,
in fact, you don't really know who you are.
You feel like you know who you are
But in fact, you don't really know who you are
It might sound quite mystical
But if you watch this show at night
I wouldn't recommend doing it now
Because you might be scared to do it during the day
This is called the mirror person exercise
It involves staring at your reflection in the mirror
Looking at yourself
At the very beginning, just don't think about anything.
Look at this person.
Until there's a moment when you suddenly feel this person is very unfamiliar.
This is a feeling your brain gives you in an instant.
That this person seems very unfamiliar.
Because we tend to have a filter for how we perceive people we know.
We idealize them.
We fill in the gaps.
You need to recognize yourself.
Not all animals can recognize themselves, a sign of self-awareness.
This is an instinct of humans.
But there's a moment when you feel detached from a situation.
Oh, this person looks either really ugly or really handsome.
But you don't know them well.
It's as if they are a completely different person.
This is a very interesting state.
At this point, you enter into an observer mode.
It's like when you play CS.
You're out.
Suddenly, you find yourself attached to your teammate.
Or you can jump back and forth in the void.
That's the state you're in.
It's something you can achieve.
When you're completely relaxed.
You'll find yourself in observer mode.
At this point, you can ponder some questions.
It's different from when you usually carry your emotions and self-awareness.
So, I'm talking about what truly allows you to perceive the essence of life
and the mysteries of life.
But I think some of these ideas might be a bit advanced for my followers today.
Even though I have 678,000 followers now,
I doubt more than 50 of them would really understand these concepts.
No more than 50 people.
It's a matter of probability.
But that's okay.
I still want to share.
Because of these things
My video materials
My voice and appearance
They will exist on the internet for a long time
They will come into play at special times
For special people
They will have a certain, how to put it,
A very subtle effect
Of course, this is not crucial
So, I want to discuss the ultimate meaning of sociology with you.
As an individual in society,
you are useful to society.
When you are no longer useful to society,
when society disconnects from you,
you may seem like an useless person,
completely useless,
but in reality, when it comes to the universe and the creator,
you are still useful.
You are an integral part of this world or even the universe.
You always have value.
It's just that you might not be useful to a particular society,
or a specific group,
or a certain company.
Just like a company,
where you are staying,
you feel very uncomfortable,
and you often think about quitting.
But at that point, you might feel like you're not valuable.
Don't have that feeling.
It's just that you and the company don't vibe well together.
The longer you stay at this company,
the longer you stay in this society,
you'll find that you dislike the social norms here.
You dislike the company culture.
It doesn’t mean there isn’t a better place for you.
So, Brother Rong sometimes tells you
Some information from abroad
It's possible that other societies might be more suitable for you
The reason why you might not fit in is
Let me put it in a rather mystical way
You have less experience here
So you're not accustomed to the environment here
That's why you've been frail and often ill since birth
Some people would say it like this
From the perspective of traditional Chinese mysticism
You're destined to be a child
But sometimes it's not about using such things to explain it
Being destined to be a child is just that
Because the understanding of ancient people was limited
Unlike Brother Rong, who is well-versed in both ancient and modern knowledge
And has a comprehensive education in both Eastern and Western cultures
His understanding of metaphysics truly surpasses everyone else's
Don't think I make money from this stuff
But in reality
It's his arrangement.
It's very ingenious.
This means that some of your main obstacles are right here.
Once you break through this barrier,
your life will see significant progress.
When you can transcend the ego,
go beyond the self,
and view these issues from this perspective,
some problems will resolve themselves.
it will be resolved effortlessly
often times
it's because you're at this stage of viewing
you're in the emotion
you're in the character
you're in the persona
you're in this MBTI
the influence of these yellow, green, purple, and blue elements on you is too strong
you're too accustomed to playing this role
You're not used to thinking about problems outside of your current state of being.
So, your potential is confined within your physical self.
These issues become unsolvable as a result.
In other words, if you truly want to make money,
you need to align your mental and intellectual levels with those of the top figures.
That's why many of these top figures gradually develop an interest in mysticism.
Whether it's mystic societies,
or unexplained historical events,
they become fascinated by these things.
One is that he has the time to think about it.
Second, he will realize that some of his qualities are not purely coincidental.
The reason people become wealthy,
become famous,
and gain power,
is because they are useful to more people in society.
But this kind of usefulness isn't in the conventional sense.
You understand?
Try to figure out why Brother Rong became popular.
This matter is an inevitable event.
Because his existence has a metaphysical effect on others.
So similarly,
If a state of your life
can serve a large number of people,
your reputation will naturally grow faster.
In other words, if what you offer is useful to others,
nature will naturally lend you a hand.
So how to make yourself more popular
Those with considerable power
and ample financial resources
need to focus on enhancing your spiritual cultivation
I’ve made myself quite clear
can you just not understand
that’s up to you
it’s about how you progress in society
the key is that you are useful to other members of society
how you build good relationships with others
You sleep with everyone
You give money to everyone
You use your power to help everyone
So you have good relationships with everyone
Once you retire
When you're old and less attractive
When you're broke
People naturally drift away from you
But that's how fate works
Once you are of value to others mentally
And useful for their life journey
For some of their
Things that help remove their mental barriers
You will naturally become wealthy
Famous
And influential
This communication is not something that can be explained simply through physical means
In other words, all these things are actually arranged by Steins
The question of which comes first, the cause or the effect
The question of which came first, the chicken or the egg
That's how it is
Which came first, the chicken or the egg
Which comes first, the cause or the effect
Did you go ahead and do it first
Or did it come about because you wanted to do it
Was it that you made the dumplings first to have this vinegar for the meal
Or did you buy the vinegar first for the dumplings
There are so many of these things.
So the things you do,
they lead to different outcomes.
So don't ask about the cause and effect.
You need to combine these elements together.
First, become someone who is useful to society.
Then, resources in society will naturally come your way.
That is to say, if you want to become more capable,
you must enrich your knowledge and expertise.
You need to build up your strength.
To put it simply, it's a straightforward statement.
It's about being someone who contributes to society.
And naturally, the things you need will come to you.
So, in today's context,
what truly benefits you is making more friends,
reading more books,
and exercising more often.
It might sound like a cliché, but it's true.
Actually, to be precise
I've figured out this kind of arrangement in the course of fate
When you are of no use to society
This society will leave you behind
You are useful to other humans
Especially for its significant role in metaphysics
Especially when it comes to the significant role of fate
And these are things you can't see on your own
So, it's about whether you can influence the lives of millions of people
To do something significant
To set long-term goals
This is crucial
All of these are available in the library
Because the library houses books from all over the world
As long as the book is published
The National Library will definitely have it
Including my B station content, it's also in the National Library
So, to speak
as long as you go out and discover
you will find this thing
it's actually a very interesting thing
so, you must never confine yourself to your current knowledge
you can't let people think that life is just like this
I can't afford a Maybach
I can only help others collect Porsche parts
I'm just a lickspittle
I'm just a turtle man
I'm just an unattractive girl
you shouldn't think like that
never think like that
because, in terms of the soul
or at the level of consciousness
everyone is in the same state
it's just that the outer shell is different
the content inside is actually the same
we all have it
how to put it
in Buddhist terms
everyone has Buddha-nature, right?
Buddha is the enlightened state that everyone will eventually reach
which means only through continuous learning
continuous learning can strengthen a nation
it's that simple
only through continuous learning
constantly discerning truth from falsehood
constantly refining and purifying
you need to refine and purify these things
so no matter what
there's a golden house in books
everyone should explore more about business
economics, psychology, humanities, and social sciences
it might seem useless on the surface
but it's actually very useful
and I always advise everyone to read the original works
the purpose of these things
is not to use these means to achieve something like in ancient times
but when you learn these things
after you become this state
your relationships will change
your way of thinking will be different
you will meet different people
after meeting different people
your fate will start to change with these different people
in other words, the more you know
the more you do
the more you will be involved in the complex cause-and-effect relationships of society
your law of causality will change
you will no longer be an ordinary person outside of society
but a person within the flow of society
you will have connections with thousands of people
their births, aging, illnesses, and deaths
their rises and falls, honors and disgraces, will all be connected to you
so at this point, you will be lifted up by thousands of people
your life will no longer be entirely your own
you won't worry about survival anymore
someone will always come to you
so, these things
will gradually produce a very positive effect
of course, you will also find that
as a small self
as an ordinary person
your ability to control your life will decrease
but this is precisely because you are connected with thousands of people
it will naturally transfer some control
so this is the core experience of life
how should one live this life
so, everything Brother Rong is telling you today is to live a happy life
to live with goals
to enrich yourself
on the surface, you may feel like you're not doing anything
but the moment that truly changes your fate
when you look back
will seem like an ordinary day at the time
It was just an ordinary day back then.