But then the video material came in.
Do you remember the incident where He Xuefeng didn't give a good review
At that moment, I thought
Hey, Xiao He, you're getting a bit too cocky
Have you made some money now?
Becoming famous, huh?
Starting to look down on the working class
Being so harsh on the workers
It's just a good review, right?
Isn't it just a small favor? Why are you being like this?
Actually, I encountered a really unpleasant situation this time
As you know, Brother Rong is such a saint, right?
Of course, speaking of that,
This is related to the increasing secretion of estrogen.
But Brother Rong has a saintly heart.
And when I criticize others,
I faced a test of my humanity today.
A couple of days ago, I was drinking Kudi coffee from Pinyin Hao Fan,
and the delivery guy brought me the wrong order.
The delivery guy said he would compensate me.
Compensate me ten bucks
I said it’s fine
Everyone’s having a tough time
In this sweltering heat
No worries
Don’t take it to heart
I’ve got your back, bro
Ordered another drink
But I’m feeling really down
I'll give the seller a bad review
I'll give the delivery guy a good review
It doesn't really matter
The next day
I ordered a steak
I was eating and chewing the steak
At that time, there were still 15 minutes before closing
So I felt really bad about it
But the seller managed to prepare my meal within 2 minutes
I was really a bit hesitant to eat that meal.
I was genuinely afraid he might spit in my food.
But I still ate it, yeah.
It was actually pretty good.
But afterwards, since I thought it was the last order of the night,
I tipped the delivery guy ten bucks.
That’s how the story began.
The delivery guy was really happy.
And I felt quite satisfied with it.
Then I also posted on my WeChat Moments and Bilibili feed.
Why?
Because I want everyone to know that I, Rong Zhen, am a good person.
I'm so awesome.
Look, I have ten yuan.
I am a good person.
I sympathize with the proletariat.
I sympathize with the workers.
I'm awesome.
I may be a capitalist,
but I can connect with the workers on a personal level.
I'm such a good person,
right? And I have a strong moral compass too.
Not to mention, I'm pretty good-looking.
But let me take that last statement back.
It doesn't matter.
Anyway, I think I'm really amazing,
really amazing.
I'm a really great person
I'm a hundred times better than Xiao He
Did you know?
Although the number of followers isn't high
I don't earn as much money as others
I don't have the same level of talent
No one is younger
No one is more talented
But I'm a good person
Did you know?
So today, I ordered another meal.
I think someone as nice as me
should be praised every day.
And today, the heavens gave me a compliment.
Did you know?
What they mean by 'kindness doesn't lead troops'
and 'righteousness doesn't accumulate wealth'
is that petty people fear power but not virtue.
I finally got it today.
I gave the delivery guy a tip of ten bucks right away.
It was for one of those Meituan delivery guys.
Then my order didn't arrive for an hour.
So I messaged the guy to ask.
I said, 'Dude, is it because I tipped you that you’re delivering my order last?'
So, the last order you delivered to me
The guy said it would be there soon, at the time.
The guy has arrived.
I see the food is wrapped up really cleanly.
I'm a bit hesitant to eat it, though.
Really, this is so saintly.
Of course, let's talk about it.
Brother Rong, let's keep things separate.
Since I don't know what's going on,
It might be because he thinks I'm easy to push around.
So you see, it's still quite saintly.
So, it was a bit late in sending it.
There might really be an issue.
The guy said the system assigned him too many orders.
Of course, there’s not much that can be done about it.
The system assigns too many orders.
That’s pretty normal.
Right?
So, I won’t tip in advance next time.
Of course, I blocked this guy.
Of course, I didn't give a bad review
nor did I make a complaint
I just blocked them
so you don't have to deliver to me next time
I won't get into that hassle again, right?
When it comes to hot weather
I always give the delivery person a cold drink
and this time was no different
I gave the delivery person a cold drink as well
And that's when my idealistic views were shattered.
I often criticize others, saying
you don't show compassion to the working class,
you're all so cruel.
You are quite cruel.
But the truth is, human nature is complex.
There are indeed people like Pangdonglai who reward others generously.
And there are those who treat the working class well.
But you have to understand, in real life,
Often, when we talk about it
it's a good opportunity to show kindness
The issue isn't that being nice is always wrong
But in many situations
for example, if you're too polite to the renovation worker
they might not do a good job for you
because they think you, a college student, are easy to talk to
In real life, sometimes
why do many people have a tough guy look
All of them have a face that doesn't invite bullying
It's because they've been bullied too often
You're kind-hearted
Whoever hands you a flyer
You always take it
Then they'll ask to add you on WeChat
You're kind-hearted
Everyone will come to you for money
And you always lend it
In the end, you won't be able to pay back the money.
After you get into trouble yourself,
no one will have any sympathy for you.
You've been kind to everyone,
you've set up a crowdfunding campaign,
you've spent money on others,
and in the end, when you try to sort things out,
you realize you're the one without any money.
You might think that in many situations in this world,
Really, the world punishes those who are too kind.
Once your kindness goes beyond the proper bounds,
people will think you're easy to take advantage of.
They might even think you're wasting their time.
Why wouldn't they?
You have money, after all.
Right?
You do have money,
and you speak so timidly.
Right?
You're so timid when you speak.
It just shows that you're easy to push around.
Oh.
You are one of the intelligentsia.
You're just middle-class.
You're so easy to bully.
You really are easy to push around.
Bro Rong is indeed easy to bully.
Brother Rong never makes things difficult for the common people
no matter who you are
whether it's the food delivery guy
or, let's be honest
or the sex worker
of course, putting these two together isn't appropriate
but I still believe that it's just different jobs
But I should be respected.
but let's be honest
In this world
In the world of The Lower Depths,
there's a lot of backstabbing
a lot of cunning grabs for power and wealth
a lot of schemes that target the honest
the poor
the kind-hearted
If you're at the bottom
you'll see a lot of the less savory aspects of the world
That's right.
That's why sometimes I prefer taking the high-speed train.
I like to sit in the business class.
At the very least, I'll choose first class.
But last time, I tried the unreserved seat.
I tried the unreserved seat.
I was shuffled around to second class.
People looked down on me.
I really felt the warmth and coldness of human nature then.
I think this is the best way to learn about society.
It's a great supplement.
This time, it gave me a valuable lesson.
He He doesn't give good reviews to people.
Actually, he's right.
Because he has the right to choose.
He doesn't want to be pressured.
I understand him now.
At the time, I thought he didn't understand.
all sorts of things
for this time, I
myself, this saintly person
I do agree
the common people are great
I treat others really well
I give tips to people
what are you showing off for
are you showing off how rich you are
Give me a discount on the takeout you're ordering.
Then you'd be a rich person.
Then you'd be a saint.
Then you'd be something special.
But I'll deliberately deliver your meal last.
I won't deliver your meal for over a month.
I'll just circle around here.
Because I know you're easy to bully.
Because I know I can't not deliver other people's meals.
Because others will file complaints against me.
They'll give me bad reviews.
But are you in the right?
You don't even buy on-time delivery insurance.
So I'll take over an hour to deliver to you.
I'll wait until the last minute.
I know you tipped me.
Your tip doesn't change anything.
It's what I deserve.
So in this world, we often say,
Many times, we say,
Some people are overly nice to others,
They provide endless emotional support,
Just like me today.
That's why we say human nature can't withstand the test.
Folks, don't be too naive.
I teach others online every day,
But in the end, I got a lesson from society myself.
You see, I really became a clown.
So this is karma.
Sometimes, not everyone,
Is worth being so nice to.