It is essentially an act of observation
The purpose is to reduce uncertainty
and increase certainty
But the key to breaking through in life isn't about certainty.
How should I put it, our Chinese nation is...
Generally speaking, not particularly inclined to take risks.
Considering our predominant way of life,
Agriculture, fishing, hunting, and various other means,
If we encounter natural disasters or all sorts of wars,
Life becomes extremely difficult.
Families break apart,
Homes are destroyed and lives are lost.
So, when we talk about it fundamentally
from the root of the source code
it really dislikes uncertainty
which is quite different from maritime civilizations
maritime civilizations tend to enjoy adventure and exploration
you might notice
on this planet
the majority at present
is still the territory controlled by maritime civilizations
Let's talk about the United States, Canada, Australia, and New Zealand
along with the South American colonies
and the African colonies
In many cases
they actually controlled most of the territories
If you want to change your life
you should try to increase the uncertainties as much as possible
The secret to life
is that many people summarize the key to getting rich as the secret to life
These things are summarized through observations of past experiences.
To make definitive observations,
One could say that the secret to life is actually just one thing:
Increasing the proportion of uncertainty.
For example, everything I do today,
You can see, everything I do is fine.
Like reading books and sleeping,
Or going for a walk.
On the surface, these things seem to add up.
Well, how to put it
I'm quite familiar with the habit of reading with certainty, right?
Sleep is for restoring energy
Going out for a walk
Yeah, to get some sunshine
But in fact, the route I take changes every time
The books I read
Often alter the dreams I have and my usual thoughts and feelings
It opens the door to my subconscious
So, quite often,
we find that
it's this uncertainty that is the key to changing one's life.
Many of us enjoy fortune-telling,
but I’m not particularly into fortune-telling myself.
However, I know a lot of people who are into astrology,
face reading,
tarot reading,
and palm reading.
Zi Wei Dou Shu
there are all kinds of methods, traditional Western
and Eastern
The reason I'm reluctant to have my fortune told is
because fortune-telling can increase the certainty in your life
but since my life’s certainty is already quite good
I’m willing to reinforce this positive affirmation
but doing so can also lead to
less change in your life
The most important thing in life is to embrace change.
Your fate is already determined.
You’ve already observed it.
It’s predestined.
The more you observe these things, the more certain they become.
Their nature can’t be altered.
In many moments of life, you’ll see this.
That’s how it works.
For instance, the major events in my life.
Let's not talk about other major events
just about what's relevant to all of you
In June 2020
I had already started living apart before the divorce
We went to get the divorce certificate two weeks after separating
Right?
During this time, I started chatting on a mattress program
The show first started with posts on Weibo
The show first started posting on Weibo
Because I had followers on Weibo before
I used to post videos on Weibo
Weibo is a platform for text
Who would spend a lot of time watching videos?
It's like posting on Douyin today
If you post long videos
It's actually a short video platform
It's a text platform
Not many people watch
Back then, if I had posted on Bilibili
the outcome today might have been very different
or if I had started posting on YouTube a few years earlier while studying abroad
it might have felt even more different
But why didn't I do it?
Well, I studied directing
and acting
I'm in the film industry
The thing I'm most certain about is film
TV series
short videos like plays don’t really make money, right?
and they don’t have much practical value either
it’s just someone chatting away
what practical value does it have?
but you never know in this uncertain world
these things actually carry immense power
you never know how far this video might travel
that’s the secret of the internet age
You need to promote your movie.
Or stage a play.
If no one comes to watch, there's no show.
It's like writing a book now.
Only those who buy the book can read it.
But when it comes to browsing videos,
You might suddenly come across one.
Come across one.
You might end up watching all of my over a thousand videos.
Then you'll become my follower.
So this thing has a huge amount of uncertainty.
And I started on November 15, 2022.
That's when I started gaining popularity on Bilibili.
But before that, I had 2,200 followers.
I was quite reluctant back then.
Maybe once every month,
or once every two months, I would upload something to Bilibili.
I used to post my videos on Weibo.
I basically update my Weibo videos every three to four days.
During that period, Weibo membership brought me a small amount of income.
With a relatively small number of followers,
it’s now just around 130,000.
Take a look,
plus these 670,000 followers,
I have a total of 800,000 across all platforms.
So, my Weibo follower count is really quite low.
Speaking of Weibo followers,
To be honest
there are a lot of fake followers
on this Weibo platform, you see tens of millions of followers
but many of them are fake
they're not real
unlike Bilibili followers, who are more valuable
they are genuine fans
back then, all my certainty was on Weibo
so I preferred to post on Weibo
I didn't want to post on Bilibili either
And just like that, two and a half years passed
Two and a half years went by
After I posted on Weibo for a year
It's now June 2025
I'm talking about what happened after I became popular
I didn't become popular for two and a half years
Two and a half years of not being popular, then two and a half years of being popular
So at the beginning, when I wasn't popular
During those two and a half years, I was posting on Weibo.
So, it grew quite slowly.
Gaining followers is kind of like this.
I was wandering in a state of certainty.
Every time I posted a video,
I would gain a few hundred followers.
Each video would spark some heated discussions.
At the very least, there would be a few thousand views.
At most, it could reach a few hundred thousand.
It even has a million views
But the conversion rate is actually quite low
Because the nature of the Weibo platform is like that
It's similar to how many people are reluctant to change careers in our daily lives
We Chinese are very, very wary of this
Changing careers or doing unstable jobs
Parents always advise you to take stable jobs
But only by taking on uncertainties can you change your fate
You're like me coming to Bilibili
I came to Bilibili
I started doing these things
I didn't know these videos would become popular
It wasn't until after I had posted quite a few episodes
Actually, it was the 147th episode that took off
But the things I did before that
Most of what you see on Bilibili
Before I became popular
I didn't post that many videos
But I decided to post on Bilibili
because my Weibo account was suspended
At that time, I had to pivot my operations
I had to do something
Because my passion for creation is still there
It's just that the platform suspended my account
The most crucial move I made at that time was to start posting on Bilibili
And I didn't go to any other platforms
Bilibili only had 2,200 followers back then
It's the same as the number of followers many people have now.
But back then, I kept posting on Bilibili.
And I was putting in extra effort.
That's when I was working on uncertainty.
So you realize that major changes in life
happen when you're dealing with the most uncertain events.
You draw a card.
Before you draw, you don't know what it is.
If you draw with the cards face up,
Your life will surely be determined by the choices you make.
If you only do things that are certain,
everyone does things that are certain,
your life will not change,
because this is a life that can be predicted.
I've been posting on Weibo all my life,
I might still be posting there now,
if I keep posting,
I might have at most 300,000 followers.
There might also be an increase
But where is the upper limit of Weibo's overall revenue?
It won't make much money
And that era has already passed
This is an outdated profession
You might be in an outdated profession
You have certainty
How much more you can earn each day at work
The total amount of salary you receive
How much can it appreciate?
How much will your pension be?
These are all things you can determine and calculate.
But if you go into business,
If you suddenly move abroad,
If you suddenly change jobs at this point,
Move to a new city,
Change your job,
Switch industries or move abroad
These things are all uncertainties.
We tend to dislike uncertainties.
At that time, I didn't know if I would become popular on Bilibili.
But after doing it for a while,
it collapses back into something certain.
So this is the most crucial point.
When we talk about many events we undertake,
we can't control anything beyond the certainties.
Once something is determined,
It's time for a change, isn't it?
Once you've decided,
you'll get used to it.
it won't change anymore.
There won't be any more changes.
You'll get used to it.
But we enjoy these kinds of things in life.
We only go out to play after checking the guides.
Whatever we do
With the lessons from predecessors,
we are motivated to act.
Zhang Haifeng tells you,
this major is great,
so you choose it,
but millions of others choose the same path,
and the competition intensifies.
So, the key lies in this:
you must embrace uncertainty,
embrace the unknown,
embrace uncharted territories,
paths not yet walked,
outcomes that cannot be predicted.
Only then will you achieve favorable results,
transform your life,
and add new certainties to your life’s certainty.
In other words, new certainties emerge
from old uncertainties,
while always relying on old certainties
only increases their proportion.
That's how it is.
If I were still updating on Weibo today,
that would be adding to the old certainties.
My followers would still grow,
but the growth and income would be much less compared to Bilibili.
But doing this on Bilibili
is meaningful.
Of course, one day, Bilibili might not be as good,
not as conducive to growth,
and then exploring a new uncertainty on YouTube could be a new venture.
This is the essence of life’s existence,
to strive against uncertainty,
to bet on uncertainty,
only then can you truly defy fate and change your destiny.