but a series of issues came up at home
This has made it impossible for my trip to come together.
you'll find that in life, often
mistakes come one after another
and your correctness is far less than before
What exactly does our education system teach us?
It instills a tendency to make mistakes.
Oh, how did you manage to score 94?
Why didn’t you score 98?
You scored 28 on the test.
Why didn’t you score a perfect 100?
Oh!
This question was way too easy, wasn’t it?
That’s how Chinese parents are.
He will repeatedly doubt your abilities.
But he won't complain about the environment.
We Chinese are a highly adaptable people.
We can transform any adversity.
This is truly remarkable.
However, similarly,
our simplicity and frugality,
our hard work and perseverance,
have left deep marks on our spiritual world and our psychological scars.
We tend to be very afraid of making mistakes.
Especially people during their school years.
They have a deep aversion to errors.
However, we often realize that.
When you're engaging in mass communication,
the rule is actually the opposite.
Because your audience is usually made up of very ordinary people,
they are the common masses.
And you are a part of the common masses too.
Who doesn't make mistakes?
Sages don't make mistakes.
Are you a sage?
You're not.
But I've interacted with most of these people who want to do self-media.
What they often give me as feedback is:
I tell them,
You need to learn how to act.
The most important thing is actually to lower your own stance.
And it's about freeing your nature
Letting yourself become more human
Like a child, like an infant
That state is something natural and spontaneous
Because of the education you've received
The education system you've gone through
Decades of this kind of torment
You gradually develop a strong tendency to be overly cautious
Many people in their jobs are particularly afraid of taking the blame
I’m really afraid of being blamed for mistakes.
And there are those who just love to blame others.
This leads to the mindset of the good student.
So, the first thing you should encounter is the mindset of the good student.
You see many people watching his videos
I didn’t want to watch it from the start.
Hello everyone.
Today, I'm here to share some experience about something.
Or it’s about myself, right?
Have a bit of experience with certain things
Possess a bit of professional skills
Then he wanted to share these things
But nobody wants to see the professional stuff
Right?
I have the professional knowledge
What should I do?
I don’t directly ask deep sick
Why don’t I just go there myself?
Find some tutorial videos to check out what you've shared.
First, it's not interesting.
Many people want to showcase their exquisite lifestyle.
Girls pick a BGM, you know.
Then, they check in.
Then they take a camera abroad and snap some photos.
Then they have a bit of coffee.
Then they listen to some Lisa Ono or something.
Then they wear a beautiful dress.
Let's turn it around one more time
Then, does it get any traffic with a single tap?
It might attract a bit of traffic from some male fans who are desperate for attention
However, in reality
it can't achieve large-scale dissemination
Otherwise, hello everyone
I'm so-and-so
Then, I hope you'll have a prosperous future, so please give us a follow.
Then don't forget to give me a Triple Combo.
This is what my life is like
You find that all of your life is meaningless, right?
Because you don't make mistakes.
Because you're such a good kid.
Because your life is too perfect.
Your life is just too perfect.
Your career is also too perfect.
All of these aspects of your life are just too perfect.
And you have experience.
You have the experience of life
You have the experience in your career
Your life is so perfect
Is that really the case?
My buddy
Let me tell you
Are you for real?
If your life wasn't falling apart
Your mental state would be close to breaking down
Can you do social media?
I'm asking you.
People who do social media,
how many of us are really in top form mentally?
We don't have a normal sleep schedule,
we stay calm all the time,
we never get anxious,
or depressed,
how is that even possible?
That means you didn’t do it properly.
Right?
Let’s talk about what you should present to the audience first.
For example, you might want to show extremely high energy.
Or very unstable emotions.
That’s one way to do it.
Take John Woo, for instance.
He does it this way.
So every shot of his is incredibly impactful.
Look, look at Marin's way of thinking
All the concepts of Marxist thinking
These outrageous claims
But they challenge your self-respect
They challenge your physical boundaries
Your sense of shame
So when we talk about it
You need to carefully examine all these things
Why the social media gurus have become what they are now
Why did the number of followers exceed one million?
The key is his ability to stir emotions
The crucial point is his content
It’s not about being absolutely perfect
No one is perfect
You see, I should have been sharing my life with you all along.
My life, for the most part, is not perfect.
Most of it is filled with the mundane and messy
Filled with awkward moments
It's filled with awkwardness
It's riddled with failures
It's brimming with discomfort and embarrassment
This is what a real person's life looks like
There are characters within the audience
What do you show to the audience?
You show the five stresses and four beauties
You display the scenic beauty of our country's lakes and mountains
That's called scenery
The documentary
Buddy
What you show is humanity
What is humanity?
Humanity means making mistakes
Humanity means pushing the boundaries
Saying things that go too far
Humanity means doing things that everyone has done wrong
You've never made a mistake
Are you even human?
You're not human.
So many shows are bland and uninteresting.
There's nothing worth watching.
There's no emotional variation.
What you make is too perfect.
His persona is too perfect.
If you cook, it’s like you’re exceptionally good at it.
Oh!
You really know how to enjoy life.
You manage your life so well.
You’re never all over the place.
You handle things with great stability.
What’s the point of that?
That’s why some people create such outlandish content.
It’s so abstract.
But it’s incredibly popular.
Because his work is close to reality
close to the characters in the show
and close to the audience's limits
You know?
This applies to all the people in crosstalk
whether they are the people you satirize in your crosstalk
or the characters you portray
It's a complete reflection of real life
This is what your social media content should be about
This is what your show should be doing.
You see, all the stories I tell
are also derived from life.
Things that come from life
are more interesting.
They are more relatable to others.
So, you should dare to make mistakes.
And you're also brave enough to make mistakes in the live stream.
You're not there to soothe everyone's emotions.
What others see in you
What they see in you
So when it comes to style
You're particularly good at stirring up conflict
How to put it
Exploiting this conflict
Taking advantage of this opposition
Then how do we use it
Calling the audience 3D
Is he really looking down on the audience?
No, he isn't.
He's very skilled at stirring up these emotions.
So, the best thing you can do in the live stream is to focus on your style.
When it comes to all these things,
Everyone's video follows a certain pattern
As you create more content over time,
you might gradually become afraid to leave your comfort zone.
Everyone has this issue.
But that's just who I am
Because I'm afraid of making mistakes
Making mistakes is a necessary part of human growth
Without making mistakes
You can never truly grow
That means life is always full of various random events
All sorts of unfortunate events
More than our plans
Like how I had everything planned out perfectly for today
I had already made it to the waiting room
I had even gone through the ticket check
I was about to board the train
but then a sudden call brought me back
it completely broke all the rules
when I came back
I almost forgot about taking the subway
and ended up choosing to grab a taxi outside the station
grabbing a taxi outside the station
I forgot that taxis aren't allowed within a few kilometers around Beijing South Station.
So I had to walk out.
For several kilometers.
Then I finally got a cab.
And I was going against the rush hour traffic.
Finally got home.
To deal with this.
Spent the whole morning at the hospital.
So handling these things is quite a hassle.
It's really tough
But these experiences can truly enrich my skills
Because in life, you realize that things are unpredictable
Many things are like this
Many things come from mistakes
From the chaos
That's where you find the value of life
That's where you discover what it means to be human
This joy lies in the ups and downs of life
You need to tell others
or they won't find it interesting
What happened, what's going on?
What's up with Brother Rong?
Is Brother Rong sick, or is it his family?
What's the story?
It only becomes a story when you tell it
It only becomes interesting then
Of course, Brother Long is fine
Brother Long is still in good shape
but he's getting older
and so are the family members
when parents have a headache or a cold
it gets really tough
it's uncomfortable
it hurts
these things are quite common
so, talking about it
Why does every time I go out have to be so thrilling?
I'm afraid something might happen to my parents.
I'm worried about my child's health.
That's exactly it.
At least the child has his mother to take care of him.
My parents can only rely on each other for support.
If I could take care of them,
I would have to be around.
So, even though I can say,
I have visas for many places,
I wouldn't dare to plan a two-month trip in Europe,
a three-month road trip in North America,
or a 90-day stay in Japan,
or even a 45-day stay in Xiamen.
I can only say I'll stay here for three or four days,
or five days there.
At most,
a week or two.
Right?
So I always travel like this.
There's no other way.
This is life.
This is real life.
Real life means making mistakes.
Real life also means being tolerant of mistakes.
Only a life that allows for mistakes,
a life where you make mistakes, is a real life.
So the core of what you need to do in your show is to let others see you.
You are an ordinary person.
You are someone who makes mistakes.
You are someone who has flaws in life.
You need to amplify these aspects.
That's what makes the story.
That's what makes it interesting.
That's what draws people in.