Here, he meets him.
They decide to team up and find a way out.
As they delve deeper into the game,
They noticed something was off.
Many players were trapped inside, unable to leave.
They realized there was a conspiracy behind it, orchestrated by the game company.
The company was using this virtual world to harvest invaluable organs.
During their adventure,
dangers kept emerging one after another.
They encountered skeletal hands that suddenly burst out of the ground.
They also came across ghosts that could teleport.
Every close call
only strengthens their bond
Love thrives in the midst of terror
growing stronger
They explore every corner
searching for clues to escape
In an abandoned castle
they discover a document
It meticulously documents the game company's plot and the departure.
The game is great.
But it requires sacrificing one person to request the escape program.
The two fell silent.
Neither was willing to face the grim reality of a human death.
In the end, he took advantage of the other’s distraction to go.
A glow enveloped him.
He called out anxiously.
Quickly return to reality
A good life
It’s impossible for him to smile
He was pushed out of the virtual world by a powerful force
He looked around the empty room
Tears streamed down his face
Recalling every moment in the virtual world
Those were his most precious yet painful memories
And she was forever trapped in that terrifying virtual world
Since then
He has been living well in the real world with his hobbies