We'll discuss this incident today
and share some of our own thoughts.
First, I'll be showing off in this video.
by using a lot of English words,
like 'rise'.
Curve functional guard
police force LAPD
riot and tear gas
rubber bullets
and more
police bullets in the west
and other things
crowd control and rubber bullets
they talk about these kinds of things
First, let's talk about this armor stacking.
In my brief life,
I've encountered RIO many times,
especially during my time abroad.
While studying and traveling overseas,
you're bound to encounter such situations.
Sometimes you might suddenly find yourself,
in the middle of a crisis overnight,
trapped in a residence.
Inside an apartment or hotel room
and you find yourself unarmed
in this episode, I’ll primarily teach you how to escape
when is the best time to seek survival?
I hope you never have to go to such places
and these riots will only escalate
it will gradually turn into looting
like today in LA, there’s already been looting
first of all, I really admire our frontline reporter
We are still delving into this chaotic area.
Reporting is ongoing.
The CCTV reporter has already arrived.
And several American bloggers have also joined in,
like Li Sanjin,
and Commander Zhang,
they’ve talked about everything related to this event.
Regarding the political aspects,
these political matters.
Regarding whether to support immigration or be against it
the rednecks are still backing the governor of Louisiana
I won't take a stance on this
Firstly, I am not a U.S. citizen
Secondly, when it comes to specific political leanings
I won't share my personal views either
You might guess that I favor immigration
whether I am liberal or conservative
but that doesn't really matter
Because I am a Chinese citizen.
So when it comes to the internal affairs of other countries,
we do not interfere.
I won’t express my personal opinions on this matter.
If I were to comment on such issues,
people would start taking sides,
and start arguing with each other from a distance.
I find that utterly pointless.
I am someone who hopes to promote unity.
So, I'd like to share a point with everyone.
This is a rather neutral piece of advice.
It's about how to handle such situations and get away.
In this context,
as they say, in the 36 Stratagems, retreat is the best option.
It's always safest to retreat at the earliest opportunity.
Then you might find yourself, for example, trapped in a hotel room,
or stuck in a standalone house,
or confined in an apartment.
First of all, let me say
The first thing you should do is
Block the entrances and exits
The specific method to block the entrances and exits is
If you don't have many tools on hand
That can be quite troublesome
When you have in your possession
For example, if you're in a separate room with tools
I suggest you partially seal the door, just half of it
Then, the lower part should primarily be able to reach the door handle.
It should allow for entry and exit.
Then, you enter in a kneeling position.
You need to prevent this area from being compromised.
Ideally, you shouldn't have just this one exit.
Once the window is set up,
it should look like a zombie-proof fortification.
Make sure you have escape equipment ready by the window.
You should be able to climb out through the window basically.
If your home is on the second floor,
it's best to have it on both the second and first floors.
While it's more convenient for coming and going,
it also means you might be the first to be disturbed by intruders.
If you have a safe room,
or a basement,
that would be even better.
If you live in an apartment,
There's nothing we can do.
So you might not have any other entrances or exits.
But first, you need to block the main ones.
The primary entrances and exits.
That's what we mean when we say...
You should have things like a corneal machine,
a nail gun,
We refer to these things as living in America.
if you're staying at a regular hotel.
You should use the wardrobe to block the room right away.
Because these looters,
when they see that your place is hard to get into,
they won’t bother to loot. Remember,
at this point,
the first thing you should change is your appearance.
That means if you have long hair,
try to tie it up with a headband.
If you have short hair,
Try to get your hair cut as short as possible
Then you can put on the mask
Just put on the mask
But if you encounter the police, take it off quickly
The most important thing is that you can't look like
Like a mobster
You should look harmless, that's the best
Of course, if you blend into the crowd
If you mix into this group of people
Try to dress the same as them
Don’t stand out too much
Don’t look like a foreigner
This is crucial
Don’t bring anything that could cause misunderstandings
like flags
or slogans and such
Of course
if you have a special job
You need to blend into the crowd.
At this point, there's another perspective.
Because the guiding principle is different.
I suggest that no matter what, you should always...
I recommend you always act in the early hours of the morning.
Between four and seven or eight in the morning.
This is the time for long journeys or crossing dangerous areas.
Because during this time, those who go out to plunder...
are usually the most tired.
This is also the time when killers are on the loose.
Actually, it's not the early part of the night.
Many people are still up and about during the early hours.
But by four or five in the morning, most are exhausted.
And people have mostly settled down.
Whether you're riding a motorcycle or walking,
or rowing a boat,
or driving a car,
you can traverse through various streets and alleys.
In some areas, it is the safest
And at this point
If you didn't manage to escape the city in time
You might not be able to get out
At this time, you should try to survive for as long as possible
The prerequisite for surviving longer is having food
Water, warm clothing, and medicine
So you should stock up on things that are hard to find normally
Like antibiotics
Antibiotics
All sorts of things
And some first-aid medications
As well as medications for chronic conditions
Such as heart disease medications
Allergy treatments
All these items should be included
If you have any chronic conditions
If you have any such special health issues
You need to get your medication in advance.
This is crucial.
It's vital to your survival.
When it comes to food and water,
if currency no longer works,
you'll be in the same boat as everyone else,
having to resort to taking what you need.
Of course,
we're not talking about stealing from others.
I mean, in many places
like, for example, some stores
some general stores and such
sometimes, how should I put it
they might keep their doors locked
of course, if you're in a situation where you can't survive
in cases of emergency and self-preservation
that's a different story
of course, as long as there's no water cut-off
If the power hasn't been cut off,
you should first use a container to collect water.
First, gather some water.
If you have a barrel or something similar to collect rainwater,
you can collect rainwater during the rainy season.
But in the city, this isn't very practical.
I strongly recommend that everyone check out the SAS,
which is the Special Air Service from the UK,
and their urban survival guide.
Of course, he's talking about infiltration.
It's about gathering intelligence while sneaking in.
But for the average person,
the concept of extraction is also important.
This is actually quite useful as well.
What you need to do is
have some means of self-defense,
some weapons,
but they shouldn't be lethal weapons.
It's the kind of thing that's particularly lethal.
If you have something particularly lethal,
it's likely to be noticed by others.
For example, the police force might notice it.
They might consider you a bad guy.
But generally speaking,
we say,
in a normal environment,
you should know that you can't get that many weapons.
To talk about it,
what do you think?
using an umbrella, that’s a kind of long-handled item,
I remember I mentioned this to everyone before,
I did a segment on Europe back then,
that was around episode 200,
I talked about the security situation in Europe,
because at that time, there was a possibility that the security situation in Europe,
wasn’t good.
So back then, I told everyone
that umbrellas are incredibly versatile
they can block things
like tear gas
and other items
and in critical moments, they can be used like a bayonet
to jab at the opponent
so they can also be used for protection from the rain
the material of the umbrella
It’s a bit tricky to describe
It’s quite sturdy
So you should keep a few on hand
If you’re in a home environment
I suggest that you
If you have some duct tape or something
Or anything like that
Try to make long-handled weapons
Don’t make short-handled ones
Because one person's abilities are limited
This is something I often discuss with women's self-defense groups
These people who are into women's self-defense
I often exchange ideas with them
If weapons can be used
In situations where weapons are used
And when using weapons, try to avoid short or long handles
Weapons are meant to be controlled in your hands
Like double-handed sticks
Things like a kitchen knife
These items aren't very effective
Western-style knives
Japanese-style knives, especially those used for slicing raw fish
are a bit more useful
You can attach them to a long handle
This is for life-saving in critical moments
You shouldn't use it to attack someone
You know that, right?'
So, the longer this thing is
keep your distance from the other person
the safer it is for you
it can also be disguised as a walking stick
or even as a regular cane, which is quite handy
let’s move on
like when I lived in France
I specifically lived in the area between two countries
how should I put it
There are rivers like this along the way
I live by the Marne River
So, in a critical moment, if the ground transportation fails
I can paddle a boat or use a ferry to cross
and slowly make my way to Germany
Back then, the idea was pretty simple
Because where there's a river
it can always ensure passage
since rivers don't experience traffic jams or anything like that
Because you wanted to fly away at the first moment
If that option isn’t available
Try to escape the city as soon as possible.
This is crucial
Head for the countryside
If that’s not feasible, go to the mountains
You can hold out for a long time in the mountains
Stay hidden for a long time
That’s when your wilderness survival skills will come in handy
So it's crucial to develop your survival skills over a certain period of time.
That's really important.
Remember this rule.
First, gather the necessary survival supplies.
Second, travel light.
Leave your valuables behind.
Don't carry them with you.
Unless you have items that have trade value.
And that's how you should handle it in this situation.
Then you need to prepare some personal weapons.
You should have at least two types of weapons.
One long one,
and one short one.
The long one is for engaging in confrontations.
But remember, if you can fight, you fight,
if you can run, you run.
That’s the principle to follow.
In principle,
If you're not alone
If you have women and children with you
Try to help them disguise themselves
This is very important
This won't be a primary target for the robber
It's not a crucial objective
The most critical thing is
I think listening to this one sentence in the video is enough
I think you should listen to this one sentence from the video, and that would be enough.
After four in the evening
to around seven or eight in the morning is the best time for movement during the day
it’s best to move between shelters
or run out of the city in one go
this way, it’s relatively safer
anyway
prepare food and water for four to eight days
you should always have an emergency kit on hand
most importantly
For Chinese people,
let me tell you,
it’s important not to flaunt your wealth when you’re abroad.
Many girls take photos,
showing off all sorts of things they have.
Actually, this is something that happens a lot overseas,
why girls are particularly vulnerable to being robbed,
or stolen from,
is because they stand out too much.
You guys really love taking photos and checking in.
You're always showing off how good-looking you are.
So this makes you a prime target for thieves.
And for robbers as well.
Actually, in many cases,
things have already descended into anarchy.
It's at these moments when it's particularly easy
to think everything is fine one second,
only to face all sorts of violent crimes the next.
So, don't get involved in such things first.
Second, when you encounter such situations,
try to stay as far away as possible.
Third, try to escape from this place,
like this chaotic city,
escape to the suburbs first,
get to the suburbs first,
then move to a much farther location.
So, at this point, we're talking about
It's important to train yourself regularly.
At the very least, you should learn how to drive a car.
Driving a car is preferable.
It's also great if you can ride a motorcycle.
Being able to operate a yacht is useful too.
You should also be able to handle a speedboat.
At the very minimum, you should know how to ride a bicycle.
Choosing the right time to travel is crucial.
Traveling before 12 PM is generally safer.
From noon to afternoon
Especially in the early part of the night, it's the most chaotic time
So, during this time, you need to remember
No matter what
Your safety comes first
If you need to, be willing to let go of your money
Before it all starts
Before the power cuts begin
Try to withdraw as much cash as possible
It’s best to carry items worth a few thousand yuan on you.
This kind of Chinese currency can be used for trade.
In that case,
salt, fuel,
food,
water,
medicines, and such
when it comes to a critical moment,
if you really can’t escape
Like the siege of Sarajevo that lasted for four years
At that time, you needed
to have a great deal of wisdom to survive
But to speak of it
I think that as Chinese people today
we don’t need to worry
because our country will organize an evacuation
Secondly, for crucial issues
I suggest you don’t go to dangerous places
So, I hope everyone, no matter what,
People traveling in America now
try to avoid these major cities,
and figure out a way,
like transferring into Canada first,
and then returning home,
no matter what,
I hope you are staying safe in North America now,
and there's no need to be overly worried.
Because in many cities, we often see such incidents.
But the question is whether it will escalate to that extent.
Like the major riots in Los Angeles in the 1980s.
That's really hard to say.
If another disaster were to strike Los Angeles at this time,
it would certainly increase the complexity of disaster relief and various other challenges.
We all know about the floods in Florida.
Back then, Miami and other places also experienced riots.
This is actually why there's a difference in thinking between foreign and domestic perspectives.
It's completely different, though.
Because once people fall into this state,
anyone can become an attacker,
a criminal.
They don’t have the same moral awareness as we do,
nor do they have our organizational skills in society.
So for these people,
don’t trust anyone,
anyone could be a beast in the flood.
In a nutshell, zombie games
Exactly
are a form of mental training for everyday people
a kind of rehearsal
because we can't constantly show scenes of violence
so the idea is that people turn into zombies
so I hope everyone can pick up some survival knowledge
I haven't really said much
but the key is in the details
Actually, it's about the handbook for military and civilian dual-use talents
or the doctor's handbook
or the urban survival guide
or the wilderness survival manual
all sorts of things like that
and there are those preppers
survival enthusiasts and the like
this kind of hobbyists
they can actually provide you with more detailed information
Let me mention a few key points.
I also talked about bulletproofing.
The most important aspect of bulletproofing is protection against
grenade launchers,
rubber bullets,
and tear gas.
If you're the one explaining it,
it's about having simple disaster-resistant escape tools.
A fire mask is something you should definitely have.
And if you can get a fire suit,
its protective capabilities are excellent.
If you have a fire extinguisher at home,
make sure to keep it in good condition.
A fire extinguisher is also a very useful
self-defense tool.
It can prevent you from engaging in intense physical altercations.
Regardless,
I hope everyone stays safe.
Life and survival are not games.
Often, it's a matter of life and death.
It's not something to take lightly.
Speaking for myself,
I've encountered such incidents two or three times while studying abroad.
These kinds of situations,
having the right equipment can reduce fear,
but there's no need to overprepare and feel like the fourth natural disaster is coming,
or that the Three-Body people are about to attack.
You might prepare a lot,
but it might not be useful in the end.
It could be a skill that's never used,
so it's not very practical.
However, to some extent,
everyone should prepare survival skills in advance.
I always recommend that if there are any signs of trouble,
escape as soon as possible.
Get to a safe area as quickly as you can,
Run away as soon as possible
Escape at the first opportunity
I hope everyone lives a life free from disasters,
and never encounters famine,
or war,
or all kinds of trouble.
We should avoid getting involved in such matters.
I wish everyone a lifetime of peace and safety.
These tools are for saving lives in critical moments,
but I hope we can live in a very peaceful and stable environment,