You might be right all along
I spent a week in Shandong
I barely make any videos.
Yeah, let's keep it short.
But this week, there have been a lot of topics to talk about.
If you've been following me lately
You'll notice that I've launched a few new series in my Power-Up videos.
I'm not sure which series will really capture everyone's interest,
so I've started a few new ones to see what sticks.
I'll check how the revenue is doing,
Now, let's talk about the free videos.
I've already outlined the main ideas.
Well, how to put it
Uh, the title for the third episode
As you all know, I usually write the titles
But not the scripts
But the titles for these three episodes are all incredibly explosive
Each one more explosive than the last
This is also my reflection on many things I've read.
So, everyone has been checking out my recent updates.
Well, how to say it
Let's get started.
There will be a lot of exciting content.
Everyone, keep following, please.
This is one of my marketing scripts.
But it really is quite interesting, though.
When I was a kid, my parents worked at this China Bookstore.
There was a KFC near Hepingmen.
Since I had a relatively comfortable family life back then,
I was in first grade at elementary school.
It was back in 1990
when I had my first taste of KFC
KFC had a store in Qianmen at that time
and there seemed to be one in Hepingmen as well
I've forgotten the specifics
but it should have been the store in Qianmen
the one where Professor Yuan Tengfei once worked
KFC's fourth store was in Zhongguancun
Zhongguancun back then
Next to the fourth KFC, there was also a bathhouse.
That was the early Zhongguancun.
These things weren't the main focus.
When I was a kid, I thought KFC was incredibly delicious.
Especially tasty.
Once I had it, I couldn't get enough.
I always wanted to go back.
The second time I ate KFC after growing up,
it was still a craze.
Thursday can be pretty wild too.
While I did feel great eating the original recipe chicken,
it just doesn’t taste as good as it did when I was a kid.
I once thought it was just me,
that my taste had changed,
that I had gradually gotten used to KFC.
So the things that tasted good when I was young don’t anymore.
It wasn’t until many years later,
but even now it’s been over a decade.
I had KFC in Toronto
and it completely changed my perception at that time
First, let me tell you what happened
When I was a kid, eating KFC
I really loved the mini burgers
mashed potatoes
and salads
of course, with one or two pieces of Original Recipe chicken
the Original Recipe chicken
I feel that the chicken broth is particularly rich.
I really enjoy the skin of KFC's Original Recipe Chicken.
It's all about this.
Of course, talking about now,
After so many years of changes,
I've grown from a six-year-old kid into a 41-year-old,
a middle-aged person,
like Old Deng,
35 years have passed.
So much has changed.
It’s been 35 years since World War II ended.
We can have a few more rounds now.
Right?
During these 35 years,
the suppliers of KFC’s ingredients,
as well as their production processes, have undergone some changes.
They have made more adaptations to the Chinese market.
Back in 2011,
After graduating from France, I went on to study in Canada.
When I was studying in Canada,
I stayed in Vancouver on the west coast.
Vancouver is a very developed city.
Speaking of Vancouver,
it's quite polarized.
There are a lot of people working in the service industry at the bottom,
and there are many wealthy individuals at the top.
The middle class is relatively small.
So the culture of KFC isn't as developed.
After all, KFC is still more of a middle-class brand.
And it leans more towards being a working-class food.
As we all know, many African Americans enjoy eating chicken.
So in the West Coast KFCs, for instance,
their market share is much lower than McDonald's.
And as everyone knows, in foreign countries,
the Golden Arches have a significant presence,
far greater than KFC's.
And to talk about it,
we're talking about the situation in Canada here,
Canada has the most Tim Hortons, right?
Tim Hortons,
and in the United States,
the U.S. has a lot of them,
what's it called again,
Wendy's,
Taco Bell
What else?
You know, what’s it called again?
Anyway, I’m not really familiar with it.
It’s just those common types you often see in GTA.
American cuisine is quite diverse, you know.
And there are more tacos, of course.
Speaking of KFC,
Apart from its well-known locations,
there’s the original store in Kentucky.
I haven't been there either.
But there are many other fried chicken places
that are already better than KFC.
After I graduated from university,
I first attended a performing arts school,
and then went to Kwantlen Polytechnic University.
After graduation, I was a regular international student in Canada,
Here’s how it works,
you get a three-year work permit.
A three-year work permit
If you work hard, you can become a PR
You know, get that so-called maple leaf card or green card
Back then, for me
As a humanities student
As an arts student
We're not joking here
The ghostwriting business was thriving
But this kind of underground business can't help you immigrate
After all, it's not something that can offer job positions
or generate tax revenue, you see
it's completely tax-free
that's how it is
so back then, it was just a business
I decided to check out the opportunities
to see if there's any new kind of relationship forming on the East Coast
to put it that way
but once you switch to a work visa
you can't change to a student visa anymore
so back then when I went there
I went to the East Coast just for fun
but in the end
I stayed in Toronto for about a month
and didn't go to Montreal
or Quebec and such
or Ottawa and Halifax to take a trip around
and later I left directly from Toronto
I flew 14 hours to return home.
Because my grandfather was critically ill at that time.
But that wasn't the important part.
What was important was that I was in Toronto.
Back then, I rented a place.
It was near UT,
right across from the University of Toronto's campus.
Across from the campus is a small area,
a really interesting Korean town.
This is a mixed neighborhood with a lot of Black residents.
There are also many Koreans.
And there are a lot of Black people as well.
There are plenty of Korean restaurants.
And haircuts are mostly handled by Black people.
The rooms are incredibly small.
This really left me with a poor impression of Toronto.
Because, to be honest, Vancouver is a bit like Xiamen.
But Toronto is very much like New York.
Toronto has that New York vibe.
The crowdedness is somewhat reminiscent of Hong Kong.
As everyone knows, I dislike Hong Kong.
But I like Xiamen.
Many people might be aware of that.
I also like Shenzhen.
And I like Guangzhou.
But I don't like Hong Kong
However, I think the people in Hong Kong are still great.
Because the Hong Kong people I've interacted with
regardless of their inclinations
have all been very nice to me
have all been very kind to me
But my main reason for disliking Hong Kong is the housing issue.
hotels are too expensive
the cost of living is too high
the living spaces are too cramped
it's not that Hong Kong people lack earning power
That's not right.
And at that time, I was in Wenzhou.
The best friend in Toronto is also from Hong Kong.
When I was in Vancouver, I was also in Vancouver.
That guy is a bit of a fraud.
Let's not go into specifics.
We won't mention TOBY.
And the friend in Toronto.
The Hong Kong friend.
He's particularly hardworking and resilient.
He works.
He takes on multiple jobs.
And his foresight is quite different.
His views on the continent,
the development of Hong Kong, and so on,
align with the mainstream values in the mainland.
That's a friend of mine.
He became my roommate in that place.
Let me talk about my roommate.
To put it simply, I'm just chatting casually now.
There are people living on the first and third floors.
My roommate and I live on the second floor with a few Black girls.
And there are those with brown skin.
The Korean couple lives on the first floor.
The elderly Korean couple really likes me.
They have a preference for Asians.
I find those Black girls particularly annoying.
Because they don't pay rent on time
It's all good, party on
It's all good
That's it
So we tend to be more rule-abiding
But back then
How should I put it
I invested in things I shouldn't have during that period
And then the economic crisis hit
I had to be particularly frugal when it came to meals.
So back then, I had to be frugal with my meals.
You couldn't go out for Chinese food every day.
When I was in Wen Hua, I mostly ate Chinese food.
Over there, you know,
I wasn't used to eating Korean food either.
You know?
Because Korean BBQ and other Korean dishes,
like bibimbap, were of course still okay.
But let me tell you
it feels like when you go out, you run into Koreans
and Japanese people are quite friendly
Koreans and Japanese tend to be quite friendly towards you
because we're all Asians
since we're all Asians
we can communicate in English as well
so it feels much better
and to that point
He sees the same people
The Korean boss sees an Asian person
Seeing a Chinese person makes him more comfortable than seeing a Black person
But Koreans still hang out with Africans and Black people
You know
Because on the West Coast, I hardly ever see
Pure African Americans, you hardly ever see them
Of course, they are different from African Canadians
And Black people are very sparsely distributed in Canada
Because it's cold
Compared to that, the cold in Xihan is less severe
Xihan is mainly populated by Indians
It's mostly Indians
Nowadays, there are a lot of Indians everywhere
Anyway, that's not important
But I went to a KFC there
The prices were really cheap
Just a few dollars per item
The kind of original recipe chicken that costs just a couple of bucks.
Later on, I...
Back then, I ate KFC for over two weeks straight.
Why was that?
Because, you know, I was broke.
But the main reason wasn't just being broke.
The main reason was that KFC...
It tasted like my childhood.
It was the same flavor I had at the KFC in Qianmen.
KFC has been adapted many times in the domestic market.
So the taste is different from the original one 35 years ago.
The KFC of 1990 is no longer the same.
Of course, my memory might be a bit off.
For example, it might have opened in 91 or 89.
Don't worry, don't attack me over this.
It's fine.
I'm not afraid of your attacks.
Just delete it anyway.
You're done.
Back in 1990, when I was in first grade, eating there felt
Totally different.
It feels completely different now.
Back then, KFC and McDonald's used to give out gifts.
It was around third grade when McDonald's started becoming popular.
Before that, we only ate at KFC.
They used to give out gifts too.
All sorts of gifts.
Back then, there wasn’t QiQi
and it had to be the earliest version of Colonel Sanders
all sorts of things
and then there was Baskin-Robbins ice cream
so it was considered a high-end treat back then
to be honest, having a meal at KFC was like dining at the Moscow Restaurant
it felt different
but it was still quite expensive
so people often chose to have their birthday parties at KFC
So the KFC I had in Toronto
was really just the original KFC
and it genuinely made me feel
It really shook my worldview at that moment.
because in my intuition
a lot of things I felt were actually right
they were indeed correct
really strange
I actually visited these two cities in Canada
It's all because of the woman.
Haha, well, how should I put it?
Back then, I thought about it.
At that time, I had a girlfriend in Vancouver.
And we dated for two years.
Then we broke up.
After that, when I found a new girlfriend,
she was originally of Chinese descent,
a Chinese person with Canadian citizenship.
Later on, the girlfriends I dated came from various ethnic backgrounds.
For instance, the girl I dated in Toronto,
Leina is Polish.
Polish.
Later, I also interacted online,
with someone from Montreal,
and even with people from the U.S.
I basically used this approach,
to travel to new cities.
As everyone knows, you're bound to meet one or two people
and then travel together
so you can explore during the day
and at night as well, right?
It's just more enjoyable
making life less boring
and interacting with people from different ethnicities
and different countries, discussing the great harmony of life
is also one of life's joys
Actually, I was already 30 years old at that time.
So it really doesn’t matter.
But what’s most important is that I felt a lot of the time,
your intuition is right.
In reality, our education system,
is often about learning from mistakes.
It frequently tells you that you’re wrong,
and you need to correct yourself to find the right answer.
Seeing internet tycoons
What ideas do they have that we can learn from?
What knowledge or social experiences do they have in Japan for addressing societal issues?
We should learn from them.
What economic principles do they follow in the United States?
We are always criticizing ourselves.
Thinking we are wrong.
But nowadays, young people are much more confident.
They believe they are right.
That's it.
Because individualism has been evolving.
In the past, the mindset of collectivism was too dominant.
Individualism is not sufficient
So now I feel that collectivism and individualism
They should coordinate the so-called Eastern and Western perspectives.
Each should take up about half.
But I feel there's a profound example.
It's about us, the generation of the 80s.
This time, we're not including the post-90s generation
nor the post-70s generation
it's the mindset of us, the post-80s generation
because we grew up between the 1990s and elementary school
to be honest, we need to ensure that reforms continue to progress steadily
continuing to develop the economy is no easy task
how can I put it
so during that time, the control over our thoughts
or the various forms of education we received
it's not as common
so the Gen Xers have a lot of mental stamps
a lot of mental stamps
which makes us hesitant to step out of line
but look at the artists from our generation
writers and filmmakers were more daring
more adventurous
most people are still quite obedient
quite numb
So you see, the mortality rate for those born in the 80s is higher.
Mainly due to overwork.
Serious illnesses as well.
All kinds of people.
It's our generation.
To be honest, we're the bridge between the old and the new.
We tend to be more utilitarian.
More conflicted.
That's why I think we often feel this way.
People our age
the least we do is think about ourselves
So you see, I have a malicious comment now.
saying that I, Rong Zhen, am in my forties
and talking about things that even a twenty-year-old dog could understand
to a bunch of immature
mentally flawed people
First, what he thinks dogs can understand
might really be within the reach of his social circle
But when it comes to many things
speaking for myself
I feel like I only realized these in my thirties and forties
or maybe I realized them in my twenties
but I only articulated these truths in my thirties and forties
My followers are countering him
saying
Brother Rong can break down these things
the kind of family teachings that wealthy people have
I'll share these insights separately with everyone.
These are things people often only realize in their thirties or forties.
It's beneficial to share these with people in their twenties.
Actually, this is a good thing.
I think this is a fairly objective view.
This perspective is quite objective.
And I've said a lot about this.
Various aspects in the course of development,
For instance, financial pitfalls and various traps.
So why am I writing a book called 'Avoiding Pitfalls'?
It’s to share these insights with everyone.
Actually, a lot of the time,
it’s like the taste of KFC’s chicken,
you haven’t been wrong,
your memory hasn’t betrayed you,
you’ve been right from the start,
but why does society insist on telling you that you’re wrong?
The compliance test is more than just a test of compliance.
It aims to strip away your individuality.
To turn you into a tool for a specific purpose.
Only then can certain collective objectives be achieved.
There's a need for directional adjustments.
But from your personal perspective,
From an individual standpoint,
We have both common and unique aspects.
You are a member of society.
The responsibilities and obligations you need to undertake
That's definitely true
Because you can't just focus on obligations
Without considering responsibilities
Focusing solely on responsibilities
While neglecting obligations is also wrong
The rights you enjoy are equal to the responsibilities you bear
This is the state of a normal citizen
But we shouldn't let this make you neglect your health and rest
You're putting the cart before the horse here.
If you don't develop your personal skills, they won't grow.
You need to develop your personal skills.
Only then can your essence move forward.
Only then can you progress.
And it's not about being a tool forever,
living a mechanical life.
It's about truly living for yourself.
So you must understand this.
Personal striving is the realization of personal value.
The development of individuality.
In terms of society, its impact is minor.
But for the individual,
its significance is immense.
What we should truly pursue is the relationship between the individual and society.
individual personality,
a balance between individualism and collectivism
Because in the true development stage of the economy,
When you finally step into society,
you'll find that not many people will really care about you.
We follow the previous generation
the people from the 1950s and 1960s, and the 1970s.
Back then, a lot of things were managed,
the state would take care of you.
For instance,
if you entered large factories or major enterprises, the state would look after you,
from birth to death.
Your retirement
your parenting and all that are your responsibility
but our generation, the market economy generation
they leave a lot of things unattended
we have entered a society obsessed with material desires
you need to earn money
earning money brings you peace of mind
Why is it that our generation
is so fixated on controlling money
That's how it is.
They're all tightwads.
Sometimes, you know,
I think Generation Z and Millennials spend money more freely than we do.
Generation X really doesn't spend much on themselves these days.
But they're willing to spend on their families.
So, a lot of the time,
Our generation isn't heavily controlled by Consumer One.
but Generation Z and Millennials are more so.
Especially the post-90s generation
Because the post-90s generation has a much better family background than we do
Over there
There are also those Chinese and Japanese teenagers participating in a rally race in Inner Mongolia
The influence of Yilin is particularly significant
So our generation, to be honest, is kind of like
Shielding the bullets of the past era
You know?
Like Wu Li Qi, for example
Over these three years
they've enjoyed the benefits of this era
but we haven't
For the generation of 99010
they've experienced the country's strength
and the benefits of being a developed nation
which we can't really feel
We are the middle-aged generation in between
so we lack the enthusiasm and drive of the younger generation
So, the generation born in the 80s has had a tough time.
That's what I'm trying to say.
This is my recent train of thought.
The first step of the reflective trilogy
No rush.
This is just the first step.
If you want to see the best part,
It's coming up.
So today we're talking about this intuitive feeling.
If you think you're not at fault
you might not have found the evidence at the time
Look at me after all these years
I started eating KFC when I was six
and by my teens, I noticed the taste had changed
by my twenties
I really felt that KFC wasn't as good as it was when I was a kid
maybe it's because I grew up
and by the time I hit 30, I finally tasted the original KFC again
The authentic KFC flavor in the Black neighborhood
The authentic KFC flavor in the northeastern corner of North America
Turns out it really is the same taste
And while other places might have changed
But in this part of North America, with a large Black population
The taste has remained unchanged
So the flavor has been consistently improved
It’s possible they’ve been making improvements there too
But it triggers the taste buds just like in my memories
His memory was triggered
resulting in a perfect blend
So often
the biggest intellectual challenge for our generation
is self-doubt
conforming to the choices of the group
aligning with societal choices
aligning with our parents' choices
leaving little room for personal consideration
A lot of things just go with the flow.
It’s better to admit that you’re wrong,
than to refuse to acknowledge
that you might actually be right
and different from society.
That’s the scariest part.
This is why when the post-90s generation emerged,
we felt that for us,
the post-80s generation brought a significant ideological impact.
Just because these post-90s, the Zang'ai Family members
They dare to think and act
Their parents are from the 60s
And the 70s
They have more money
More knowledge
More confidence
And fewer historical burdens
The post-90s dare to perm their hair
The post-90s dare to play Dance Dance Revolution
Dare to engage in all sorts of
So why do post-80s and post-90s tend to marry each other more often?
Indeed, this is complementary
Many times, I really feel that the post-90s
The post-00s are 20 years younger than me
The post-90s are only 10 years younger than me
So, the interaction between post-80s and post-90s is the most frequent
I really admire the individuality of the post-90s from the bottom of my heart
So I think that Chinese generations change every ten years
We must stay within this cultural context
Only within the country can you truly reflect the differences between generations
The differences between different people
The differences in social and ideological trends are interesting
So I think, uh
We always need to continuously analyze these things
And see how different generations
Feel about the same things completely differently
So we say that what post-80s really need to do is
Not to deny your memories
Not to deny your intuition
Not to deny your personal subjective feelings
And not to conform to the so-called correct answers imposed by collectivism
and don't succumb to the pressures of collectivism that are imposed on you
So many times it's like this
Especially in essays, there are no correct answers
Everything should be expressed
Express your own thoughts
Develop your own thoughts
If you don't even dare to develop your own thoughts
How can you become a knowledge blogger?
How can you become a teacher?
How can you become a researcher?
Right?
If you can't even doubt everything
How can you possess a scientific spirit?
The spirit of science is to doubt everything
This is very important
So you need to have the courage to say
You dare to doubt the world
I am right
There's something wrong with the world
The Mandela Effect issues, I am right
In many cases
I need to find evidence that I am right
So the spirit of getting to the root of things
The post-90s have it, the post-00s have it, and the post-10s have it even more
So I think, when it comes to Chinese generations, each one is better than the last
Each generation has its own Shangganling
Each generation also has its own Waterloo
Every generation has its own Waterloo
As long as each generation is stronger than the last
As long as human society continues to progress
This is also what I admire about young people
Human society just needs to move forward.
Believe in your intuition
Don't always think you're wrong
The world might be wrong