it’s not really like that
but I’m actually quite heavy now
I’m 88 kg now
That's 176 pounds.
You see, when I was in my twenties and thirties, I only weighed between 108 to 120 pounds.
So, this is currently my peak weight period.
Some people say it's related to the drinks I consume.
But I really am not hungry.
Look, I've been hungry all day today.
It's not a big deal.
In this episode, let's dive into our content.
In the previous episode, we discussed why we should go to Northeast China.
Why Northeast China is a great choice
What I'm planning to talk about in my next four episodes
Why you should visit Northeast China
Why you should go to Chengdu
Why you should visit Hangzhou
Why you should go to Foshan
Why you should visit Xinjiang
I'll be doing five consecutive episodes
All about the beautiful landscapes of our country
Often, the reason people feel depressed
is due to a lack of choices.
For instance, I decided to pursue a direct Ph.D.
However, my mentor wasn't very nice to me.
He bullies me.
I got married.
My husband
My wife abuses me
As a result, I'm not doing well.
I'm in Shanghai.
I can't make it back to my hometown.
I'm in Beijing.
I can't make it back to my hometown or I am in my hometown.
There aren't many opportunities back home.
So, how should I put it?
Life shouldn't be a narrow bridge.
Life should be an open field.
There are many times
We think we know our country
but in reality, one can't be in Beijing
in 2025
and in Hangzhou at the same time
Look, I've made five trips back and forth
You can't remember everything about Beijing
and Hangzhou simultaneously
So you can't enjoy the benefits of both cities at the same time
But the benefits of each city are entirely different
There was a trending topic this year or last year
about the second-tier university admission score line for Heilongjiang being 212 points
many people commented
how could the scores in Northeast China be so low
because the number of students in the three Northeast provinces is roughly 100,000
with about 100,000 candidates each year
which is a million fewer than in major college entrance exam provinces like Henan over the past two years
you have to understand that
competing with 11 people is different from competing with just yourself
That's a completely different feeling
So, when we talk about it
When the population decreases
It naturally follows a trend
Schools become less challenging to get into
Jobs become easier to find
So I often say that China is now on the path to becoming a moderately developed country
I believe we are already a developed country
But some people believe we are still on the journey.
Some people think there's no need to emphasize our status as a developing country.
This is because GDP is categorized using PPP.
It's another matter altogether.
So, no matter how you look at it,
I believe, regardless of anything else,
we are now a middle-income developed country.
That's my take on it.
But even developed countries have their own set of issues.
But what choices do we have?
Many people
I don’t recommend that you start thinking about settling down in your twenties
about where to settle down
the issue of settling down
should be addressed in your thirties or forties
but the biggest issue with settling down is where your in-laws and family are located
many Chinese elders are deeply attached to their hometowns
they hope you buy a house in Beijing
and also hope you buy a house in the county town
It would be best to buy another house back in your hometown.
It would be best for him to buy another house back in his hometown.
This whole thing is just so frustrating.
What good would a house in the county town do?
Let me tell you,
buying a house in Beijing,
you might end up being a mortgage slave.
So, what kind of choice should be made?
First, look at China’s top 20 cities for earning potential.
Are there any cities where the housing prices are relatively cheaper?
And the competition is not as intense?
Yes, there are.
Changsha, for example.
Suzhou as well.
Right?
I mentioned Chengdu because Brother Rong is currently there, you see.
Does Straight Man Wei Shuang like effeminate men?
Not really.
Why
Because Chengdu has attracted a large number of beauties from Tibet
Xinjiang
and throughout Sichuan Province
So the number of small and medium-sized enterprises in Chengdu, Sichuan Province, ranks very high nationwide
Probably first, I think
I can't remember for sure though
But we need to back up our claims with solid data
After all, this is a talk show program.
We might not be as rigorous
But in this episode, we're talking about 212 points in Northeast China
What does 212 points mean?
Is Qiqihar University going to welcome you with drums and gongs?
And fireworks?
As Comrade Zhang Xuefeng said
Zhang Haifeng is particularly something
So when it comes to it
You're just like my kid, it's awesome!
His mother is from Heilongjiang.
His father is from Beijing.
Which one will he choose?
Or perhaps the educational resources are particularly good.
The scores aren't that high.
Or maybe the natural resources aren't that great.
But these two provinces really don't have high scores.
Of course, Beijing is a municipality outside of the provinces.
So let's be precise.
Departing from Beijing Chaoyang Station today
it takes about eight hours to reach Jiamusi
five hours
four hours
54 minutes or four hours
51 minutes to get to Harbin
It's incredibly fast
I noticed it has been sped up
How many stations are there in Beijing?
Chaoyang Station
Fengtai Station
Nan Station and Xi Station
Bei Station
I'm near Bei Station
Bei Station goes to Zhangjiakou
and to Inner Mongolia
Chaoyang Station is specifically for Northeast China
Nanjing Station
Xizhan, or the Western Station, handles the majority of westbound trains.
But the busiest one is Beijing South Station.
Of course, for nearby areas,
local trains,
like those heading to Hebei,
Henan, and Shandong provinces,
Fengtai Station also sees a lot of traffic, especially for those in the railway system.
If you’re willing to correct me, please go ahead.
Correct me if I'm wrong
Because I'm not quite familiar with it
This thing
But Brother Rong is someone who enjoys the thrill of spending
He always opts for the business class whenever he travels
Why is that?
Because after a high-speed train ride
There are costs involved
We can't keep letting him operate at a loss
We need to make it profitable.
So when conditions allow, go for the first-class seat.
And if you can, opt for the business class.
Especially for short trips.
Let’s go for the business class.
People might say it’s a waste or something.
But the experience is different.
The most important thing in life is the experience.
We save money in other areas.
We don't have to be frugal all the time and in every place.
Right?
So, we should spend where it counts, spend a bit more.
It's good for economic growth, after all.
Right, spending a bit more helps young people earn money.
Isn't it?
You,
don't be a bunch of old tightwads,
spending not a single penny.
Which line?
Right or wrong?
So Brother Rong has arrived at Zhongdeng.
Is Zhongdeng what we're talking about?
Ah, Zhang Bin is the one from Zhongdeng, Zang Bin.
About Zhongdeng,
Brother Rong is also from Zhongdeng.
But Brother Rong is a couple of years younger than him.
I'm not even as tall as that guy's foot yet.
So, the reason we chose Northeast China is
because Northeast China is often referred to as the eldest son of the People's Republic of China.
It’s a testing ground for social models.
As the saying goes, oranges grown south of the Huai River are oranges,
but those grown north of the Huai River are citrons.
Most people in today's Northeast China,
were originally from Shandong Province,
or Hebei Province,
but why do they become Northeasterners once they get to the Northeast?
That's because the natural environment is different.
And Northeast China is a truly magical land.
Most of its cities are industrial cities.
When we talk about people from Western Liaoning, of course.
Farmers in Eastern Liaoning are different from those in Heilongjiang and Jilin.
We haven't conducted a detailed survey.
We're just talking about what we've observed.
Large-scale farms,
agricultural mechanization, right?
Large agricultural machinery
and gender equality in the industrial age
As we often say, Northeastern only daughters
When comparing with the four provinces of Shanhe
it’s a completely different concept
So, to put it this way
We have very conservative regions in China
We won’t specify which ones
Of course, everyone feels differently about what is conservative
Some say Shandong is conservative
Some say Northwest China is conservative
But that's not the case
When it comes to the most pioneering places in China
Speaking of the most forward-thinking areas
In terms of social structure
Let's not talk about economic development
When it comes to social structure
Considering the population ratio and people's mindset
Northeast China is absolutely top-notch
When it comes to Northeasterners
They can be found all over the world
Because they have a pioneering and enterprising spirit
This is truly remarkable
And all of this wisdom is encapsulated in four-character phrases
So what can they do?
When things hit rock bottom
What else can I do, right?
What can I do about it?
So, in many cases,
Let's talk about the philosophy of survival.
We need to learn from the people in Northeast China.
First, no difficulty can crush me.
Second,
There's always a way out of any situation.
What else can we do?
Right?
So this is the harsh environment
that has forged resilient people
That makes all the difference
So, when we talk about it
When we say, of course, we're talking about moving to Northeast China
I explained why I chose to talk about Northeast China first
First of all
The most significant feature of Northeast China is the relatively low prices of agricultural and food products
In Shenyang
Except for Dalian, though.
Dalian is Dalian, China.
You're in Shenyang.
In western Liaoning.
Eastern Liaoning, yeah.
Among all the cities in Liaoning Province.
I've been to more places across the country than anyone else.
Basically, all the medium and small cities in Liaoning Province.
From these big cities to Jilin.
When talking about Heilongjiang,
You say you're not eating well,
Saying you might starve to death,
But in modern society, that's highly unlikely.
So, when we talk about eating, clothing, housing, and transportation,
Let's talk about housing and transportation.
When it comes to these things,
There's absolutely no problem in Northeast China.
First, let's talk about housing.
It's not just a Hegang issue
You see, many places like Fuxi
When you look at many places
Of course, I don’t recommend holding onto it
From the perspective of property ownership
You should still hold onto it
Real estate in first-tier cities
But from the perspective of renting
Is renting a house very expensive?
For younger people, you can stay on the fifth or sixth floor.
For someone like me, in the middle age,
I stay on the third or fourth floor.
When you get older, you can live on the first or second floor.
So, in many places, the real estate is like this,
first of all, it’s not expensive in terms of this aspect,
the food is also affordable,
and the housing is also inexpensive.
Sounds good.
Do we need a lottery system like in Beijing?
Are you riding correctly?
You're riding a motorcycle, right?
Of course, speaking of Northeast China,
I don't recommend you get an electric car.
When it comes to riding a motorcycle,
At least it won't freeze up.
Speaking of electric cars,
The performance degradation is quite significant.
But there's no issue with gasoline cars either.
So a lot of the time, for clothing, food, and accommodation, you buy local clothes and eat local food.
You just eat locally.
And for transportation, you figure something out.
So a lot of the time, we need to consider that the cost of living isn't that high.
You don't have to work so hard.
Many people will tell you,
Especially some of the old hands.
Let me tell you,
you've got to live in a city with high housing prices,
those cities are where the cultural atmosphere is,
but do I really need all those cultural activities?
I just want to live my life,
And my life now is quite simple.
just playing some War and Delta Force,
trying out some murder mystery games,
and maybe checking out some comic conventions, that's it.
My life is over.
I mostly spend my time making videos.
Watch others' videos
playing on the PS5
playing on the Xbox
playing on the Switch
and playing on the Steam Deck, that’s it.
My life doesn’t have much significance
and the most I do is take care of the kids
Spend some time with the kids on weekends
Maybe go for a stroll somewhere
Then hop on my little electric scooter and go out to play
I’m actually already living a retired life, in a sense
So what should retired life be like
First, convenient healthcare
But when it comes to healthcare
In Northeast China, healthcare shouldn’t be a problem
In my opinion
all you need to do is register for an appointment
So, to put it simply
accommodation, travel, and medical care can all be taken care of
And most importantly
If I am, let's say
I am 40 years old now
I mentioned 20 years old
30 years old
At 40, the differences are significant.
At 20, you should be striving in a big city.
By 30, you face the prospect of marriage and starting a family.
Then, you might move to a smaller place.
If you earn a good income,
stay in the big city.
If your earnings are modest,
consider returning to your hometown,
or even a third location.
At 40, it’s all about taking it easy.
So, speaking for myself,
a 40-year-old in the media industry is already in a laid-back state.
If there weren’t kids to send to school,
there wouldn’t be the issue of picking them up.
Actually, going to Northeast China would be the best choice.
I had thought about my ex-wife taking care of the kids,
if we were to return to Heihe,
for them to go to school there.
Then I'll live in Heihe
There's absolutely no problem
Because for me
Like web novels
Like those writers
Like some social media creators
Musicians and the like
To be honest
We actually have very few social activities on a daily basis
You might notice that my social activities are almost non-existent these days.
I occasionally go out for a meal with someone.
And drinking is pretty rare too.
Although I'm quite outgoing, you see,
I'm not particularly keen on making friends.
So, in many cases,
I try to cut down on social activities as much as possible.
That's why being in Northeast China suits me just fine,
since food and accommodation are affordable.
If I'm being honest
Look at me in Beijing
I've just got a car license plate through the lottery
It's really giving me a headache
I plan to buy a car in half a year
Why
Because I got the license plate through the lottery
I feel like I have to buy a car
I don't have a place to park it
I don’t commute.
I don’t drop off kids.
So what’s the point of having a car?
Parking is tough in Beijing.
Driving is tough too.
So it doesn’t make much sense.
But it’s different in Northeast China.
I can live in a very suburban area.
With a car, I can go anywhere.
You can go buy groceries
You can go
Why is it that in Northeast China, four-wheeled vehicles are considered better than two-wheeled ones?
Because it's cold
Really cold
Right?
Your 400km range suddenly drops to 230, right?
When you ride a motorcycle
You look more beautiful in Beijing
There, it gets down to minus twenty or thirty degrees
You said you couldn't stand it
So, to talk about it
And when people go to cold places
Those bugs and cockroaches
They just don't exist there
The chances of bacteria surviving are low
So, in that sense
You're full of energy and vigor
Everyone eats so well
Especially in places like Tongliao, the food is fantastic
I often wonder why, under these conditions, especially in the east
In the eastern part of Inner Mongolia
Why the conditions in Erenhot are so good
Because it has a culture that combines fishing and hunting, farming, and nomadic herding
A fishing and hunting culture
Many people might only know about the Manchu in this central-northern region
And the Mongolian ethnic group
But not much is known about the Daur people.
Not much is known about the Oroqen and Evenki either.
There are all sorts of ethnic groups, each unique in their own way.
Many of these ethnic groups are not nomadic.
Nor are they agriculturalists.
They are hunter-gatherers.
Hunter-gatherers, nomads, and farmers have all played significant roles in human history.
So, in such places,
why do the young men and women look so good?
Why is your body so robust?
Because you eat everything from flying birds to land animals and fish.
You eat all kinds of things.
You eat fish,
meat, and farm produce.
You have beef, lamb, and fish.
Plus, you farm.
So, it's basically impossible for you to lose weight.
That's why as people get older,
The absorption and metabolism have slowed down.
The absorption isn't as good either.
So, you need to eat some refined foods.
You need to eat some richer foods and let yourself cool down a bit.
So, the same principle applies.
Hokkaido, Japan,
is a great place to visit.
visiting Canada is also a good choice.
because I like the cold climate.
I like places like Russia, where it's cold.
Cold climates contribute to a longer lifespan.
Bacteria don't thrive easily in the cold.
To be honest,
I actually live in Guangdong.
I quite like Guangdong.
But it's so hot there,
and I really can't stand the bugs.
It's wild and humid.
This thing is unbearable for northerners
That's when the characteristics of northerners come out
That's why I have tough skin
Why I have thick fat
Like a Polar Bear
It's due to the cold weather
Living in Canada for a long time
Has developed this cold-adapted physique
Now I'm in Northeast China
I feel full of energy.
I feel like my body temperature and blood pressure are all back to normal.
I always feel uncomfortable once I'm back in Beijing.
Especially during the summer in Beijing.
Oh, it's so uncomfortable.
Especially last year when I went to Shanghai in the summer.
I saw the asphalt on the roads almost melting.
So, as the saying goes, an orange grown south of the Huai River is an orange,
but an orange grown north of the Huai River is a different fruit.
This mole, well, I'm a northerner.
I'm a typical northerner.
So, when it comes to northerners,
they offer you more options,
all of which are cold climate options.
For example, going to Northeast China,
going to Hokkaido,
going to Canada,
while southerners provide different options.
Let's talk about the Greater Bay Area.
And then there's Australia and New Zealand.
So, they are quite different.
It's a place full of sunshine.
So, the living conditions for people in the south and north are really very, very different.
The experiences vary as well.
So listening to Brother Rong can give you an introduction to some of these concepts.
But not all concepts, of course.
For example, going to Xinjiang.
The temperature difference between Southern Xinjiang and Northern Xinjiang can be around 25 degrees.
While it's 30 degrees in the ancient city of Southern Xinjiang, it's only five degrees in other places.
So, for those who go on self-driving tours,
especially those who travel by motorcycle,
if you're heading to Xinjiang,
not preparing two sets of clothes,
that's just asking for trouble.
Four wheels are definitely more convenient than two wheels.
At least they can carry more stuff.
You attach the two wheels
Then you install the trunk
You add the side bags
You can do it
Then add a front box
A center box
How much stuff can you load
Right
And the more you load
You might end up swaying dangerously
Isn't that so
So, motorcycling really tests a person's character
But let's keep going
As the backbone of a family
Northeast China sees a lot of people leaving every year
Why
Because it's hard to find jobs locally
Jobs are really hard to come by
So, to put it this way
But people like us don't have strict location requirements for work
We should actually go
Places like this should be where a northerner should go
Actually, there should be a spirit of rushing to Northeast.
I'm not saying everyone is suited for it
If you have a job locally
If you have a job there
In the northeast, you might not find a job with a high salary
But if you're a web novelist
Or if you work in new media
Or if you transition your life in this direction
Like cross-border e-commerce
It doesn't matter to you
I just shoot videos for Douyin and Kuaishou
So now, more than ever, your lifestyle determines where you can live
How you make money
Decides where you can live
To put it bluntly, if your lifestyle is entirely dependent on the internet, like us
Then you can work remotely
You can completely ignore all the things about your living place
So, I advise those who can adapt to living anywhere in the country
People who can travel and live anywhere
Give it a try
Whether it's the food or the cultural environment in the northeast
Of course, you might not adapt
Because Brother Rong is a tough northerner
Like a bear
Right
So why can't I keep a round face with a beard
If I go to Chengdu
I'm afraid my lifestyle will change drastically
That's how it is
So, let's talk about this episode: the northeast is a good place
If you work in the internet sector
You can consider living there
Settle down and start a family there
Your kids can enjoy the 212-point college entrance exam
You'll be living in one of the most forward-thinking places in China
It's really interesting
Of course
We're not saying we'll settle down forever
We're just saying we'll live there for a while
Always changing, always new
We have four more episodes coming up
Listen to me as I slowly unfold the story