Plagiarism
It all started with academic misconduct
For those wealthy second-generation Chinese in Vancouver
Specializing in writing their assignments
Helping them with their papers
Assisting them in revising their papers
Right?
So, engaging in these gray area activities
Earned the first pot of gold
Of course, why isn't this industry as profitable now
Because you can't reach the high-paying clients
So, in the world
There's a fair principle
which is that as long as you can find a big sucker
you can set the price for your product
meaning you need to find high-quality customers
the high-quality customers you find will eventually pay for your product
instead of manufacturing goods first
and then figuring out how to sell them
you should identify the needs of high-quality customers first
and ensure you can connect with these high-quality customers
Then, for premium customers,
we tailor the products and services they need.
This is the best logic for making money.
Whatever they spit out,
you take in—it’s that simple.
But what’s the point of telling everyone this?
Hey everyone, as you know, I recommended it back then.
don’t open a coffee shop,
don’t open a restaurant.
This kind of thing is a money-losing proposition.
It can be quite a loss.
I actually delve into studying this group.
Who would want to run a coffee shop?
Who would want to do baking?
Who would want to work in food?
You'll find that these artistic young people in the city,
they love doing this kind of work.
I have a lot of artistic young people around me.
They have a passion for art.
They yearn for poetry and distant places.
They enjoy a beautiful life.
They organize idealistic events.
But in real life, they tend to be quite unrestrained and free-spirited.
Their lives are relatively comfortable.
They are often pampered.
They usually come from wealthy families.
Silly sons and silly daughters.
People like that
I actually despise and loathe
Just like when I was in Beijing
the place I hated the most was 798
because the people in 798 and I are completely at odds
because I believe a person's attire and appearance
should reflect their actual financial status
however
I clearly haven’t reflected my actual financial status
I wouldn’t buy it even if I had the money.
I only have a few pairs of shoes and a few pieces of clothing.
And I never replace them until they’re completely worn out.
It’s the same with my shoes.
I never replace them until they’re completely worn out.
The second pair.
I’ve been like this for more than just the past few years.
Back in high school,
and even in middle school.
In junior high, I only had a pair of Asics.
This running shoe cost 698.
When I was in high school, I only had a 399
Li-Ning basketball shoe.
In college, I changed shoes quite a bit.
Shoes made in Putian, yeah.
But they usually cost around one or two hundred.
Pretty cheap.
But later, I went abroad for my studies.
I'm still wearing the shoes from junior high.
Those Asics are really designed for jogging.
They are truly well-made.
Because they are quite expensive.
Over 690 bucks.
So I've worn them for many years.
The soles have worn through.
The entire sole has worn through.
A hole has appeared.
It's not a puncture
but rather worn thin and flat
a large hole formed on the sole
and it just tears easily
That's what it is
I've been wearing it for so many years
Do you think it's because I can't afford to buy new ones?
No, it's not that
Right?
It's just that I dislike this kind of thing
I'm willing to spend money on electronics, though.
Right?
I'm also willing to spend money on studying abroad.
I just compared the expenses for my study abroad.
with that of Xiao Bawang.
He announced the actual cost of the diploma mill in the U.S.
These easy credits.
I paid 1,500 Canadian dollars.
His Yi Xue score is only 196 dollars.
So that's it.
I'm willing to spend money in many areas.
But visiting Vancouver has one advantage though.
You get to meet a lot of rich second-generation kids.
You get to meet a lot of rich heirs.
The losses of these rich heirs are your gains.
Many of them have dreams.
Like those who want to open a coffee shop.
Their loss is your gain.
So, you need to shift your perspective.
These people open coffee shops,
you should consider getting into barista training,
or coffee shop renovations,
or coffee machines,
buying and selling used coffee machines,
it's all about supply and demand,
and then
Doing the wholesale business of Coffee Beans for that coffee shop
These are what they call upstream businesses.
You can make a profit where they lose money.
The money that comes out of it.
So, a lot of times, people need to shift their mindset.
Talking about economic upturns and downturns,
that's all relative to the overall environment.
But when it comes to specific industries, there are always some making money,
and there are always some losing money.
So, it's just that the real estate game doesn't work anymore.
Right?
So there's nothing to worry about.
People will always want to spend their money here.
So you just need to identify a specific group's needs.
Develop products and services for them.
For example, it's really hard for college students to find jobs these days.
What should you do?
Now, so many people are taking the postgraduate or civil service exams.
The chances of passing the postgraduate or civil service exams are so low
but they insist on taking them
insist on taking the civil service exam
people who take the exam for 78 years are not uncommon
before reaching the age limit
they will persist in taking the exam
the family would rather have him rely on them
than let him take the exam
despite clearly not having the capability
It has to be 1978, huh?
If he doesn’t pass, he won’t hate the owner so much.
And he’s even preparing for the civil service exam full-time.
He’s also planning to retake the postgraduate entrance exam.
Third or fourth attempt, you know.
So where is all this money going?
Most of it goes to tutoring classes.
Spent on tutoring courses.
So you should open one of these tutoring classes.
Offering such tutoring classes
means becoming a supplier for such demands
So this is the money you should be earning
That’s why in this world, where some people lose money in certain areas
there are always others who make money in other areas
For example, many people spend money on buying grains
or figurines
Many people spend money on catching dolls
Many people spend money on karaoke sessions
Many people spend money on travel
But where does this money go?
Right?
Broadly speaking, it’s earned by certain industries
However, if we look at niche markets
If you can grasp the main supply for niche demands
That’s how the money flows
Of course, when we talk about it
You grow millet
You could be sued by the copyright holder, right?
There are some things you still shouldn't touch, though.
Some things are really off-limits.
But remember, where there's demand, there's supply.
We're in the era of singles now.
In the singles era, there are more big spenders giving gifts.
Right?
There are many other needs as well.
Like the demand for the Holy Grail and such.
His needs are changing.
Or his needs remain the same.
It's still the same need.
But the way it's provided has changed.
It has become different products.
It has become different services.
So you need to follow the actual development in society.
These changes.
Where they are heading.
You should change in the same direction.
Regardless of what it turns into.
Or when it changes.
Follow the changes in societal development.
Changes in policy.
Analyze what's profitable now.
What new demands have grown larger.
What kind of demand is widespread.
I'll tell you again,
Products can be sold worldwide.
They can be sold nationwide.
Services can only be provided locally.
That's a basic principle.
So today I'll teach you another principle.
What others lose is what you gain.
Where others incur losses is where you make profits.
Where others lose money,
Is where you can make money. It's that simple.