Many people took it out of context
Brother Rong
You're someone who pursues fairness and justice, right?
Because you like the Great Emperor of Genuine Prowess
A couple of days ago, the Great Emperor of Genuine Prowess appeared to me in a dream.
He said, 'You're doing a great job, kid.'
He told me that I have the right to hang his portrait at home.
The Great Emperor of Genuine Prowess is a god of righteousness.
Why do I need to say these things?
It might seem so dark,
so terrifying,
but it's because I'm also a Machiavellian.
The core premise of being a Machiavellian is
One must not admit to being a Machiavellian.
From its inception, Machiavellianism has been
criticized and condemned.
However, it reveals a true principle in political science.
When I stand in the darkness, yearning for the light,
one person's dirt brings cleanliness to ten thousand homes.
What kind of realm is this?
Many people, lacking wisdom and possessing only a naive heart,
cannot understand your motives.
Of course.
Today, we'll continue talking about my social circle.
I left a question in my social circle.
I said, imagine you're the village chief,
you have 100 loaves of bread,
and you have a population of 100 people.
At this point, how should you distribute them?
Then I said, what you should do is use 10 of those loaves of bread
to reward the top 10 most outstanding individuals.
Then let these ten people divide up the ten loaves of bread
How much he eats himself
How much he gives to the other nine people
That's his business
But you're only responsible for distributing the ten loaves of bread
And you need to keep ninety for yourself
Then many people start to say
Brother Rong, what exactly do you mean by this
Why be so harsh
That's so cruel.
Why do you have to treat others like that?
Why can't you be a bit more kind?
A bit more forgiving?
Have you played a game called Age of Weapons?
Ah, Age of Weapons, that game.
1.0
What about 2.0?
I played Age of Weapons 1.0.
This game
is said to be completed very quickly by Chinese players, ha ha
because we have mastered an advanced theory
Marxism
the distinction between productive force and relations of production
and after many years of revolutionary practice in real life
we have found that
prioritizing the development of productive forces
is the prerequisite for all stability
So, in the early stages of playing this game,
we recommend that everyone work overtime,
strive to accumulate material wealth.
Later on, the robot core will appear.
Once everyone discovers the robot core,
they can gradually replace human labor with robotic technology.
At the same time, we have accumulated abundant material wealth,
which allows us to use this wealth to advance technology,
to conduct research.
Boosting productive force
Accelerating production efficiency
Ultimately achieving uniformity everywhere
Everywhere is full and rich
So Chinese people not only don’t find this game difficult
But they mostly achieve the best and excellent outcomes
However
Just like Western media
They would say
But at what cost, right?
But what is the cost?
This is the core topic we're discussing today.
The art of ruling.
We often say sacrificing the small self to achieve the greater good.
What is the small self?
The small self is your individual personality.
Your self is who you are.
I want to achieve my personal goals.
I need to maintain my emotions, both positive and negative.
I want to reproduce.
I want to procreate.
I want to achieve my personal life goals.
Regarding this trap of Maslow's hierarchy of needs,
What is the greater self?
For me,
the greater self is the me across lifetimes.
The eternal me.
But another way to explain the 'greater self' is that it refers to society, right?
The greater self is our community.
The greater self is ours.
To put it simply, it's the Chinese civilization.
The personal development of an individual and the collective development of a nation or race.
Which one is more significant?
What we mean by sacrificing the small,
To achieve the greater good.
To put it bluntly, it's a fearless spirit, both in public and private matters.
But how to put it,
I've always emphasized,
I really hate idealists, you know,
A couple of days ago, someone had Che Guevara's profile picture,
Ah, a lot of good-for-nothings like to use Che Guevara's profile picture,
and then started cursing at me,
saying I use all Western stuff,
and that my ideas are really unhealthy,
that I'm corrupting the youth.
Then, we should promote the idea of cutting.
And similar medications.
Everyone needs to come together and work as a team.
Basically, it’s all about chanting slogans, you know.
Actually, from a certain perspective,
Idealists are like the Western saints and social justice warriors in my eyes.
Social justice warriors are quite interesting.
Social justice warriors distribute bread.
They would say to distribute this bread to 100 people.
There are people in need
Because you can produce 100 loaves of bread a day
When you distribute the 100 loaves to these 100 people, it won’t be evenly distributed
And there won’t be any idle hands
Then these 100 people won’t start working
Instead, they will all rely on your welfare to survive
But that’s an ideal scenario
How would it play out in reality?
Because you’ve provided generous welfare
This is particularly beneficial for them.
They can eat their fill without working.
So, in reality, countless people will flood into your country.
Flood into your tribe.
Today, it might be 100 people.
Tomorrow, it could be 5,000 people.
The day after, 300,000 people.
And the day after that, 1.5 million people.
How do you deal with such a large influx of immigrants?
You can increase your magic power from making 100 loaves of bread to 150 loaves.
Can you sell ten thousand loaves of bread?
Then what would you become?
Wouldn't you become a feeder then?
Most importantly, you wouldn't be able to motivate people in society to work.
That's the world the Western saints hope for.
You should pay more taxes.
The rich should contribute more money.
But the rich aren't foolish either.
The wealthy will leave.
Large corporations will move to other countries to grow.
So, how do you maintain the art of governance?
How do you ensure the broadest possible benefit for the entire community?
For the whole civilization?
For the entire large nation?
Actually, governing a small country
Like Finland,
Or Liechtenstein, is relatively easier.
But governing a large country can be extremely painful.
Generally speaking, the universe is indifferent.
Look at the dynasties throughout Chinese history.
The most terrifying are all kinds of natural disasters and human misfortunes.
When it comes to these things,
these matters are quite challenging.
But you'll find Marxist theory interesting,
I really like that aspect.
Why I particularly enjoy the Book of Lord Shang and the Discourses on Salt and Iron.
When it comes to Legalism
you might find that on the surface, Legalism seems heartless and cruel
but in reality, this heartlessness towards certain individuals
is limited
and not entirely ruthless
while many people, like Ye Wenjie, who are seen as benevolent
if you truly act that way
it could potentially lead to the end of civilization
so your compassion needs to have a boundary
Your compassion
as a Buddha
you can
love all and refrain from aggression
love the world without discrimination
as a clan leader
how should you safeguard the rise and fall, the glory and disgrace of the entire group
share life and death
this is a very complex matter
So you must not only have a compassionate heart
but you also need to be wise
what we mean by having virtue
is to have moral integrity
to influence others with your virtue
when it comes to virtue
in the Warring States period
or in a complex and chaotic environment
it's impossible to survive in such a world
So, generally speaking, it's about paying lip service while acting contrary.
On the surface, we uphold the highest moral standards.
We still need to promote this image publicly.
We are people of high moral principles.
We are not Machiavellian.
But in reality,
it's always about the Legalist tactics under the Confucian facade.
The power must be wielded with precision.
When immigrants flood in, there’s no solution.
Of course, some people might say
if you set the price of bread so low
look at how high the prices of agricultural products are in Japan
is it because Japan has agricultural cooperatives
ensuring farmers have enough to eat and wear
and that farmers are doing really well
but compared to many other countries
the attitude of Japanese agricultural cooperatives towards farmers is different
when Japanese agricultural cooperatives ensure farmers have enough to eat and wear
He raised the price of the most basic necessities to an extremely high level
which would lead to an intense competition across society
everyone would go to great lengths to secure these 2,200 calories
the economy would certainly grow
right?
the happiness index of the people would also rise
but no one could afford to stop working
so how exactly does this play out
you'd find that 100 loaves of bread are given to these ten people
Whether it's the scholar-official groups or the Brahmans and Kshatriyas
or the samurai of Japan
regardless
it's all about the art of proxy rule
when you play Mount & Blade without mods
you'll find that there are far too many kings in Calradia
but think about it, to rule the Calradia continent perfectly
as long as you don't use cheats
you have to rely on the nobility
Because in feudal times
orders couldn't be transmitted instantly
there was a time lag
so you had to use a proxy rule method
that's how it was
just like Heshen's way of governance
with two mouths above and below
if you don't serve the mouth above
the mouth below can never be satisfied
So this is what caused the redundancy in governance.
There were many redundancies in the distribution system.
This is the issue we're discussing.
To put it another way,
We say that the imperial system and the feudal system are two completely different systems.
Feudalism,
the establishment of vassal states, is a feudal system.
The imperial system,
provincial administration,
These items
bureaucratic counties
This is another system
So we talk about Machiavellianism emerging
When discussing this book
Machiavellianism isn't meant for the common people
In fact, Machiavellianism is intended for the wise
to help you understand
when you are a common person
When you are a ruler,
you also need to be aware,
you can't be too naive,
you can't be overly merciful,
being overly merciful is not an option,
it might end up harming the other party,
so in many people's opinion,
we say that the messenger of light standing in the darkness is truly remarkable,
the so-called morning star
Morning Star
the so-called Venus
it's actually the same thing
we often talk about a movie
there's a TV show called Lucifer
talking about Lucifer, the devil himself
I'm not promoting devil worship
I'm talking about the metaphor behind it
Lucifer is the fallen angel
He messed up this angel
And then went against God
You'll find out what these things are really about
They're talking about evil
The role it plays in goodness
Taiji is not purely white
Taiji has yang within yin
And yin within yang
It's a blend of black and white
It embodies the principle of Yin and Yang, opposing forces that are interdependent.
It represents the coexistence of good and evil.
This is the concept of opposing elements existing simultaneously.
Therefore, good and evil are intertwined, each defining the other.
So, among all the angels, we say that
Lucifer is the best and most benevolent,
the healthiest one,
because he plays the role of the antagonist.
Perhaps this idea might be hard for you to grasp.
But in Western mythology,
Lucifer is often portrayed as a villain.
However, in Eastern mythology,
Lucifer, the Morning Star,
is seen as a good character, the planet Venus.
In fact, Venus truly helped Sun Wukong.
Many people don't understand this point.
But why did you suddenly start talking about this Venus, Brother Rong?
Why start mentioning this Morning Star?
This is actually a superficial metaphor for a statesman.
It refers to people who cause chaos in the world.
Yet, they are the ones who uphold peace in the world.
For example, conflicts and wars in various parts of the world today.
These conflicts and wars create immense chaos.
But they also contribute to a trend that maintains overall peace in the world.
Because people come to understand the true horrors of war and famine.
The devastation and massacres that these bring.
Thus, extreme good and extreme evil can sometimes be a matter of a moment.
In a split second
people's polarity can easily shift
but often
great deceit appears as truth
sometimes you don't understand this concept
but we talk about knowledge
the accumulation of knowledge is boundless
in our land
knowledge is unrestricted
You can buy Hayek's books in all the stores today.
Even the unedited versions.
That's why
our knowledge
including political science
sociology
and humanities
is actually open to all citizens.
This is one of the greatest aspects of it.
In our time, speaking of it
as an intellectual
it is a joyful thing
so we have to talk about the issue of bread distribution again
what is the main goal of bread distribution?
The main goal is to harness the maximum labor power of these 100 people
because when you achieve the maximum labor output
when you have the maximum labor productivity
the resources you acquire are the greatest
It's the most abundant
You can use the remaining 90 dollars to buy bread
Or you can leverage the output of these 100 people
You expand his house
Water management, healthcare, and education
Then you build tall barriers
You can't let just anyone join your country
That's how it is
And then we boost our economy
To make our tribe thrive and flourish
And gradually grow
The population will gradually increase
Only then can everyone finally put down their hoes
And eventually step into the classroom
And ultimately go home to play games
So, regarding my view of the future
I’ve never really been an optimist
But I’m optimistic about the future
I believe that human technology
robotics
brain-computer interfaces
and all these things are well-aligned with the priorities of some countries
I would say there are only two great nations in the world
one is the People's Republic of China
and the other is the United States of America
I have always praised both China and the U.S.
because many people compare various aspects of China and the U.S.
He doesn't understand the art of politics.
So he sees some surface phenomena.
He will criticize them.
He will add something to it.
But a lot of these issues are growing pains.
Of course, one day when we truly achieve an abundance of material wealth,
everywhere will be balanced,
everywhere will be warm.
I believe this is due to AI technology.
This was achieved due to the manufacturing of robotics.
What new formations of society emerged at that time?
Or what new distribution structures appeared?
That's what we're talking about for that period.
But we believe one thing:
Because the productive force has advanced.
Because the total production of materials has increased.
Because today we're not just producing 100 loaves of bread anymore.
We might have 10,000 loaves of bread.
A million loaves of bread
and they are produced automatically
So, for humans
we can say that compared to the primitive people, the people from the Stone Age
and the people from the feudal era
our labor is much easier
So, once you understand the Bronze Age
this is an incredibly good game
it can help you understand economic development
The distribution in society
the art of political governance, how should it be approached?
What strategies should be adopted in the early stages?
What strategies should be taken in the middle stages?
I believe the creator of this game is also a staunch
Machiavellian
a firm Machiavellian
who speaks very frankly about the essence of politics
which involves some level of deceit and cruelty
and some level of manipulation
not overly concerned with
initial fairness
if the initial stage is too fair
you might forget that society needs competition
because there's not just one nation in this world
not just one tribe
not just one race
all these things need to contend with natural disasters and human calamities
and immigration
and emigration
and the cycle of life and death
and all sorts of challenges
while maintaining stability
and expanding outward
so in many cases
maintaining a large country
maintaining a peaceful state
maintaining a state of abundant resources is extremely difficult
you can't judge the whole by a part
seeing a little bit and drawing a hasty conclusion
that would be entirely wrong
for me
a Machiavellian sees everything as normal
sees everything as normal
so in many ways
today, you must possess a very high level of wisdom
to understand some of the events that happen in society
not just from the perspective of the parties involved
how to achieve the greatest common good
from the perspective of the broader racial interests
from the perspective of the development of civilization
what is most important
certainly, sacrifices must be made for the few
the few
or even many people over a long period
that's how the world works
there is no absolute fairness
you can't be like Ye Wenjie
can't be too idealistic
only by not being too idealistic
can we survive in the future
and thrive in this era
Living in the present era