what we do is just like everyone else’s
but in reality, it’s quite different
Many times, our own qualities are actually quite strong
but we just don’t realize it
For example, recently, Dong has been delivering food
I watched Dong Ge deliver food.
That's when I realized many people
basically just leave the food at the door on the ground.
This is actually pretty good.
For more people,
they might see the delivery person only when they step out.
reaching out their hand quite far,
grabbing the food once they get it,
and then quickly pulling back.
Actually, I think this way of doing things
In broad daylight
How should I put it, you become
A grown man
You don’t need to be afraid of another grown man
I feel many people might, how to say it
Out of social anxiety or something
But they just don’t want to meet the delivery guy
But generally speaking
Not only open the door for the delivery guy
But give him a nod
Thank you, sir
Often times
If the delivery person comes often enough
I would offer him drinks, fans, and such
This is a very common thing
It’s not about how much these things cost
It’s the thought that counts
So everyone's approach to handling problems is entirely different.
Just as the saying goes, 'In the nick of time'.
I just received a package.
I just got some takeout.
Often, when I talk about how we evaluate ourselves,
our self-examination,
sometimes we automatically assume that
everyone in the world is just like us,
that they share the same perspective as we do.
An action
The circumstances we encounter are the same
But in many cases, the attitudes we face
The behaviors and situations are vastly different from others
I'm not just talking about food delivery
In many instances
We assume others are just as good as us
In reality, others are not as good as we are
Others might not even be one-tenth as good as us
Sometimes you might feel everyone is just as bad
but it's possible others don't encounter the same bad things you do
life might not be as painful as you think
life isn't as good as you make it out to be
nor as bad as others say
it's not really that painful
a lot of things require empathy to truly understand
you can't really feel what others are going through
that's a tough one
You can't really know for sure
how others feel about you
Let me elaborate on this
In many cases
like when I went to La Dao's exhibition
attending La Dao's exhibition
I was wearing flip-flops
my usual white shirt for shoots
and black pants, I just went
There are many people here today
most of them are UPloaders from Bilibili
and there are also a lot of media representatives
everyone is dressed very well
I'm the only one who's dressed pretty casually
but everyone knows I'm usually casual
because I'm just casual all the time
it's this kind of vibe
so many people think, 'Oh, Rong Dao'
You've got quite an attitude there.
Are you really not at all concerned about how others perceive you?
I think the issue is that you don't fully understand what others really think of you.
What exactly is their impression of you?
Many people think that wearing the most worn-out clothes makes the strongest impression.
This way, people remember me the most.
But that's not entirely true.
Or perhaps Director Arong is just different.
He can simply ignore how others feel about him.
Actually, not really.
I do have my pride.
I do have feelings.
But why do I dare to act this way?
It’s because I understand it all too well.
Often, we can sense things ourselves.
For instance, I might feel my outfit today isn’t great.
Or that my hair today isn’t looking good.
Or that I’m not in the best state today.
You always feel that others will have a poor impression of you.
People might say, 'Oh,
look at how yellow this person's teeth are.'
Look at how bald this person is.'
Look at how overweight this person is, and so on.
But in reality, in this world,
most people are more concerned about themselves.
What they think about,
first and foremost, is whether they look good or not.
But once people see me,
they all feel that they look great,
and standing next to me makes them feel even better.
So this is what we call the 'Short Person Effect'.
That's just how it works,
if you find someone shorter than you,
you won't feel short anymore.
Even if you're actually one of the shorter people in the room,
that's just the way it is.
You've given someone an anchor point
You've provided them with an opportunity to boost their self-esteem
This is the reverse psychology I'm utilizing
So in many cases
Even if I carefully pick
I carefully dress myself up
My weaknesses will still be there
It's just a matter of whether others notice them or not
And more often than not
Often, you might feel that others look down on you
or think highly of you, and so on
let me tell you
at the parties I attend
I've worn shabby clothes plenty of times
I'm completely
I have a don't give a damn look, you know
I simply don't care how others perceive me
I don't care about those who look down on me
It won’t really affect me
Because most people have no real connection to you
Even if you exchange WeChats with most people
You won’t have much in common
Most people are just passing through your life
But if you can feel at ease wherever you are
That’s a precious asset
So we often say
Don’t worry about it
Some of your things
Because some of your things might be completely different from others'
What you care about might not matter to others at all
Like when I go to open the door to welcome the delivery guy
Because I think it's a matter of my upbringing
It’s part of my normal routine
I’m willing to interact more with working people
I’m willing to connect more with these hardworking folks
And I feel there’s no difference between me and them
But many people are different
I've already had takeout
I'm at the office
I'm a white-collar worker
I'm really different from you guys
Right?
What about you, just a delivery guy
How can you do that
That's why people have different perspectives
So, people are different from one another.
From this perspective,
we need to remind everyone,
that sometimes your moral standards may be higher than others',
and you might not even realize it.
Another point is to tell you,
what others truly feel,
what others are truly passionate about,
may not be important to you.
There's also one major issue that is
Actually, I later talked with a few UPloaders who I got along well with that day
I said
It's really that you can't tell how much someone earns just by looking at them
But you can tell how much they're willing to spend from their appearance
You know what I mean
I believe if someone really earns a lot of money
It doesn't matter if they spend a bit
This aligns with their social status
But when I wasn't making much money,
I was willing to use my external spending behavior
to show how much I actually earned back then.
I should have been in a state of not making money,
giving others that impression.
However, most people,
even if they haven't earned that much money,
still spend a lot of money,
and they don't want others to feel they can't afford to spend so much.
So this is the biggest difference among people.
For example, if I earn 100 yuan,
I might feel pained to spend even one.
Some people might earn just ten yuan,
but they don't feel bad spending five or six.
So this is the difference between individuals.
What really makes the difference between us?
When it truly matters,
is that one day you might do something I can't.
That’s how I feel we’re all unique.
So, just by looking at what people wear,
I think a lot of people in the fashion industry or those who study art,
or those who study fine arts,
usually dress really well,
but in reality, their earning power,
is actually inversely proportional to their style.
So, there’s no real correlation here.
In fact, the better you dress,
How to put it
Considering one's true identity and status
And the actual income level
For me, it can also occupy more, how to say
Profit margin
Most of the time
If others feel that I come across better in comparison
Speaking of which
I might feel more at ease
Of course
I'm also doing it to strengthen my will and character
In such situations, I can still feel good about myself
Without embarrassing myself
Then you truly are at ease
You won't be held back by external things
So at that point
You really reach a state where
What you wear doesn't matter
I don't really care what I wear
It's like when Mi Heng played the drum, it doesn't matter
So this is a person's, how to say it
A strategy in life
I'd rather lose face at a critical moment
Than to spend money frequently
For seasonal changes
Always buying new clothes
I keep buying books
Keep buying games
But I really don't spend much on clothes