But that's not the case at all.
In fact, these leisure activities are one of the greatest inventions of our time.
You see,
Look at me now, staying at home.
All of my entertainment gadgets aren't expensive at all.
Including my car
Including my motorcycle
Including all my gaming consoles, they're not expensive
The sports model is over 3000, right?
The PS5 is over 2000
The Switch is around 1000
And the TV is over 4000
The computer, when added together
The configuration back then was over 7000
Right?
you can still afford them
so in our current era
even if you don't play official games
there are many games you can bundle up
to enjoy to the fullest
Right?
so in this era
you can spend the whole day watching Bilibili with the TV on
Then you just scroll with joy
Of course, hard work is crucial at times
Like reading to improve yourself
Learning self-discipline is important
But to be honest
The key to getting rich lies in seizing opportunities
I mentioned to everyone the other day
You can join me as a guest
But many people just turn a deaf ear
Just let it go
But some people actually did it
They quickly recorded over ten lessons for me
And it went pretty well
I immediately submitted it for Bilibili's review
Right?
This is a great start
So the key is how you seize the opportunity
But what about the rest of the time besides seizing opportunities?
You should still conserve your energy.
Many of these wealthy people tell you,
how they maintain self-discipline,
how their cognitive abilities are so high,
but most of the time, they are just like you,
they play games too,
they also entertain themselves,
it’s just that their entertainment might differ from yours,
it might have more social elements.
It might be a bit stronger
For instance, your entertainment might be playing billiards
His entertainment might be playing golf
It’s just that the people who play are different
He might focus on some investment information
You might listen to things related to your career
So, to put it in perspective
A lot of the time
We choose different ways to relax
But when it comes to nipple joy,
it's the greatest invention of our time.
You see, in the past,
people sought entertainment,
they looked for ways to cultivate their emotions,
they wanted to relieve their stress,
they could only read books,
go on outings,
take walks, or do other activities.
Now, let's talk about this.
You shouldn't stay at home all the time.
Staying in a safe place is fine,
where you can enjoy food delivered to your doorstep, right?
And you can also call a car,
even a luxury car,
you can get a luxury car for over a hundred bucks,
and have food delivered to your place,
not just short videos.
Beautiful women from all over the world will dance for you
And all these things
Used to require reading books to acquire
Now everyone can easily provide them to you
They just give you an online course
It’s all explained clearly
Like Brother Rong as well
This standard sociology
Father
Cyber Godfather is here to chat with you every night
to lull you to sleep
to ease your worries
and this is the best thing about our time
because he brings a lot of resources closer to you
in ancient times, people didn't have so many resources
you needed money to enjoy various entertainments
like going to a theater to listen to a performance
you had to spend a lot of money wherever you went
Spending a lot of money might not even yield today's results.
But to be honest, we should thank platforms like Pinduoduo today.
It's not because I've taken ads from Pinduoduo.
It's platforms like Pinduoduo that
offer our industrial products to you at a very low cost.
So, the existence of Pinduoduo and the like
like JD, Taobao, and Pinduoduo,
some sell at lower prices,
while others sell at higher prices.
Different people have different spending levels.
But you know, you can get the same experience at a lower price.
Isn't that right?
And every time I shop on Douyin,
If I don’t buy something right away,
They quickly offer me a discount.
Hehe, that’s how it is.
So, in our era,
So, let's talk about our era.
We can use a very affordable amount of money
We can use Pinduoduo or Pinduohao
We might not be able to see it on Douyin
We can watch Kuaishou
If it's really not possible
Or we can check out Alipay
We can watch the video section on Pinduoduo
There are many places where we can watch short videos
There are many places where we can play games
You might not be able to afford the console for a game.
You might not be able to afford a computer either.
But there are mobile versions available.
And in many cases,
if you don't want to pay for the official version,
even though the official versions are quite affordable these days,
many people still hesitate to spend the money.
You can enjoy so much entertainment for a very small cost.
This is actually a pretty amazing thing.
And we can enjoy a variety of vegetables with just a little money.
We can even afford meat.
This is something that some countries simply can't achieve.
Our agricultural product prices are incredibly low and affordable.
To be precise,
this allows you to use a minimal amount of money
to acquire a relatively
comparatively high standard of living.
And if you understand this,
The difference between you and the rich isn't that big.
They buy luxury cars,
drive luxury cars,
but you can directly ride in luxury cars.
They live in spacious penthouses in large mansions,
but you can also experience staying in homestays or luxury hotels.
You can also enjoy it,
living in luxury every day can get boring too,
they enjoy luxury cars and beautiful women.
Is that right?
He’s got a lot of women around him, and it cost him a fortune.
Should we set up a booth?
Now, to be honest,
You can get almost the same experience at a much cheaper price.
It’s just that someone is doing it for him.
You’re doing it yourself.
That’s the only difference.
So, in many cases,
We're talking about the present era.
I've enjoyed something
that even ancient emperors couldn't experience.
Like online shopping,
or having food delivered to your door,
these things are actually great.
Don't let some people dissuade you
by saying that it's not good or something like that.
You should be disciplined.
Then you'll have to go back and read the books
I actually read books too
But I read them out of necessity
I read because I need to learn
As a knowledge influencer
It's crucial to keep learning
But as a consumer
Why do you have to put yourself through so much stress
Work is already exhausting enough
Right?
Going to school is tough too.
I just want to have some fun.
Is it wrong to use my phone for entertainment?
I’m not hurting anyone else.
Right?
Why are some people in a hurry?
It’s because you’re not contributing to society by doing so.
That’s why they’re anxious.
So he’s going to manipulate you
So he’s going to tell you
You can’t do that
You need to improve yourself
Yeah
You improve yourself
Your work efficiency gets higher
Hey, you improve yourself
Your work becomes more outstanding
Right or wrong
He's taking advantage
As a worker
You're trading time for money
Why do you care so much about those things
Actually, your youth is valuable in itself
He's just buying your youth with money
Of course, if we want to get rich
We need to seize the right opportunities
This opportunity isn't available to everyone.
Many people can't recognize it.
And he says,
That's how fate works.
It's just the way it is.
Actually, personality is destiny.
With such a lousy personality,
You're bound to have a lousy destiny.
There's no way to change that.
And you don't recognize opportunities either.
But I said it.
Most people,
the majority of ordinary folks can't all become bosses.
ordinary people are content with a warm home and family.
just a small piece of land to call their own.
that's all there is to it.
just staying warm and comfortable,
just indulging in desires.
That's all there is to it.
There's no difference at all.
This is the common crowd.
Not everyone has to be an alpha male.
Not everyone needs to engage in wordplay.
Not everyone has to talk about being at the top of the pyramid.
Then defecate at the top.
It's not like that.
Not everyone is cut out to storm Chang'an and slay the hundred flowers.
That's it.
Otherwise, society would be in chaos.
So, in this context,
being a 'nipple' is a very normal thing.
It can make us very happy.
It can make many of our worries
and troubles disappear.
Actually, this is a good thing.
Don't let those social media influencers,
including myself,
lead you into a lifestyle you dislike.
If the way of life I advocate
happens to be one you like,
for example, I'm an ENTJ,
I think everyone is lazy when I look at them.
But are they really lazy?
They might just be living at their own pace.
If everyone were like me,
we'd all be exhausted.
You know,
ambition every day,
various kinds of revenge,
figuring out how to make money,
and gain power,
that would be exhausting.
That's the heart of an emperor.
To be honest,
it's better for everyone to be a commoner,
to live a simple life.
There's nothing wrong with that.
Don't think buying a spinning top is a bad thing.
I'm not being sarcastic.
Because being happy is the most important task in life.