But I don’t plan to discuss it.
Why don’t I plan to talk about it?
Because over the past couple of days, I’ve seen many bloggers
talking about this incident.
They’re all riding the wave of this traffic.
Many people are spreading their opinions on this.
It leads to another level
the issue of gender opposition
as a positive influencer
I don’t intend to
stir up and exacerbate the topic
today I will only discuss how an individual in society
should know and abide by the law
how to uphold the law while being aware of it
and how to promote legal awareness
We need to respect the law.
Respect the facts.
On this basis,
How can we protect ourselves?
As a person in the real world,
When I was 12 years old,
My parents took me to Xidan Book Building,
And bought two books.
This book is a bit thinner than the first one.
I hadn't started looking at civil law back then.
Later, I read civil law, contract law, and so on.
But criminal law was the first thing I needed to look at.
Because I was about to start middle school.
At the time, I didn't understand the significance of what my parents were doing.
But I understood later.
Life is a journey where I tread as if on thin ice.
Life is a journey.
Actually, according to the standard theory,
teenagers tend to be more impulsive,
in your twenties, you have all sorts of desires,
and all sorts of behaviors,
by your thirties, you might start a company,
right?
and there’s real criminal investigation involved,
it involves detailed work,
right?
What do you have in terms of financial matters?
Areas where you're confused
Areas where you lack legal knowledge
Places where you don't know can easily lead to mistakes
So throughout one's life, it's essential to know the law
First and foremost, you need to understand the law
Understand the situation at hand
And you must respect the law
Respect the authority of the law
For me,
the authority of the law lies in what?
It lies in seeking a lawyer first when there's an issue.
Not going to the media.
Many people nowadays are swayed by online trends,
which can lead them astray.
They think that as long as they make a big fuss about it,
once everyone knows about it,
the parties involved will feel embarrassed.
He can bring up something that is actually useless, right?
It's actually useless.
You'll find that when things escalate, that's when people start talking.
Ultimately, it's still about who has the right and who has the advantage.
Often, you know,
We need to respect the professionalism of the law right from the start.
There are many types of lawyers, you know.
There are divorce lawyers,
contract lawyers.
Is that right?
There are legal advisors from large corporations.
There are all sorts of them.
For example, there are copyright lawyers.
There are civil ones.
There are criminal ones.
Criminal defense lawyers.
They're all different.
So each law, like copyright law,
That's precisely the case.
So, every law has its specialized content.
When we look at their entire lives,
starting from law school,
graduating with a degree in law,
passing the bar exam,
and then interning at a professional law firm,
interacting with the courts for a long time,
and dealing with the police as well.
The experience accumulated by others
is not just several times more than yours
it's hundreds of times more
and there's a statistical probability for that
like when I sometimes do consulting
Check out this one from my company.
the scope of business
corporate culture consulting
personal financial management consulting, that's how it works
The more clients you interact with,
the more accurate advice you can give them.
Why is that?
Because most people,
they accumulate their experiences of success and failure.
Lawyers do the same.
Being a lawyer is a highly professional career.
Often,
they base their advice on past clients.
The actual handling situations are different.
And I suggest that everyone,
if you are in Shandong,
find a lawyer in Shandong,
if you are in Henan, find a lawyer in Henan.
Never cross regions,
cross industries,
or cross specialties to look for one,
as it's not appropriate.
If you find yourself in a new place,
where you don't know anyone or anything,
try not to be overly boastful or aggressive.
Don't act like a bully.
Avoid doing such things.
You should tread carefully.
When you're in a different place,
make sure not to be overly showy or arrogant.
If you're eating dumplings, dip them in soy sauce if that's what you should do.
You should dip it in vinegar when it's appropriate, right?
In many cases,
don't do things that may cause suspicion.
because you never know when certain things might come your way.
And when such things happen,
The first thing is to stay calm
Believe that,
believe in the fairness of the law,
and at the same time, understand that the law is fair.
So you need to find the most professional people to help you.
So, no matter what,
Like me, speaking here,
I have many lawyers on my WeChat,
I specifically label each lawyer’s location,
For example, this lawyer is from Wuhan,
This lawyer is from Nanjing,
This lawyer specializes in contract law,
This lawyer focuses on criminal defense.
This lawyer specializes in divorce cases.
This lawyer deals with legal matters related to going abroad.
It's about foreign trade.
I always give people special notes.
I have a great deal of respect for the lawyer among my friends.
And for all kinds of police officers.
That's how it is.
Because everyone has their own area of expertise.
No matter when you encounter something, it's always like this.
Ask others more often
Consult a lawyer for some matters
Uncle Hat can be consulted for certain things
It's actually very safe
In many cases
If you don’t do anything that could be misinterpreted
If you don’t do anything ambiguous
Some things won’t find you
Some things won’t come to you
We can't really specify what's ambiguous.
In any case, don't leave room for misinterpretation.
Don't give the other party a chance.
Just proceed with it.
How should I put this?
Tsk, leave a way for them to counterattack.
Many people often say,
I'm willing to go to bars and nightclubs.
I'm willing to go to PC.
I'm free
I don't care about being young
Anyway, it's no big deal
I belong to the vulnerable group of citizens
The law will protect me
Don't think like that
Because many people, once they commit a crime
They are no longer ordinary people
They become criminals
There's not much to talk about when it comes to criminals.
Not much at all.
You're different from ordinary good people.
Right?
So, a lot of the time, it’s best to avoid places like bars.
Nightclubs and such.
Because in those places, you’re more likely to encounter things like prostitution, gambling, and drugs.
The closer you get, the more likely you are to run into problems.
Look, I’ve never dared to touch prostitution, gambling, or drugs in my entire life.
Why?
Because I know the harm isn't in the thing itself.
It's not just about the money.
It really goes beyond just money.
Often, what gets you into trouble is this kind of issue.
You have to be very careful.
Always stay humble and cautious.
Don't be arrogant or impatient.
Throughout my life, I tread as if on thin ice.
I've never dared to confront such matters head-on
And most importantly
Remember, the character for 'color' has a knife above it
Many people say
Going to bars to pick up people
You're saying this kind of behavior
It's just plain stupid
Some say
I don't have any issues with that
Often, you think you're fine.
But that's just the survivor's advantage.
Often, you don't know about it.
When something really goes wrong, you'll regret it.
So you should be grateful for the past.
Everyone gave you a break.
In many cases, it's like this.
And let me tell you,
There are some things that, you know,
We're not talking about everything.
Many things can be resolved without escalating the situation.
When you calmly and rationally discuss things with others.
There's always room for negotiation.
And often, the outcome of many issues comes down to money.
It's about financial matters.
It's about disputes over interests.
Many people argue with you because of this.
Including incidents like car accidents.
Don't argue over this and that with each other
Everyone uses their own energy
To do their own thing
In the end, it all boils down to the amount of compensation
So you have to believe
There's nothing in this world that can't be resolved
Even when you see a lot of people involved
It often comes down to the compensation amount
So at any time
Remember, first and foremost, don't suffer immediate losses.
Second, don't confront head-on.
Third, try to communicate effectively.
Make sure to explain the rationale clearly.
Don't.
How should I put this?
Acting rashly in the moment.
Giving in to a moment's anger.
The result of confronting someone head-on is that you end up losing.
Because often times,
we emphasize being modest and cautious,
not being arrogant or impatient is a proper way to handle issues,
a way to resolve conflicts.
Many times, don't think of seeking out journalists just because you're idle,
or posting on Weibo just because you have nothing to do,
or sharing on your Moments just because you're bored,
or publishing all your chat records and such.
Actually, this is a sign of legal ignorance.
This is the most fundamental issue.
Today, I saw someone in the group chat saying,
about that scumbag,
what he did and all that.
I said this is a classic case of legal ignorance.
This scumbag,
his home address,
Everything I did was exposed by you, right?
you've committed the crime of defamation.
He said that what he did was wrong.
The law doesn't care about that.
That's what he means.
If you leak this to the media,
it counts as defamation.
This is the truth.
He's enjoying himself even while eating shit.
Even if it's true,
you're still committing defamation.
Do you understand?
If this isn't true,
Defamation is a serious criminal offense.
That's why many people think they can get away with anything online.
You see, whoever spreads false rumors doesn't go unpunished, right?
So, in many cases,
the more famous someone is,
the more attention they attract.
having a bit of power
being a minor official
having some money
people will start to covet you
they'll try to bring you down
just look at the false accusation case against Zhu Jun
so remember the right approach
first, you need to back down
back down
Don't always assume that everything is presumed innocent.
It's not that easy.
First and foremost, you need to trust the law.
Trust the professionalism of your lawyer.
Follow the lawyer's guidance and advice.
There are various actions involved.
Don't do anything the lawyer advises against.
And most importantly, you need to understand.
Many things, to put it bluntly, can't be spelled out too clearly.
It's not good if you're too explicit.
Don't act on impulse.
Don't let someone who doesn't understand the situation
your parents speak on your behalf,
or do things for you.
Don't give them ammunition by idly saying something.
This is crucial.
Maintaining contact is right,
but let the lawyer handle the communication.
Let the lawyer handle it.
Anything can be worked out.
There's always room for maneuver.
Whether it's your attitude in admitting fault,
or your willingness to compensate in various ways,
in many cases,
if you haven't repaid the money you owe,
and you don't show a good attitude of repentance,
then you might as well stand your ground.
You need to trust in the fairness of the law.
This has become known nationwide.
Then you might really have no room for maneuver.
Of course, the most important thing is not to break the law.
Don't infringe on others' rights.
You can think the other party is...
No matter what.
If someone bullies you.
The other party has no reason.
This mistake isn't yours to bear.
But in many situations,
in practical operations,
you've already taken a clear hit,
so don't insist on fighting it out.
It's pointless.
Because in many cases, it's not a place where you can just reason things out.
I mean, it's not a place where you can argue your case freely.
Often, things have to be handled according to the law.
Based on the facts at the time
Following the procedures of the investigation
Isn't it that everyone would feel wronged if they said that
Wouldn't that just be chaos
So in many cases
It's not about what you think
It's not about your subjective perception of the facts
But it's about the objective view from a third party
Whether you are the perpetrator or the victim
It's about how a third party perceives the situation
And it also depends on the social context of the time
This is crucial
What was the prevailing social climate back then
What was the social situation at that time
It's very important
The development of China's legal system has been a long process
You need to understand that going back a few decades
There were many crimes that don't exist now
Right?
So now you have to look at it from that time's perspective
To understand the issues of that era
And the issues of today
Everyone would deserve to be shot
Right?
Many things are like this
We need to have wisdom when it comes to many things
Don't argue with history
Don't argue with reality
You can't win a fight against a stronger force
There are many places where we can speak openly
We can find someone to help
Find someone
We can leverage connections
Leverage connections
Many situations aren't as inflexible as they seem
In China, many issues
Everyone believes that offering a cigarette
or raising a toast can solve it
So what I'm talking about is
the difference between a 20-year-old and a 40-year-old
At 20, you're full of vigor and enthusiasm
thinking you can take on the world with your bare hands
but in reality, it's still your parents who clean up your mess
So by the time you reach 40, you realize
that everyone is equal before the law
We need to learn the law
We need to spread legal knowledge
Mastering the right methods is crucial
I'm still learning about new developments to this day
We need to keep learning
Follow these cases and such
Many people tend to get caught up in their own emotions
Thinking they are someone else
Thinking they are that person
The woman puts herself in the woman's shoes
The man puts himself in the man's shoes
So they both speak from their own perspectives
Both believe they are the victims
Both see themselves as the injured party
Each expresses their own views
And then
Regardless of how society ultimately turns out
You feel that there are all kinds of provocations causing conflict and division
Actually, this is not a good approach.
It can easily create a chaotic and negative social environment.
Self-media platforms should also have a sense of responsibility.
They need to keep learning.
They need to know when it’s appropriate to speak up.
And when it’s better to stay silent.
So I can offer a reminder here for everyone.
Remember to avoid walking by the river whenever possible.
Frequent walks by the river are risky.
Who says you have to get your feet wet?
Then you don’t go.
Look at the internet cafe.
Places like nightclubs and bars, why not go to a pool hall?
Why not play on a PC?
Why not stay away from adult content?
Why bother with these things?
Why touch those slot machines?
Where would there be so many troubles?
Is that right?
So in many cases,
especially a lot of people don't know this,
those so-called Nine Great Deity Welfare Machines,
the bosses who illegally collect public deposits,
many of them have already been caught,
so a lot of people are unaware of these things,
you really need to be cautious,
even someone as cautious as me, who is always on guard
Sometimes, you might also encounter some
very challenging situations
In such cases, when it's necessary, you should consult a lawyer
consult a lawyer
you should seek advice from
If you trust Uncle Hat, then trust Uncle Hat
Often, in many situations
you need to have friends
you don't have any friends
There's a person who's away from home
What else are you going to do
Some dirty deeds
So you've been wronged in this matter
Falsely accused
Set up by someone
That's quite normal, right
So when you're not in your own backyard
You need to mind your own business
You always have to remember
you are just an ordinary person
just an ordinary individual in a big city
couldn't be more common
you're not from an ancient noble family
In my hometown, the Brahman community
If you really are from the Brahman caste and plan to leave your county
there might be something wrong with me too
it's the same in any society
A few days ago, a blogger was filming in Sweden
and then got arrested
That's how it is
Sweden is one of the most anti-China countries in the world
When US police encounter some issues
In our place
people can throw tantrums and act unruly
there's room for de-escalation
but over there, they might just shoot
So, often it's not about which society you're in,
it's the same in any society,
the United States is also a society where personal connections matter,
Japan is no different,
so to speak,
if you have a relative over there,
would you be able to get an advantage in Kyoto?
would you be able to get an advantage in Texas?
Do you think you can get the upper hand over Texas?
If you have two lively friends
then it really makes a difference
The environment is quite different
So never compete with the environment
While we're alive
don't think these things have nothing to do with you
Always keep the warning bell ringing in your mind
Stay vigilant
Because losing your freedom will cost you a lot
Losing freedom
You'll have a criminal record
And you'll also have to pay civil damages
Right?
You'll bear criminal responsibility
And also have to pay civil damages
In many cases
So I'm telling you, don't fight
Don't fight
Don't make any economic mistakes
And avoid getting involved with gambling, prostitution, or drugs
Many things are ambiguous
If you can avoid doing something, then don't do it
When you can avoid making mistakes
Try not to make them
Don't leave any room for ambiguity with anyone.
Think thrice before you act
Some things, you know
think about how difficult it will be to prove your innocence later
so don't engage in such activities in the first place
So, when it comes to many things
it's not about being evasive; rather
you need to understand the law
so that no one can use the law against you
Secondly, it's about respecting the professionalism of the law
if you need a lawyer, get one
Thirdly,
it’s important to make as many friends as possible,
try to make more friends,
right?
having friends in every division,
that’s a good thing,
right?
they can at least speak up for you,
far and wide.
So, in many cases,
the most important thing is not to break the law.
If you do commit a crime,
others can't always speak up for you, right?
For minor issues,
like getting a ticket,
it might be forgivable,
or it could be a special circumstance,
for example, if you're pregnant and didn't wear a seatbelt
Then it can be forgiven.
So that's how it often goes.
There isn't much more wisdom I can offer.
Tomorrow is my book signing event.
I'll be arriving at the Shandong Book City on time tomorrow.
This person throughout their life,
Let me tell you, in many cases,
Even if you don't make mistakes,
Trouble will still find you.
So often, when faced with issues, don't be afraid.
It's important to respect the authority of the law.
Respecting the authority of the law is crucial.
We must also respect the professionalism of the law.
The key is to avoid making mistakes unnecessarily.
Even if you do make a mistake,
it’s important to repent promptly.
Communicate appropriately with others.
Having a good attitude towards admitting guilt is essential.
Problems that can be solved with money aren't really big problems.
So, don't push people to their limits.
Don't make absolute statements.
Don't act on impulse.
Often, that's how things are.
Don't do things that please your enemies and upset your friends.
Many things don't have clear rights and wrongs.
Just because you escalate an issue doesn't mean it will be resolved.
Try to resolve issues within a small circle.
So, I'll say this to everyone again.
No matter what,
remember, in this society,
you may not intend to harm others,
but you can't guarantee that there aren't psychopaths in the world,
or small-minded people,
or those who want to bully you,
or harm you.
Many people in this world feel uncomfortable if you don't escalate things,
they think it's a good thing,
it's just crazy.
So, don't provoke these people.
If you do provoke them,
remember at the first moment,
Remember to tune in to TIME No.1 as well.
the first thing is to calm them down.
I think I have the right to speak on this.
So, often remember this point,
don't do anything too outrageous.
If you do something outrageous,
you should know how to handle it timely,
how to handle it,
don't do anything illegal or risky,
risky things,
some people often take pictures or videos and sell them online,
sell them on Twitter,
thinking it's fine because it's not seen in China,
do you think the police are fools?
Right?
Some people even say, 'I've just made a few more friends, it's not a gathering or anything like that.',
Is that true?
Brother,
do you understand that the law doesn't consider your specific circumstances?
So, often speaking,
we must enforce the law,
pay attention to these matters,
but we can't mislead public opinion in the wrong direction.
This is very important.
As a media creator,
don't just chase traffic,
you'll regret it.
Often, that's how it goes.
Pay attention to these matters
no matter what happens,
we always say,
don't break the law,
know and abide by the law,
this is very important.
And I hope everyone,
lives happily every day,
know and abide by the law,
you won't have to fear these things.