And Yin has another path.
They are different.
Often, we talk about being consistent inside and out.
But in reality, the surface and the inside can be different.
There are many aspects to consider.
It represents the interplay of yin and yang
and the connection between above and below
which are in opposition
meaning that some things have one form in folk culture
and another form in official contexts
some things look one way for men
and another way for women
some things appear one way on the surface
but are quite different behind the scenes
We often say that our culture is inclusive and diverse.
Chinese culture has elements of subtlety.
This is quite prevalent.
It's more of a philosophy of survival.
After all, we are a civilization with a history of thousands of years.
Isn't it a civilization with a 5000-year history?
More accurately, it's a blend of various civilizations.
Along with this inclusiveness.
Of course, we have our own cultural and philosophical traditions.
There are many things to talk about
like what we're discussing today
including what you see me talking about
although on the surface, I'm discussing Machiavellianism
the core foundations of Western political science
and Adlerian psychology in the West
and how to put it, Max Weber's sociology in the West
but in reality, I'm also delving into our own
Chinese philosophical principles
Oh, last time I talked about the widespread AOE among the post-60s and post-70s generation.
So many people said, 'Hey, Brother Rong, that's not right.'
Actually, there are quite a few post-60s and post-70s who are pretty decent.
I was referring to these decent people,
who are definitely more open-minded in their generation,
more understanding,
and more capable of being inclusive.
And those who lack this inclusiveness,
the ones who get upset and angry right away,
Actually, to me, animals are just objects to be utilized.
It's because, from any era you look at it,
or from any perspective,
we say no regional discrimination,
no ageism,
no gender discrimination.
But when you don't engage in some aspects of communication studies
your content won’t create much of a stir,
and after watching, it won’t evoke any emotional response from the audience.
When it comes to this thing
From the perspective of communication studies
It won’t spread very far
Therefore, it hasn’t been properly transmitted
It’s given a strong name as the Way
Even though it’s named as the Way
In reality, there’s nothing gained, nothing to be gained
So when it comes to many things
The purpose of spreading something is actually about
A genuine achievement
A real celebrity
The established figures from the 1960s
And those from the 1970s
is dismissive of the previous forum or video
To hurl insults at others
Or engage in verbal battles through private messages
When you are 50, even 60 years old
Or 70 years old
At 567, you're already one foot in the grave.
The yellow earth is already up to your neck.
It’s already up to your chin.
You’re going to compete with the younger generation?
This first shows that you haven’t attained enlightenment.
You lack virtue.
You haven’t seen through the mechanisms of life.
Secondly, speaking of which,
Aren’t there many people of your generation?
Indeed, just like Yuan Tengfei
just like Shi Guopeng
it's this kind of thinking
this is the understanding I was talking about
it also refers to some of the outstanding figures
he is like this
but this is the sorrow of the times
it flows like a long river
it is the sorrow of the times
So it's a monk
Haha, it doesn't matter
But for the later generations
The younger ones looking ahead
When they look at people like you
They actually see things quite clearly
Especially for those of us who are better at English
When we look at America or the West
We see things more clearly, right?
Because you didn't get an 8.05 in IELTS, right?
That's how it is.
So many times, these people are not convinced.
These people, their views on Western politics are often shaped by a lack of understanding.
They have a deep and profound affection for Western systems.
A profound love, you see.
That's just the way it is.
They simply don't understand.
They suffer from not being proficient in English.
Did you know?
They haven't implemented widespread scientific literacy education.
Nor have they provided education in humanities and political science.
So, he always has a vague admiration for these things.
It's almost like a religious sentiment.
A deep affection for A MEEA.
So, it's quite normal.
He has experienced the United States during the Clinton era.
He has seen the U.S. military during the Gulf War.
He looks ambitious.
Watching Titanic,
he naturally has a fantasy about that kind of beauty,
but this fantasy is disconnected from reality.
In reality,
what he sees is the emotions between white people,
the emotions between white people and their countries,
the love that white countries have for white people.
He doesn’t factor in that he is a non-believer.
I am not Anglo-Saxon
I am of the yellow race
I am a descendant of the Chinese civilization
He couldn't have predicted this
So it often leads to the tragedy of their era
So it still hurts
Hehe, why be so sad and hurt
So just watch him
It gets funnier
Let's be honest here
Where does power come from?
He would say
Whom does it serve?
You folks, the older generations, the 60s and 70s babies
Let me ask you
People often say
I've given you a like and followed you.
You're amazing
What's the point of it?
Right?
The most useful followers for me are those who have powered up with a payment.
My captain
My consulting followers
These people are putting in real money.
For what?
And what are most of these people?
Mostly they are from the post-90s and post-00s generations.
Most of them, you could say over 80%, are from the post-90s generation.
There are very few from the post-80s generation.
And even fewer from the post-00s generation.
Because the post-00s are still mostly in school.
Speaking of the post-80s generation,
many of them don't use Bilibili.
There are usually only a few from the post-60s and post-70s generations.
Even if you really like it, from my perspective,
it doesn't make much of a difference, right?
No Poland, nothing to see here
You're not a paying customer
Others won't be inclined towards you
Especially in today's internet context
You had your time
Back in your day, Yilin magazine
Many things were already given to you back then
So arguing with people online now
Or criticizing those people
You're actually a giant baby of the times.
You've already passed the age of thirty, the age of establishment.
Forty is the age of no confusion, which is already in your fifties or sixties.
The age of sixty, the age of maturity.
By then, you'll have lost most of your functions.
You would have already retired.
Now you're using software that young people use online.
And competing for gold with the younger generation.
What's your reason for that?
You're most likely around 1450.
You're not a true person from the 60s or 70s.
Think about how many people from the 80s use Bilibili.
People from the sixties and seventies who still use Bilibili to watch trending videos
make up a small portion of the crowd.
I'm even among the genuine followers
Among the genuine paying followers
people in this age group are very few.
Because I can see the actual data precisely in the backend.
My followers from the post-90s generation make up about 400,000.
My Gen X and Gen Y followers add up to 390.
Right?
You can't even tell.
So how did these people suddenly appear?
That's why many people notice this kind of thing.
Seeing this kind of traffic,
they think it's about them.
You are not who you think you are.
You don't have to admit it.
You can just click the exit button in the top right corner.
Why do you have to complain?
Why do you have to attack?
It's pointless.
So if you want to achieve something in today's self-media,
you first can't be afraid of being attacked.
You also can't be afraid of being slandered.
Sometimes you just need to AOE.
Sometimes, overcorrection is necessary.
After you've said something that went too far,
you should apologize if you need to.
But if you're constantly afraid of losing followers,
constantly afraid of saying something too harsh,
you'll never gain new followers.
You won't grow at all.
It's the same with everything.
Including when you see me criticizing Confucius.
Isn't Confucius considered the Supreme Sage and Teacher?
Isn't he?
Well, it's a bit complicated.
He was one of the notable scholars during the Spring and Autumn and Warring States periods.
So, when we talk about it,
we're discussing Confucius's historical significance.
It's not something that can be undermined by just a few words from me.
I've also mentioned Zhuge Liang.
Is it because I dislike the Chancellor that I talk about Zhuge Liang?
I'm not talking about the Zhuge Liang from historical records.
I mean, not the Zhuge Liang from the novel.
When I mention Zhuge Liang, this person who has been gone for a thousand years,
it's not to nitpick or criticize him.
Rather, it's for the people who admire him in later generations,
those who love him,
so they don't make the same mistakes he did,
and end up with regrets.
The same goes for Confucius.
Was I talking about the real Confucius himself?
I was referring to Dong Zhongshu.
I was talking about those pedantic scholars.
Not Confucius himself.
So when many people hear this,
Rong Zhen says those from the 60s and 70s,
You’re actually insulting us and the like,
You’re at this age now,
And you’re still so worked up about it.
Don't you have the three highs?
Don't you have high cholesterol and high blood pressure?
Right?
Don't you have diabetes?
Don't you have prostatitis?
A lot of issues are like this.
Do you really have to compete with the younger generation?
And this is a topic we're discussing among ourselves.
Rather than putting it in the newspaper.
Then talking about the post-60s generation
the post-70s generation being bad or something
I wonder if there are more bad apples among you
or more brainwashed ones
or if some people are just from your era
Some people say
that in our time, we still have entrepreneurs
Which era doesn't have entrepreneurs?
Buddy
Are you?
You're not though.
You need to power up.
Then you could become a business owner.
But you're not though.
So you have little influence.
To me, you're nothing.
So let's talk about what a true fan is like.
What defines a true paying follower?
What kind of person are you?
gave others money
gave others a real boost of energy
only then will they respect you
So that's the way of it
Why do I respect the post-60s so little
What about the post-70s?
Ah, what do you all think?
Maybe it's because there's indeed Shi Guopeng
Yuan Tengfei talks about human existence
Of course, let's start with that
Do you think I haven't bought any of Yuan Tengfei and Shi Guopeng's books?
Oh, I have bought their books too
When it comes to learning from others, I always focus on their strengths
I always look for the best in others
I always see the good in others
Like how I have books by Yi Zhongtian at home
You can see I have books by many authors at home
These people's books
Do I agree with every single one of their viewpoints?
Right?
That's not the case.
But when it comes to a person
When it comes to Yan Chongnian's books, do I have a lot to say about them?
If you want to study someone
You need to understand their work
They can become a leading expert in their field
He must have his own skills.
I haven't bought any of Zhang Xuefeng's books, right?
But when you say I agree,
with Zhang Xuefeng's views on everything,
his views on women's efforts in particular,
I don't align with him, right?
So it's not about being exactly the same as others,
it's about finding common ground while respecting differences,
and learning from each other's strengths to make up for our weaknesses.
Being able to see people's strengths is truly important.
So, in many cases,
I'm talking to those of you who insulted me in the comments of my last video
Actually, I was swept up by my own traffic.
Every time you scold, every time you like
every time you share it,
every time you do something,
you're helping to expand my influence.
If you truly dislike such statements,
You should just close it from the top right corner.
And the official can approve it for me.
If the official lets me speak for 45 years here,
That proves my words have a market.
I can influence a lot of people.
Your words can't influence many people.
So you only have a dozen followers
You have fewer than a hundred followers.
So your words carry little weight.
So this is the fact you should accept.
All these things.
Don't always complain about them.
I can't figure out what's up with the young people nowadays.
I can't stand that.
You're always criticizing me.
Remember, this person is a big deal in China.
Even if it's something happening in the world.
Even if there's something you don't understand at all.
You should also understand that they have their own audience.
Just like a Gen X once told me,
I don't get what today's kids are into with all this cosplay.
What's the point of it?
Well, if you don't understand, then you just don't understand.
You've hit the nail on the head.
You don't understand,
it's because you're out of touch with the times.
it's because you can't see through these things.
And now, those who are making a mark in society are the post-80s generation.
The post-90s generation.
The post-00s generation.
In a few years, I'll start criticizing the post-80s generation.
Because by then, they will have become an obstacle to social progress.
As a member of the post-80s generation,
I am also an obstacle to progress.
So I criticize myself along with them.
Do you think I don't criticize myself often enough?
I criticize myself a lot too
Let me tell you
Know yourself
Understand the world
Embrace all beings
These are three realms
Have you truly known yourself?
Extend kindness to others
Do you dare to confront your own ego?
To break down the barriers brought by self-esteem
If you can truly overcome these obstacles to this extent
If you can truly understand to this depth
Eliminate the ego
Then you will truly see the greater self
See the universe and all beings
See yourself and your true self
In fact, these are all the same
The universe is also you
All beings are also you
You are also among all beings
You are also yourself
Often, some people reach a certain age
I think it's still possible to catch up in your thirties and forties
Or even in your sixties and seventies
Or fifties and sixties
There are still those with a childlike mindset
Even after adolescence, they still have youthful aspirations
If you care so much about face and self-respect,
you'll end up achieving nothing in your life,
amounting to nothing at all.
Using this to describe you,
is an insult to nothingness itself.
You can't even understand a few harsh words.
Are you the one who was verbally abused by Prime Minister Zhuge Liang until you spat blood?
Is it
Are you Wang Lang?
Is that right
You can't even bear a few harsh words
Let alone something that doesn't concern you
Why are you so eager to prove yourself?
Didn't you just fall into my trap of communication studies?
Buddy
So these people are useless
These people don't pay either.
These people aren't my followers at all.
Not even followed
You either follow
or pay,
right?
Either you don't even follow
after all these years,
Do you think you've given me the Triple Combo?
I have to answer you
Do you think you can give me a Triple Combo?
You followed me
Are we equals?
We're not equals at all
Buddy
So, when it comes to it
I won't pay you any attention
I'll just use you
and won't pay you any attention
and when we get to the crucial moment
China has always operated on both yin and yang principles simultaneously
our high school
our high school had very strict rules
boys' hair couldn't be longer than one centimeter
girls weren't allowed to wear makeup
we couldn't have much of a life
we couldn't do anything at all
Unlike today's middle school students
Of course, our school's academic performance was only average in Haidian District
But our school had strict rules
Why did our school have such strict rules?
Because it was a special era
Our school produced a particularly high number of delinquents
These delinquents from our school
If you take the time to look into it
You can start by searching for Rongzhen High School on Baidu
Then, over the decades, what this high school has been up to
You'll find out
So the school later tightened its rules
But let me tell you
The stricter a school is
The greater the contrast
The more rebellious people there are
That's the characteristic of our school
Well, our school has produced another talent, how should I say it
Someone from the performance department has become the lead singer of a rock band
It's all about death metal and such
So, the more repressed, the more liberating it becomes
In our year, it was the least romantic across the entire school
There were all kinds of couples, but the least amount of dating
But there was this girl in our year
I knew her before
She hasn't really talked to many people since high school
She has generally avoided boys
Later, she married her junior high school physical education teacher
Based on my deduction
This is my deduction
I'm not slandering anyone
Based on my deduction
This girl was probably still a minor during her school days
And she might have had some inappropriate relationship with the teacher
But to talk about it
He was the victim.
This teacher turned out to be such a wolf in sheep's clothing.
Although they ended up together later.
They seem to be divorced now.
But it was over this very incident.
I've been talking about this all along.
In our school, where the discipline is so strict.
How could something like this happen?
So, human nature is truly unpredictable.
There's another teacher at our school
who also got divorced
and is now with a student
so when we talk about it
we say that the kind of thing that often happens at Japanese schools
the kind of thing you see in adult films
actually happens at our school
of course, I'm not saying we spread gossip
or use it to attack others
Where are you going?
You didn't know these two students at first
What are these two people doing now?
Where are they?
To start with
This was something from 20 years ago
But we were all quite surprised back then
How did you get married right after graduation?
How did you end up marrying the teacher so soon after?
How did the teacher get divorced from his wife?
You two are together now?
It's just that back then, there was a lot of gossip.
They had to go through a lot of such pressure.
But what I'm saying is,
As a role model,
If you're a college teacher,
In some aspects,
You marry a student.
It's still somewhat possible, not too disgusting.
You're a teacher at an art school.
Or a regular middle school teacher.
A junior or senior high school teacher.
A school actually had this happen twice.
Two teachers from the same year went to mess with students.
It makes me feel really... I don't know what to say.
Because they're minors.
They don't have much judgment at that age.
You can care about others
You can love others
You can tutor others
You can follow others' growth
But you bring someone home to marry
What's going on here
Right
Isn't that a creepy old man
So, to talk about it
Often, you see,
people say that the postgraduate entrance exam is tough.
Regarding postgraduate studies,
sometimes I hesitate to mention,
things about the academic circle to you.
Of course,
many postgraduate supervisors are not inappropriate in their behavior.
You folks from the 60s,
70s, and even the 50s,
Many people in the circle of knowledge
Many so-called people in the cultural circle
Do you not feel tempted to touch a young girl's thigh when you see it?
So on the surface, you appear to be a role model
How do you appear on the surface?
How do I appear on the surface?
I am the one who supervises China
Then you should be touching your students' thighs
Touching students' thighs, right?
Isn't that right?
You said it
For the sake of art
So in many cases
China is a place of yin and yang
Precisely because we often advocate for moral righteousness
Full of moral righteousness
So hypocrites can easily gain the upper hand
That's why I use this kind of value system
Just like the Machiavellianism you mentioned
We appear to be bad on the surface
But in reality, we are far from being true villains
We are just not hypocritical
Teach people to be genuine
To be a real person
To seek the true path
To be truly constant and firm
In many cases, it's like this
So essentially speaking
What I study is Eastern philosophy
Indeed, I am sharp and true
So these things
I have a strong pursuit of truth
But I can be unrestrained and free
I can be unrestrained and free
Why do I add little sisters on WeChat
Because I am a true and sharp person
I must tell you
I want to add you on WeChat
I might have all sorts of intentions
If you're not afraid and you also have intentions towards me
Then we can collude and act in concert
If you are a very pure person
You don't want too much of this kind of thing
Then I naturally will demote you
But there are some hypocritical people
Not at all
Let me tell you about aesthetics
Let's discuss art
So the distinction between truth and falsehood is usually like this
But falsehood often exists in the world in the form of truth
And true people often use falsehood
Using good and evil to represent themselves
To proclaim themselves
Because we are still far from the true path of sainthood in our hearts
So I don't consider myself a perfect person
But I pursue the true path
I pursue true beauty
True goodness
But I am still far from those truly pure and good people
But what do we call this
We call this chaotic good
Ha, we are not neutral good
Nor are we lawful good
We are chaotic good
People are different from each other
So in the yin and yang of life, everyone should understand
This is what is necessary to survive in Chinese society