I'm trying to get everything done before the strong winds arrive.
Now, the strong winds have already reached Zhangjiakou.
They are expected to hit Beijing around seven o'clock.
I shouldn't have to take care of the kids this week,
since they don't need to come over.
I think it should be a level 12 wind.
I'm really, really excited.
Beijing residents have already started on their social media circles,
awaiting this big wind.
I have plenty of food at home.
Batteries and water, no worries.
I've been working on a grand narrative these past couple of days.
The blogger has been talking about the trade war recently.
Actually, everyone has been following the trade war.
A lot of people are doing it
The traffic is really good
With tens of thousands
Even over a hundred thousand
And some have over a million
But most people are just quoting authorities
Or telling stories and such
Without getting into specific details
So I'll just focus on two points
Firstly, we are definitely going to win this trade war.
We will definitely win.
No need to worry too much.
Secondly, why will the U.S. lose?
It's quite simple.
I'll try to keep it as simple as possible.
Because the U.S. has two major cognitive errors.
One is that their imports are high,
and their exports are low.
It's a trade deficit.
So we're more anxious about it.
This is the first point.
Secondly,
It's Old Cuan's view that this tariff
it's China that's paying this tariff.
First, let's be clear and straightforward.
The faster I explain this, the better.
Because, first and foremost, it's the importer on the other side who pays.
So why does China export so much?
Actually, a lot of the time, American manufacturers
need China for production, packaging, or mold making
or to produce certain items
they need China to handle these tasks
but the final products are still made in the U.S.
For example, if you want to create a perfume
you might have China manufacture the perfume bottles
or if you want to produce a toy or something similar
You handle the design
and China helps with the production
so that you can ultimately sell for a higher price
or, for example, the cost of his product
is one dollar when sold in China
but now it sells for two dollars
yet its final selling price is sixteen dollars
so in this case
it’s actually the American small and medium-sized enterprises that are taking a hit
industries like manufacturing
and large companies like Apple
places like Tesla
We talked about this issue last time
Secondly, it's the U.S. importers who pay the tariffs on their goods
once they arrive at U.S. ports
and then they are held there
and you have to pay the fees
before they can be released
That's it.
It's about customs clearance.
That's how it is.
So, to explain it,
From our perspective,
There's nothing that absolutely has to be from the U.S.
I had a knife sharpener that featured ONiON from the game.
Later, the ONiON's knife sharpener broke after being used fewer than five or six times.
Later, I bought one.
And then the exact same one
That one is a knockoff, a Chinese OEM product
Because it’s from their contract manufacturer
It’s common for contract manufacturers to pick a new brand and start producing again
So you see a lot of things are like this
The original brand might be gone
Nowadays, what’s being sold might just be from the former contract factories
So what are you afraid of if the factory is still here
It’s just like playing Civilization
You have productive force.
You have the little gear
And the blue shield as well
This thing is really useful
Because the factory here just needs one design
If you completely tear up and disconnect our ties now
Then
We won't have any intellectual property issues
And we can freely replicate the items
We can do whatever we want
Your product design drawings
All the raw materials are here
Right?
I
And the most important thing is
It doesn't matter if you have trade barriers with me
We can export to Canada
Or to Mexico
Right?
You could smuggle or resell to Mexico and Canada.
Just like you import gasoline into Russia.
Like oil and natural gas.
It’s just a matter of middlemen.
India, the largest country in the East.
He’s raking in the profits, right?
It just means more middlemen.
So, one of the most profitable jobs now might be going to Mexico.
Selling products to the U.S.
So that's how it is.
He didn't figure it out.
Not Chinese, though.
The 16 dollars I sell to the U.S. isn't mine.
I make that one dollar.
Now, to put it this way,
I still make that one dollar.
It's just that the additional cost of one dollar is on you.
Then you earn 16-15 from what you made before 16
which turns into 15-14
meaning the extra money from the reduced tariff
is actually one hundred percent from China
the export cost here has increased by 104%
around 125
it doesn’t matter
isn’t it already one and a quarter?
it’s all good
This small amount of money really doesn’t matter.
It’s just that you don’t have the capability to produce it.
You still have to buy Chinese-made products.
Moreover, when comparing Chinese-made products to American-made ones,
the service,
the quality,
various aspects,
the difference isn’t just tenfold,
it’s more like twentyfold.
So, if you're off by 20 times,
you might set the tariff to 3000% or 5000%,
which would be better.
But if you do that,
there would be too many smugglers.
People would flood in from Canada and Mexico,
and the Chinese communities in Canada and Mexico would thrive.
So, the best strategy now,
is to immigrate to Canada as soon as possible.
Sell things to the United States
Or hurry up and go to Mexico
Mexico should be visa-free or something, right?
Or has that been paused recently?
Anyway, for going to Canada or Mexico, you use this NEFA
To deal with it
It’s like when there’s a trade barrier between China and the U.S.
And if there’s a free trade zone between China, Japan, and South Korea
There will definitely be a demand from Chinese people
You can sell American products from Japan and South Korea to China.
Just slap on a Japanese or Korean label, and it’s done.
But the most important thing is,
the demand for American products in China isn’t high.
Watching some pirated movies at night is enough.
Right?
You're not going to the cinema to watch The Avengers
I just watch it online, and it’s done.
What about Steam? Isn’t that the case for Steam as well?
So, does that mean pirated games can't be played?
Right?
He can't completely do that, right?
And I'm not in the China region on Steam anymore.
I've taken my Steam account abroad.
Right?
It doesn't really affect you, does it?
Actually, it doesn't really have much of an impact.
The price of the iPhone hasn't gone up.
Because the demand in the domestic market remains unchanged.
And that demand is real and present.
It's not entirely about the end consumer.
A fivefold trade deficit.
No, that's not the case.
It's not the end consumer.
Many are manufacturers.
We provide raw materials.
We're not the providers of finished products.
We're the partners in raw materials or intermediate stages.
So ultimately, it impacts and harms American industry and commerce.
It's that simple.
It affects American industry and commerce.
China is the supply chain.
Supply chain.
It's that straightforward.
So they think China sells only products.
Have you managed to get Chinese cars running on American roads?
Did you get a Chinese-made computer to run in America?
Do you want Chinese-manufactured weapons
Did small arms go on the run in America?
No, right?
There have always been bans.
There used to be.
But not anymore.
The honeymoon period is over, right?
The honeymoon period of the 80s is over.
There's been no more selling of dog weapons or anything like that.
He didn't figure it out.
So many people, you know,
Especially a lot of people who are quite Americanized,
They just say,
Trump has great wisdom.
His team are all professional economists.
Aren't they more knowledgeable than you?
So, who is VR?
You get it too, huh?
Hehe
So, in many cases,
Old Cui seems to be unclear about tariffs,
thinking that tariffs aren't that straightforward,
believing that it's the foreign government paying the bill,
the Chinese sell finished products,
and Americans also sell finished goods,
but it's not that simple,
in many cases,
we might need American cooperation in certain areas,
but to be honest,
there aren't many areas where we need their cooperation,
the U.S. needs more cooperation from China,
because Chinese products are affordable and of good quality,
and they ship very quickly,
without any unnecessary hassle,
many American manufacturers,
they also need to collaborate with others,
for producing packaging materials,
producing various products,
they have a design,
they have an idea,
and they realize it in China,
so the ones getting hurt are their own industrial and business owners,
so once this is understood, it's all clear,
so we will definitely win this trade war,
because the ones losing are them.