So, why are wealthy people wealthy?
It's not just because they have money.
That's what makes them wealthy.
Rather, their awareness and thought patterns
Their methodologies and approaches differ from those of the poor.
His ability to accumulate such wealth
is closely tied to the choices he made.
It's not just the act of starting a business
that made him wealthy.
That's not the case.
From any perspective,
this endeavor
starting a business
and venturing into new enterprises are incredibly challenging.
But for different people,
the strategies vary.
So you often hear people say,
in this day and age, teaching people to start businesses,
is just shameless.
The failure rate of startups is 99%.
Listen to this sentence,
people who talk like this are usually poor themselves.
The life of the poor is always driven by fear.
You can't afford not to study.
If you don't study, you won't find a job when you grow up.
You can't be without a job.
No job,
and you'll end up on the streets.
You can't avoid getting married.
When you're old, no one will take care of you.
If you get married, you'll have someone to look after you when you're old.
With a job, you won't get fired.
Right?
Now, as a parent,
you've put down a down payment for your child,
and you think they won't be fired for 30 years?
Do you really think the economy will be that smooth for 30 years?
Right?
Once you sign a mortgage, it's a 30-year commitment,
20 years of debt, that's a long time.
That's why children from poor families learn to be responsible early on.
Just because the parents are too
Parents
So he is driven by a sense of fear, generation after generation
To do certain things
But for wealthy families
The most important thing is that parents will have your back
So they allow you to take risks
And actually, there is a difference between the poor and the rich in one aspect
When it comes to entrepreneurship
Some people say, why would the rich even bother to start a business?
Most children of the wealthy, when they're young,
tend to do something on their own,
pursuing what they really want to do.
Then, as they get older,
if they're not up to it,
they take over the family business.
Actually, in wealthy families,
they don’t really want their children to build their own careers.
I hope he takes over directly.
But the child may not have the talent or interest for it.
So for most people,
fathers don’t necessarily pass their business to their sons,
and often,
sons don’t carry on their fathers’ businesses.
They don’t necessarily follow in the same footsteps.
But typically, they allow you to make a few mistakes.
Speaking of the rich second generation around me,
The success rate of starting your own business is, realistically, about half.
Almost half can succeed.
That means around 40%.
About 42%, to be more precise.
But the majority of the rest don't succeed.
The reason they don't succeed
is that they don't have the right mentality.
In terms of their thinking,
they are more focused on enjoyment.
rather than building a career
he tends to oversimplify things
and the poor are prone to over-simplification as well
he fails to see the dangers
he tends to idealize matters
all the poor friends around me who start businesses
without exception
mostly end up opening stores
like bubble tea shops
Opening a coffee shop
Opening a flower shop
We ended up doing the very things we’re worst at
Including getting into the food and beverage industry
I’ve said it countless times
Stay away from the food and beverage industry
We don’t have the skills for that
Absolutely don’t do it
But everyone still wants to open a store
For example, he opened a milk tea shop
a beverage store
The children of the wealthy don't follow this pattern at all
When he did it for the first time
he definitely tried it out on a small scale first
I have a wealthy friend
his family is in the wood furniture business
he set up a water purifier himself
for this purpose
Is this a small-scale cost experiment?
No, it's not.
I told him
you're not familiar with this thing
and as the company's representative
to be honest
it's a minor requirement
and you're less likely to succeed
Sure enough, it failed after two or three years
Later, he said he wanted to open a store.
I said, 'Oh no.',
This guy is probably going to lose money again.
Then he said before opening the store,
He would try setting up a stall first.
I said, 'Your location is great.',
Because he mentioned setting up a stall,
It can directly test the actual sales in each neighborhood.
To see if the demand is real or not.
If you open a store
let's say a lemonade stand
we're talking about lemon juice
when you sell this product
you start with a small stall
if the stall runs really well
you can expand it into a store
so as I often tell everyone
before you do something, try it on a small scale first
Let's start by becoming a sole trader.
A sole trader first becomes self-employed.
What type of self-employed immigration?
What does it mean to be self-employed?
You should first take care of yourself.
Start as a small sole trader.
Start by setting up a stall.
Many people take things out of context.
Saying that you're just asking them to set up stalls.
You're making a graduate student set up a stall
They should be preparing for their postgraduate exams
People who are preparing for the civil service exams
You're making them set up a stall
You have ill intentions
You don't need to say anything about him
These people aren't my audience either.
I don't really care
It's your choice to take the civil service exam
27%
with a probability of just over 10%
that would be a great honor to the family
right?
getting a salary of 358,000 would be quite nice and satisfying
isn't it?
could you live that kind of life?
don't ask me, without you
I'm not your dad
I can't possibly persuade you to live that way
Is it the life I want to live?
And then I lead you down my path
You don’t have to follow in my footsteps
You don't have to listen to me.
No worries
But what are these rules?
Hurun Report mentioned online
Families with assets exceeding 100 million
Not many are professional managers
Most, about 80%, are business owners
The rest are into property speculation
or stock trading
Can you get insider information
for property or stock speculation?
Are you buying a house
You're not into property speculation
Are you trading stocks?
You got played in the stock market
80% of all businesses are run as companies
But some people say
This is the probability of the fittest surviving
Right
But why do business owners stay in the game
It's because starting a business
Whether in China or in America
You'll find it's more about entrepreneurship than stocks
Stocks can at most be like Pelosi,
a few years,
using leverage and all sorts of insider trading to multiply tenfold,
that's the most impressive part,
multiplying tenfold,
if you say you turned 100,000 into 1 million,
that's already the most impressive state,
but with startups, your salary and valuation,
can reach tens of billions.
It turned around in no time.
Even if you start a small business,
selling tens of millions is quite common.
Starting from zero,
from scratch,
Often, it’s not about teaching people how to start a business,
because entrepreneurship can’t really be taught,
it’s just a piece of advice,
and as you fill in the gaps in these areas,
You'll find that many of these startup-related books
are written by Americans.
Americans have written a lot about business.
Including Carnegie's works,
and the Wealth of Nations.
Actually, what I recommend to everyone is a kind of American approach.
Now, it has become a widely accepted business philosophy.
Because their society is a hundred percent
a market economy.
We are actually part of a market economy
It's just that in many cases
All these things work this way
This is indeed a component of the economic structure
Private and corporate sectors have started to develop
You need to understand that the development of state-owned enterprises has nothing to do with you
It has nothing to do with you
It's not your personal property
It's something enjoyed by the state
It belongs to everyone.
It has nothing to do with you.
If you want to strive personally,
want to move up,
you say you want to take the civil service exam,
then take the technical exam.
You'll just be a cog in the machine.
Then you'll just be a cog in the machine.
You won't be anything else.
You're here to serve others.
You're not in a position to control everything.
If you want to be free and easy.
If you want to control everything yourself.
Then starting a business is definitely the way to go.
Because you don't have a family business to inherit, right?
Right?
That's why the biggest difference between the rich and the poor is...
the issue of testing and learning from small-scale costs.
No matter what
You see many people blindly jump in
Frequently, those who come to me for consultation
Some people are not cut out for entrepreneurship
I would tell them straightforwardly
I have a buddy
A few of us partners
Take on a project
I have a channel
Then this thing started making money
Hey buddy
Calm down, calm down
Do you know anything about these things
Corporate law
Do you know about tax laws and such
Ah
What kind of liability does a limited liability company have
How are different taxes calculated
Do you know about this?
If you don't know about it,
how do you calculate the cost?
Not calculating the cost,
how do you know how much money you need?
How much funding do you need?
Once you have this money,
how many people do you need to hire?
How long can it sustain you?
You have no idea at all.
You never calculate the costs.
How could you possibly succeed in the end?
It's impossible.
Right?
There's no way you can.
Oh dear.
Our buddy can get things done just like that.
Others can make it work just fine.
That doesn’t sound like something a wealthy person would say.
So when you talk about it, it’s about the things inside you, your inner thoughts.
Once your knowledge and awareness reach a certain level,
you can achieve something, and then you’ll succeed.
It’s really about accomplishing something.
It’s about getting one thing done.
If you have a master’s degree or higher education,
you tend to have a very strong need to excel.
You fear failure.
You're afraid of making mistakes
which stops you from taking the first step
Of course, blindly taking the first step isn't right either
but rather those who
at thirteen or fourteen
fifteen or sixteen, start entering the market
Those folks are sharp as a tack
Serial entrepreneurs are usually these people
They're not doing it for the first time
I might have failed at something I did before.
Now it's probably the second or third time.
If you haven't started your first business by the age of 42,
you're unlikely to do it in your lifetime.
So you see, I've been talking a lot,
but I've never actually told you anything specific.
I haven't gone over the steps you should take for starting a business,
nor have I given you any specific advice on that.
I haven't explained how this should be handled either.
Or encourage you to do it
Then I'll start a startup boot camp
Never
I'm just telling you
This is something you should do in your lifetime
There's nothing else besides that
Someone told me
The startup mentor said I'm down
Am I down
I poured it right in front of you.
I even poured it while looking at your mom's photo.
How did I pour it?
I didn't pour it at all.
I never mentioned this to you.
Starting from 123456, how should we proceed?
Right?
I didn't go through each step with you.
How do we register at the bank?
How do you go to the bank to open a corporate account?
How do you register at the business administration office?
Did I mention that?
What's the tax law like?
No.
If you need knowledge in this area,
There are various dedicated UPloaders
I can provide you with experience in this field.
They are UPloaders in the startup zone.
What you truly need is something else
What you truly need is knowledge
a mindset
a way of thinking
more specifically, a pattern of thought
This pattern of thought involves being bold enough to take risks
to experiment and make mistakes on a small scale
The money you receive isn't meant for paying your employees' salaries
This money is given to you personally.
The agency uses it to ensure you can survive.
It’s for buying necessities.
It’s not for the rent of a new company.
Let’s repeat that.
Now, these smaller, more specialized agencies.
You should really read both of these books.
Especially in the AI era now.
In this high-demand environment.
Within the scope of growth that relies on the internet,
when it comes to many things,
the products and services an individual can provide,
can be connected with the majority of people.
So, how should you create something
that everyone needs in terms of services?
Why create a product that everyone needs?
It's that simple.
Actually, it's not about the company structure.
It's not a management issue
It's not about how many people you task.
A lot can be achieved through early outsourcing
Learning and drawing from others' experiences
Actually, a lot of things do require spending money
The areas where you really need to spend money
Look at so many people
I don't even want to comment on these things anymore
Just look at all those who failed in their startups
Without exception, they spent most of their money on renovating new stores.
They all share this trait.
They love buying houses.
And once they buy a house, they renovate it.
Then they rent some kind of store.
Or an office.
And they spend a considerable amount on renovation as well.
This is the behavior I despise the most.
What does renovation really bring anyway?
I'm asking you about the relationship between your renovation costs and your actual revenue.
What does the actual cost of renovation have to do with your revenue?
Can't you live in a simply renovated place?
Can't you buy a second-hand house?
Can't you rent a place that's already furnished?
Why do you have to renovate?
How much money do you have?
Do you really need to renovate your home?
Some people say
Look at Rong Zhen's house; the decoration isn't great.
Why should I spend so much money on decoration?
Can't he live there?
Is it polluted?
Do I have guests over every day?
I insist on decorating.
This decoration has to have a focal point.
Are you telling me you do interior design?'
Why is it necessary to renovate?
Look, you don't have this issue.
What's the core issue here?
If I open a store,
I need to renovate first.
If you're opening a billiard hall,
if it's an internet cafe,
or a nightclub,
or a massage parlor.
A large massage parlor
or something like a spa or water therapy
a one-stop shop for eating and drinking
you should pretend a bit
Northerners care a lot about face
face is really important
but in most cases
your office is a mess, like a pigsty
why would you want to renovate it
Why do you insist on renovating?
Have you ever thought about this?
It's about your mentality.
Why do you feel the need to renovate in your mind?
Haven't you considered this?
For the sake of appearances.
Your place is always hosting guests.
Are you the one hosting guests or is it your mom?
Have you thought about this?
Why is it that your home must welcome guests?
Many people still keep a guest room in their homes.
Is anyone actually living there?
Have you ever thought about why, when you start a new company,
the most crucial costs are spent on the decoration?
Even if it's a rented place,
There are also many UPloaders who are
I'll start with a small villa,
I'll get it renovated first.
Let's start by spending a year
or two years
investing a few million
Oh
You make money so easily
You're just like Brother Daxiang
It's not easy to earn some money
To make a large sum of money all at once
and then spend 1.2 million on a 1.19 million car
You're really acting like a small-minded person who got a bit of wealth and is showing off.
Why do you have to renovate?
What's the purpose of your renovation?
I don't mean to oppose any UPloader who adds decoration or renovation content.
Many people, when making their VLOGs, do things like this:
I set up a room or something like that.
I transformed it into something I really like.
I turned it into a cozy little courtyard that I love.
I did this and that.
How much did it cost?
This little courtyard is so cozy.
But when you're broke,
why don’t you buy the Xiaomi Su 7 Extra Ultra?
What’s the point of your renovation?
Do you know that renovation isn’t about having a million dollars
and spending just three or five thousand to fix it up?
Renovation means if you have a million dollars, you spend three or fifty thousand,
or seven or eighty thousand.
If it's a villa you're renovating
A problem that over a million can't solve
Do you have any revenue that can help you come up with a million?
Two million?
In a year?
Are you the one who made ten million that year?
You're spending a million on renovation right now
This kind of luxurious and competitive spending
Is the most crucial reason for your business failure
How much can you eat, anyway?
Let me tell you.
The most common reason for startup failure is low profit margin.
One reason is having too many employees.
Another is choosing a location that's too large.
Spending too much on renovations is also a big issue.
These are the main two reasons.
It's tough being a solo entrepreneur.
Being the only boss.
Where did you register your company?
Has the business administration forced you to hire employees?
Can you hire temporary workers?
Can you use interns?
Can you get friends or family to help for free?
Can you hire fewer people?
Just hire one or two people?
Can it work this way?
Tell me.
Tell me
Why
Baby, why
Is it often like this when you answer me?
So why do you have to renovate?
I can understand you renovating the store
But why do you want to renovate the office?
Many people don’t get it
Is he into home renovation or something?
This UPloader has a particular fondness for home renovation.
Is home renovation something a poor person should do?
You are a poor person.
You have to admit that.
Otherwise, why would you be working so hard?
But when your business isn’t taking off,
Why would you spend money on decoration first?
I’ve been complaining about the renovation for so long.
But I really don't understand
all those who failed in their startups
without exception, they spent tens of thousands on renovations
after spending tens of thousands on this store, it still didn’t work out
the fire department said it wasn’t up to code
so they had to make adjustments
and then spent another tens of thousands
and then the startup failed again
isn’t that you?
Is it the environment that's the problem?
This is clearly your fault, isn't it?
Your little, poor, tiny brain
is filled with too much useless knowledge.
What does interior design have to do with entrepreneurship?
Real entrepreneurship is something you can start in a garage,
in a basement,
or even in a rural house.
It's about setting up your framework.
Get your circular economy going
instead of just renovating
So let me tell you
for the poor
I haven't complained about renovation before
but to be honest
most of it is about keeping up appearances
so he buys a car
after buying a house, how can it just be about the house?
I actually didn't say that
I didn't mention that point
Many people buy a house and
it's not just about buying a house
the car cost over 100,000
like a G-Class or something
and I plan to get a better car in the future
a better car
spending over a million on the street
You have over a million on the street
Then in a couple of days, it depreciates
It drops to a few hundred thousand
It becomes a few tens of thousands, right?
Is that how it works?
Then the car dealers are happy
The used car dealers are buying your car, right?
And the second-hand coffee machine dealers are buying your coffee machine, right?
They specialize in official stores
That's the full-service funeral arrangement, right?
This renovation must have cost you a pretty penny, didn't it?
Next time, open a different kind of store.
They would have to redo the renovation, wouldn't they?
Isn't all your money going to the renovators?
Hmm, why do you need to renovate anyway?
Have you thought about it?
So, the difference between the poor and the rich is often that
Many times, the poor start by opening a store.
The wealthy start by setting up stalls
It's really just like that
Because you get familiar with these processes
Often, you'll find that many things aren't necessary
You don't need so many employees
You don't need such a large office space
With the shared workspace
You don't need so many people dressed in formal suits
And the coffee machine is set up, among other things
These things have nothing to do with your company's profitability.
Your company can operate entirely from home.
No problem.
Tasks can be coordinated through the internet.
As a result, you don't have to hire employees.
Then let AI handle everything.
Hire fewer people.
Rent less space.
Do less renovation.
This is the best advice for starting a business.
Let me tell you.
Many people fail and don't even know where they went wrong.
It's not in those areas.
There are real questions about management.
What kind of issues?
After opening the store, they might only make three to five thousand.
They can only earn three to five thousand.
If you're doing it alone
That three to five thousand should be enough for you to live on.
When they first started the shop, they might have only made ten or twenty thousand.
You might not be able to work from home.
If you can work from home,
work from home,
if it really doesn’t work out, then you’ll have to produce something.
if you can do it yourself,
if you can have AI do it,
don’t hire employees to do it.
That's how simple it is.
You just hired an operator.
The amount of money the employees earn
is not commensurate with the service provided by the products they offer.
Many things are like this.
And a lot of things don't require you to renovate your store.
So you see, what I'm telling you is
the only advice I can give you is 238.
In the video, if you're doing blind massage,
you don't need to renovate the store either.
Just paint the walls.
Just lay some flooring tiles.
No need to overdo the renovation.
Or make it overly fancy.
It will cost you a lot of money.
And you haven't even started making money yet.
Why spend money first?
This is the problem of the poor
They haven't earned any money yet,
but they want to spend money first.
Once they get funding,
or borrow money,
or take out a loan,
they think, 'Oh, I have money now,'
I'm a rich person now.
I have a million in my account.
I'll spend 300,000 on renovation.
So let me tell you,
the point of failure in entrepreneurship
is not necessarily that you failed in management or anything like that.
A lot of it is due to wasteful spending.
That's how it happens.
So let me explain,
the difference between the rich and the poor is significant.
Rich people are very, very careful with their spending,
very, very frugal.
So at the beginning, they only set up a stall,
only do very simple small things.
It's the poor who will spend a lot of money on
useless things.
Buy a new set of clothes first,
renovate first,
buy a car for show first,
have to have the appearance,
without the substance,
nothing at all.
This is the biggest difference between the poor and the rich,
the difference in mindset,
the difference in spending speed.
Poor people are very willing to spend money,
but rich people aren't rich people
who save every penny.
Of course, there are some expenses that shouldn't be saved,
they won't save or impact production and income.
If it should be saved,
they won't save it.
But not for the poor,
who will spend several times more for the sake of appearances.
That's why they fail.
Because they think starting a business is a matter of having face,
fail once,
and then retreat again,
get through it,
rely on parents to cover the losses,
This is the case for most people,
especially in the Beijing area,
the actual situation of entrepreneurs.
Learn from these lessons,
it's never too late to mend.