Actually, there is a basic principle to being a good person.
And that principle is not to be too nice.
Why shouldn't you be too nice?
Let me explain it to you in detail.
First, let's talk about this.
The term 'good person' is used with quotation marks.
Being a good person doesn't mean you have to do good deeds all the time.
It's not about not being a kind person,
but rather, you shouldn't be too easy to please.
Someone who is overly generous and kind,
and very approachable.
Recently, a few younger guys,
got thoroughly scolded by my four consecutive posts on social media today.
Actually, they are all my loyal fans.
They are all pretty great.
After the young guy added me on WeChat,
he was really happy.
He’s willing to share anything with me.
Then I quickly went off on a rant in my Moments.
Why is that?
Let me tell you,
First off, I have around 17,000 WeChat friends.
Every day, countless people ask me all sorts of questions.
So when I'm consulting,
I set a threshold,
you pay,
and you can ask me some questions.
If you don't pay,
I won't even bother to respond.
Why do I have to do it this way?
Then they mention Brother Rong
Are you short on money?
You're referring to that, right?
It's about being short on money.
But this is also a strategic issue.
Why can't you be equally kind to everyone?
Why can't you be generous to everyone?
It's because humans are very complex creatures.
It's not that you're good to others,
that they will definitely be good to you.
Or most of the time, when you're good to others,
they will be grateful to you.
But they won't do anything
that actually benefits you.
Over time,
your kindness
will be perceived as cheap.
So in this sense,
you'll end up feeling very drained.
If I were to attend to everyone
everyone would get involved in their personal karmic cycle
offering all sorts of advice
without charging a fee
then I would be exposed to these situations
and be weighed down by these people's karmic issues every day
the more advice I give
the more I get involved in their relationships
the more I get entangled in their lives
My final personal fate and fortune
various daily routines would be significantly disrupted
so when some people start asking me all sorts of questions
I give them a stern warning
don't really treat me like a godfather
you need to understand that we are two equal individuals
if you like what I do
then please be an independent and self-reliant person
this is a crucial matter
I have a friend recently
who is a PhD from a certain university
a PhD in psychology
and he also works as a mediator
but in this role
he worked as a counselor for about a month
and then he quit
because he is a typical example among my friends
of someone with a people-pleasing personality
Why would someone with a people-pleasing personality study psychology?
They themselves have a bit of a need in this area.
They might feel somewhat abnormal in certain aspects.
But many kind children
hope for a world filled with fairness,
filled with love,
and filled with all sorts of harmonious things.
I also hope the world is full of love.
Otherwise, some of my actions would be hard to explain.
But you still need to live strategically to make this world full of love.
You still need to live strategically.
If you can't live strategically,
without thinking,
without some strategic goals,
you'll end up being weighed down by the values of being a good person.
For many people in making friends,
in pursuing a career,
in being a person,
Often in a state of being exploited
being used
being controlled
So sometimes being a pushover doesn’t work
That is to say, any of your actions
any of your acts of helping others shouldn’t be devalued
There must be equivalent benefits in exchange
You can help others
But when you help others
If you don't ask for a penny
people might not really appreciate it
nor would they really do anything about it
perhaps half of them would be grateful
and your relationship with them would gradually improve
but consider this person
who takes up so much of your social space
what kind of real connection would you have with them
it would just waste your time
So, whether from the perspective of time dilution,
or from the aspect of benefit exchange,
you can't help others for free.
No matter what,
even if you charge someone 20 yuan, you should still do it.
This is a fundamental issue of values.
That is to say, in our daily lives,
all your interactions with others,
should not devalue your actions.
If you're helping others out of various obligations,
or out of kindness,
when you assist someone,
whether you're helping a woman,
or a man,
basically helping someone of the opposite sex,
or even helping your parents,
or anyone in need,
remember the help you offer
First, it shouldn't be cheap
It shouldn't be free
It shouldn't be voluntary on your part
As long as the other party proposes it
The other party needs you
They genuinely need you
And they are unwilling to spend money on something like this
This is the right approach
Because if the other party thinks your actions aren't worth spending money on
That just shows your actions are cheap
or that he's quite stingy
so this matter isn't worth your help
Of course, when it comes to making friends, it shouldn't be about such tactics
Speaking of making friends
it starts with mutual gestures of goodwill, a form of reciprocal benefit
but you'll find that many people in this world make friends
solely for the purpose of exchanging benefits
seeing them as mere tools for their own gain
But how does he put it?
From his perspective,
you are merely a tool to be used.
You are just a resource manager, someone who controls resources.
So, in this world,
in our human society, most of the time,
you can maintain a childlike heart.
But let me tell you,
a childlike heart is only for children.
And it's particularly young children.
By the time the child is eight or nine years old,
At eleven or twelve years old,
Thirteen or fourteen years old,
They start to develop a sense of social awareness.
You can be a bit nicer to those who are genuinely good.
But if you are overly nice to those who are genuinely good,
Without any protective shell against social threats,
They will also be in trouble.
So a truly good person should have pure intentions
with decisive actions
fierce as an angry Vajra
compassionate like a Bodhisattva
both qualities are essential
if you only have the compassion of a Bodhisattva
then to outsiders
many would see you as someone they can easily manipulate
to put it bluntly
Just a casual object
Guys can be casually exploited for gold coins
What kind of girls can be casually taken advantage of
Just a casual object
An object that can be casually ordered around
You're pretty nice to people
But whether you're nice to people
Depends on your youth
Your family during your teenage years
Regarding your education
How you should face society
Being kind to others and such
But remember
To protect the goodness in your heart
Your shell needs to be tough
Like a hedgehog
A tough exterior
And a soft interior is enough
when doing good deeds
for those who truly have no ability to defend themselves
when performing genuinely good actions
you can go ahead and do it
but when it comes to helping an elderly lady
or an elderly man
you need to understand strategically
because these people may not necessarily be worthy of your help
Some people might turn the tables on you
Often, that's how it goes
When you face the world with a kind heart
The world can be full of malice
But good and bad are equally present
Treat good people better and better
Treat bad people worse and worse
Otherwise, you'll just be seen as a resource by others
A herbivore
Do you understand?
So I'm teaching you
this set of principles and behaviors for life
most importantly
to understand what the core of Machiavellianism is
it's not egoism
but rather strategically dealing with all kinds of treacherous situations in the world
the intelligence in politics, the military conflicts
and the power struggles
All of these require your strategic thinking.
When you need to deceive, do it.
When you need to bluff, go for it.
If you need to play a trick, then play it.
Because that's how it is between nations.
However, Machiavellianism is more often used in political arenas.
Business battles are not fought in personal relationships.
In personal relationships,
if you always treat everything as a trade-off,
You can't get true friends
Sometimes, in a friendship
You need to receive some genuine responses
But let me tell you
Making friends also requires a strategic approach
If the other person has no resources
If the other person is just an ordinary individual
Then you have to see how things develop
If it’s a couple of years
Within 45 years, a very remarkable person grew up.
He might not even repay you.
So instead of that,
it's better to directly befriend someone who already has resources.
That's how people often are.
If you say it's completely about no interests,
it's impossible when it comes to exchanges.
Otherwise, when someone gets old, they will have
people frequently coming to visit them.
But when it comes to a lifetime
are you living for your friends?
or for your career?
or for love?
You need to make your own choices.
Because you only have so much to give.
If your efforts are scattered,
they become cheapened.
And you should trust the people around me.
Especially female influencers
Especially those who are good at making friends
They have quite a few friends
If you try to pursue a female influencer
It's different from pursuing someone who has many friends
It's really hard to get close to someone who boasts about having many friends
That's incredibly difficult
I particularly dislike people with too many friends
I have a lot of friends too
But I don’t really get along well with anyone.
That’s just the kind of relationship I have.
When I need someone’s help,
I’ll quickly warm up to them.
But when I no longer need that person,
I will definitely cut ties with them.
Because I believe that, to me,
everyone is a burden and a hindrance.
Except for family, of course.
Even loved ones can be foolish at times
And their foolishness can affect me too
So I often tend to be very cautious and introspective
For historically, solitary rulers have always been like this
As an ENTJ
As someone with a strong and commanding personality
You have to accept this loneliness
Because you look down on ordinary people
You find it hard to tolerate ordinary people
Intolerable
You'll find it incredibly annoying
So this world offers you a unique perspective
It gives you a more personal touch with the pen
It almost feels like an NPD
Right?
But we don't leech off others' hard work
We keep our distance
Maintaining a certain distance from everyone
To prevent others' foolishness from hurting us
But more often, it also presents a cold front to others
Because your time is precious
I've added so many friends
If I added all 660,000 of my
669,000 followers on WeChat
I wouldn't have any time for myself every day
So many times, you have to be tough
Making choices is the first principle of being a person
And more often than not
If you're not tough enough
Your actions
Your career will suffer
So have you given a lot of your time to
The wrong people
Have you invested a lot of your youth in
People who don't deserve such dedication?
Have you been giving too much?
By giving so much to others
You have less time for yourself
Less time to develop your career
Less time to cultivate your true abilities
So don't be love-struck
Don't be overly kind and helpful
There needs to be a limit