I'm talking to you, the so-called middle-class parents
Are you trying to elevate your social status through your kids?
Now there are even two-year-olds on the ski slopes on Xiaohongshu
Where are the skis?
You know about skiing, right?
In Western countries,
it's a trendy activity,
but the fatality and injury rates are quite high.
Actually, I suggest you consider,
letting your child practice stunt motorcycling.
The fatality rate for stunt motorcycling
is lower than that of skiing.
The risk in skiing isn't about whether you can do it or not,
it can happen suddenly.
You, like me, a 170-pound adult,
could send your 30-pound child flying,
and there's a high chance they might end up permanently disabled,
or even in a vegetative state.
You middle-aged moms facing a midlife crisis,
can you please
just not use your children as tools for social mobility?
If you're experiencing a midlife crisis,
consider having an affair,
it might actually be a good thing.
This is quite good.
Then you can dream about meeting a domineering CEO.
And have the domineering CEO duel with your husband.
Don't think of using your young child for that.
Especially children under 18.
If it's not their own wish.
Don't take them to the ski resort.
Whether it's the beginner slopes.
Intermediate to advanced slopes.
Because of those instructors.
Those people at the ski resorts
Those refined ones, how do I put it
The refined elites on Xiaohongshu
They won't tell you the truth
They won't foot the medical bills for your child
So many people around me
Who have been disabled
Who have lost money
Who have been severely injured
Are all here
But you keep on
You should take responsibility for your 120 pounds
Or your 160 pounds
It doesn’t matter
If you die, so be it
Your lives don’t seem to have much value, right
But please don’t let the flowers of our country
The future ones who could potentially bring more social value
These young people
Those post-2010s, don’t take them to their deaths, okay
Especially after 2020
Don't do that
Don't do such despicable things
This is murder
Are you really that clueless
You guys are clueless
If you die, so be it
It's not a pity
But don't let the kids suffer
Ok