I suddenly had a feeling,
It's something I wanted to share with all of you.
Quite often, I give likes to some people
whom I really like
but they don't return the favor
However, I post on my Moments every day
and there are always some regular followers who like my posts
Sometimes I go back and like theirs too
Why does this happen?
What does this situation actually mean?
Often, we say when someone gives you a like
This value is different.
If it's someone you like,
who gives you a like,
you'd be particularly happy.
If it's someone you admire,
someone you really care about,
and they give you a like,
it means they're really pleased.
But for everyone,
Let's start with this
Everyone has a different value in others' hearts
I have many friends
I keep giving him likes every day
but he might have blocked me long ago
or never checks my feed
or it could be that among his friends
I only make up a tiny fraction
just like you are in my circle of friends
I have about 5 per thousand left.
But now all three of my accounts are full.
So it might be 15 per thousand.
So I might not even know you.
I don’t know you exist.
This is also a result of Brother Rong’s mistake.
A really big mistake.
So the people who can see my Moments now,
are those who added my main account.
But I do have an assistant now, don't I?
My assistant will later post all my Moments
to my secondary account.
This way, I can manage everything myself.
But they say I cry every day,
posting so many Moments,
like a pyramid scheme marketer.
That's not a big deal.
The most important thing is not to take it too seriously.
Whether others will praise you is a matter of perspective.
This means it's a mindset issue.
We often say,
If your love,
Your efforts are all aimed at getting something in return,
This can put you in a vulnerable position.
Because often, giving and loving don't always yield returns.
But I'm not suggesting that
You should give endlessly without bounds.
As a provider
That's not what I mean
Your love and effort should be randomly directed at some people
Why am I telling you this
This random chance is not worth someone who doesn’t deserve your affection
No matter how good you are to them, it’s useless
Especially people like the UPloaders I know
Or particularly famous and wealthy individuals
People in power
These people often receive a lot of likes from others
who praise them
no matter what nonsense they post
there will always be someone to praise them
but I'm different
if what I post is really nonsense
people won't pay attention to it
but when they find something reasonable
they will give me likes
So, my goal in posting on social media is to gather positive feedback.
What kind of thing?
What topic?
What really resonates with people?
Then I focus on creating content around those topics.
Also,
It helps me predict the future views of the upload.
But in most cases,
I really have no idea what the outcome will be.
So, let's talk about it.
There are many people you don't need to flatter at all.
And there's no need to predict whether she will favor you.
For example, if you have a crush.
Whatever you post on your social media,
it's all to catch her attention.
If she suddenly gives you a like,
you can be happy for days.
But she did give you a like.
Does that prove your strengths are equal?
Your strengths are still not on par.
The gap in your looks
The gap in financial conditions
The gap in height
And the gap in personalities
Will never be bridged.
So don't try to get a return from others.
If you don't try to get a return from others
False responses from others won't throw you off.
Let's be real, many female streamers
will occasionally give you some perks
or say a word to you
and you'll be over the moon
then you'll coolly shower them with coins
and these female streamers mostly rely on this to survive
so there's no need to restrict yourself just to get such responses
and hold back on what you want to do
And often, I don't care about the returns.
Who are they?
They are people with social resources.
They often won't be interested in your likes.
But if you pay them,
they will serve you.
They will go all out for you.
It's quite normal.
Everyone has their price.
The reason I know these people
is sometimes due to a recommendation
or because I'm aware of some of their insights
which have been helpful to me
So, the purpose of keeping these people in my contacts
is to admire them
and to learn from them
the qualities I lack
and I can't receive such kind of positive feedback from them
This is quite normal.
Because these people receive so much kindness.
So, this gives you two insights.
One is that if you don't worry about whether you get anything in return,
then your true goal should be to learn what you need from each person,
and absorb it for yourself.
Then make it your own.
This is what will truly benefit you.
Secondly, you can respond to these people randomly.
When you reply to these people
We should say
From a pragmatic perspective
People who like you and people you like can both be attractive
People who like you aren't necessarily less attractive than the people you like
So much of the time, this is an unequal dynamic
When you desire something
That you consider crucial
You subconsciously put a filter on her in your mind
You should up the ante
She's my goddess
I really like her
This way, you get a response
You'll be over the moon
But what do you have to give up?
You'll buy gold coins for him
You'll put in a lot of genuine effort
However, when it comes to this
You won't get the corresponding return
due to the gap between you
the positional difference
the disparity in strength still exists
so there's no need to pay a price
just to get a response from others
but when you do respond to others
it can make them overjoyed
this is the disparity in status between the two of you
The existence of potential energy
When high potential energy moves towards lower potential energy
it creates a gradient effect
Water flows downhill, right?
Heavy objects fall downward
So, in all these cases
you should leverage this potential energy to get things done
Don't beg your teachers or mentors
or those who are more accomplished than you
I can give you a normal, reciprocal response
because the relationship between you is inherently unequal
so don't aim for equality
because once the other party pretends to be equal with you
they definitely have an ulterior motive
or want to take advantage of you
that’s when they would do it
so pursuing this feeling
will instead put you in an unbeatable position
a disadvantageous position
When should you secure an unbeatable position?
It's about how you respond to the people around you, those who like you
A sufficiently kind response is enough
There's no need to fantasize about winning the love of a goddess
But the love of female followers is always within your reach
I'm just joking around
But often, I tell you, the value in human relationships
depends on your own preferences
Because you want to lick whoever you want
admire whoever you want
you may misjudge their value in many ways
my female followers are actually much wealthier than me
much stronger than the so-called goddesses I pursue
and much more attractive
their affection for me is also higher
so often you'll miss out on key opportunities in life
due to your preferences
Many pivotal opportunities in life
can be skewed by your own filters.
Some people might not be beneficial to you,
and they might not be very attractive either.
yet you spend money on them.
You even go to great lengths to spend time on them.
Many people might not be on your radar,
but they quietly follow you.
They are good to you.
But you overlook these people
So sometimes we must break free from our ego
Break free from our own obsessions
Because our obsessions might mislead us
And prevent us from moving towards the most beneficial direction
If you want to maximize your own interests from a pragmatic perspective
To get the best possible outcome
You must have a fair and comprehensive judgment
Who is truly the most useful to you
And who is most useful to you
That's not up to you, understand?
The person you feel is useful to you
is someone you admire
someone you like
but the person who is truly most useful to you right now
you might not even know exists
or you might be aware of their existence
or you might know about these people
in the relationship between the two of you
so you want the random chance to favor you
you want the goddess of fortune to smile upon you
you need to be kind to people around you at random
be nice to this person today
be nice to that person tomorrow
have a chat with this person today
have a chat with that person tomorrow
many times there are a lot of resources
some cards at the bottom
when you're flipping them over
you can't see them
it's the same principle as playing cards
so let me tell you
game theory
everyone should learn
often times
your chances of maximizing your opportunities depend on
It's not about whether you have a specific preference or affection for someone
because your judgment can influence various aspects of your life
People generally tend to favor those they envy
but this favoritism means nothing to others
Your genuine kindness
to those who admire you
your kindness
your goodwill has a multiplier effect on them
so you need to understand this
When your goddess is nice to you
you can be nice back
treat the people you admire well
so you should keep those who love you
and those who admire you, close to your heart
this is the most crucial part
this is also why female streamers can raid others' gold coins
while others can't raid the gold coins of female streamers
it all comes down to this
Because they don’t easily get emotionally involved.
Celebrities are the same.
They receive so much love,
so much attention,
that they can’t experience the feeling of being unnoticed.
If he’s not the center of the stage,
he would feel very uncomfortable.
That’s why many actors tend to stick together.
Generally speaking,
There just aren't as many
Of course, when an actor is surrounded by a group of fans
They feel very happy
That's the difference in human nature
So you should really focus on those who love you
Those who like you
The ones who truly care about you
To gain more resources
Instead of those you see as
You think his resources can be utilized.
So people who are better than you,
You can only learn from them.
Only those who are weaker and chasing after you,
You can gain practical benefits and value from them.
That's a big difference.
So people often mix these two things up.
Let me say it again,
Those who truly like you
Admire you
Love you
Are the ones who truly want to help you
Willing to help you improve yourself
But those you think you admire so much
Those you really like
Aren’t that useful to you
You can only learn certain things from them
But you might not be able to apply those things right away
It might not be the right fit for your path
So, in many cases
We should, of course, treat everyone equally
But it's impossible to treat everyone exactly the same
How can anyone treat everyone exactly the same?
You have your own emotions
I have mine as well
You have your preferences
I have mine too
Is that right?
Everyone feels that it hasn't been fair from the start.
It hasn't been just.
We haven't been entirely equal.
We haven't been of the same country.
So often we have to ask how we should really live our lives.
How we should really face the people around us.
Just be kind to others at random.
And don't think those who seem arrogant now are all bad.
He will always hold his head high with pride.
Just because others might not value his time,
They don’t notice you in his world.
So let me tell you,
It’s really hard for UPloaders to make friends,
It’s difficult to interact.
Because everyone is used to being followed,
Like me, I occasionally go and flatter other UPloaders,
Or flatter their followers.
Most people can't tolerate it
But doing so can give you a significant edge
Why could Liu Bei and Cao Cao become heroes
It's because they handled human problems differently
Why could Liu Bang become an emperor
It's because he handled human problems differently
People have feelings
Often, you need to figure out those around you
Your business will naturally thrive
What's the customer's mindset?
The way of cooperation
How to understand others' psychology
In this world, people hustle for their own gains
When others can get something tangible from you
You should give to them
You only gain when you give
Great rewards bring out brave men
When this giving is just an act of kindness
Or it's related to time and a dynamic relationship
You need to turn it around
Do the opposite
That's why we're saying this again
Never think you're protected by a lion
I just like guys who are 1.85 meters tall
I just do this
Those people won't respect you
Those people won't truly help you
You like those good-looking guys
With fair skin and beautiful appearance
You put them in your favorites
Just look at them when you're free
It's fine
This is fine
It's not embarrassing
But the people who can truly help you
Are the ones who like you
The ones who admire you
The people who can truly help you
Are also the ones who appreciate you
These are the people you should keep closer
These are the ones who are truly useful to you
The ones who truly help your growth
The ones who will spend money on you
The ones who care about you
These are the more valuable people
People are often like this
They lick those they can't reach
But neglect those who are truly valuable to them
People are just like that