But I believe that pursuing love in itself isn't wrong.
Speaking of our show,
we've always promoted the right values,
guiding everyone towards the right path.
Well, how to put it
a straightforward path in life
breaking some fixations
some of my stubborn beliefs and superstitions
to achieve a state of inner purity and balance
in these 26 years of my life
although I'm 40 now
but actually, starting from the first
real, physical girlfriend
It started when I was 14
But I began to talk about it
Thinking about these questions
Actually, it began when I was four or five
But even in kindergarten, there was this urge
By the time I started primary school, at six or seven
It's not that I was precocious
This liking for the opposite sex had already begun
But as a kid, you wouldn't do anything about it
But it wasn't until I was 14
when I was pushed over by a senior
that all sorts of messy things started happening
So it all began from that day
and it's been 26 years since then
So in these 26 years of life
what have I learned?
Absolutely nothing
because I realized that all these things don't really matter
Whether he gets it or not
is actually a form of self-attachment
an excess of self-consciousness
stemming from one's own fantasies and self-deception
A lot of self-deception forms the essence of love
We say that everyone has a different view on love
and thus adopts different life strategies
which ultimately lead to different outcomes
But in my opinion
Everyone's ultimate outcome is the same
it's death
so death is a gradual process
gradually you become old
nobody likes you anymore
you become lonely
nobody comes to visit you
and finally, death arrives
so to speak
The final stage of life can be quite tragic.
So, to combat the hardships of the last few years of life,
you hope to find someone to share your life with,
someone to help raise a child,
so they can take care of you in your old age,
visit you,
but these are all forms of hypothetical value investments,
meaning they may not necessarily lead to the desired outcome,
and your investment might fail.
The person who might end up loving you the most
could be the one who leaves you
Another thing is that your children might be very busy with work
and they might not even live in the same city as you
and they might not make it in time to see you for the last time
Even if they are in the same city
they could be delayed by traffic
These are all things that have actually happened in my family
So when I talk about this
We find that a large number of people in life
spend a significant amount of time pursuing love
or seeking a perfect romantic partner
or wanting to have a perfect relationship
From a sociological perspective
people look for a mate
seek a marriage partner
and build a family
This is a perfectly normal stage
But from my perspective
let me analyze it for everyone
why there are some pitfalls in pursuing love
that are particularly easy to fall into
one of them is the idea of seeking the perfect match
looking for an ideal and flawless partner
first, you need to understand one thing
you are not perfect
and neither is anyone else
You're not just a pretty face.
So, it's a matter of being born at the wrong time.
People often say,
Bro Rong was really handsome in his youth.
Actually, Bro Rong's looks back then,
Let's be honest here,
Putting aside the makeup,
All the lighting and photo editing effects,
My looks are actually just average, about a six.
At most, six points
You could say seven points if you want
But let's be honest
A ten is absolutely stunning
A nine is generally attractive
An eight can already rack up a few million followers on Douyin
So for a seven
We can say they're good-looking enough to turn heads
I was at most passable when I was young
So it's six points
Now, I'm older and heavier
And there are wrinkles too
Plus, the neck isn't visible anymore
Right?
Considering many factors
So the current score is four points
If we add this four to the six
We can take the average
I'm just a five out of ten in looks.
Just a five out of ten.
This person is just average, you know.
Most people are average.
But actually, reaching the average level is already pretty good.
But in our daily lives,
we five-out-of-ten people often idealize those who are seven or eight out of ten,
and set them as our fantasy and pursuit targets.
This creates a significant misconception about ourselves.
I realized that I had once pursued someone who was his ex.
Ultimately speaking,
the outcomes aren't usually great.
It's not like they all married into perfect situations.
Some might even get divorced,
or their husbands might be worse off than me.
Some might be better than me,
but overall,
when it comes to people who are more than one point higher in looks than you,
It's usually not easy to succeed.
Generally speaking, it's not easy to succeed.
When you're at a six, finding someone at a five is no problem.
Finding someone at a six is also no issue.
But in all my relationships,
As everyone knows, the people I've dated,
Let's just say the people I've dated,
Actually, I'm just seven numbers away from hitting a hundred.
So I've managed to achieve something truly through my own efforts.
This person obtained a sample space
as a form of social survey
which is quite accurate
and I have moved several times
but my appearance hasn't changed
nor has my height
my weight only started to increase
after I got married
so during the time before marriage
It has been in a relatively stable state
120 to 130 pounds, or even a bit less
So, a guy weighing around 100 pounds
With a face score of six
A 78-inch-tall man from the north
What kind of person should we be talking about
He is just an average guy
No matter if it’s five or six
But this result will tell us
I've noticed that among all the people I've pursued, none of them have had perfect looks.
There are those with very good looks, though.
And there are plenty with average good looks.
Those with decent looks make up the majority.
People with somewhat average looks also make up a large part.
As I get older,
I realize that the people I've been with,
most of them had looks that were just average or even below average.
In other words, as my looks age,
The people who pursue you might not necessarily be the ones you can end up with.
At the beginning, for example, you might be a six.
While the other person is an eight.
Or a seven.
Or even a five.
A six is still a six.
In such cases, there are many scenarios.
But when your attractiveness drops to a five or a four,
Your partner's attractiveness will also decrease accordingly.
Especially in recent years,
I've noticed why dating has become increasingly difficult.
It's because men always seem to prefer women in their twenties.
But as you get further from your twenties,
it starts as just a year or two difference,
but over time, it becomes five years,
ten years,
and eventually, twenty years.
This makes it hard to have a normal dating experience.
He would prefer someone who is significantly older than him.
We often talk about the golden age gap, you know.
About 5 to 8 years.
Some say it’s 3 to 10 years.
Anyway, anything over 15 years is a bit much.
That’s a bit scary.
Just imagine.
Sometimes I think about dating someone who’s 20 years old.
What’s the difference between liking someone who’s 60?
Is that right?
So, in many cases,
At 60, that would be old enough to be everyone's mom, right?
Or even grandparents.
So, as age increases,
I've noticed,
How can one still maintain an active sex life?
It's about being more open-minded about gender.
Of course, I'm just joking.
But let's be honest
Your previous high standards for looks
Don't aim for someone who is 1 or 2 levels above you
Or at least on the same level
Now you should aim for someone 1 or 2 levels below you
You always want someone in their twenties
But now you should look for someone in their thirties
Or even in their mid-thirties
But there's an issue here
You'll find that people in their mid-thirties
are mostly married
if they're married
or divorced
or still single
but let's talk about a common social misconception
a common social misconception
that if someone is in their thirties and still single
and has never been in a relationship
I wouldn't recommend you to look for someone like that
because such people haven't established a proper perspective on relationships
or values
of course, this is just an individual case
but more people are looking forward to love entering their lives
so I wish them all the best
after all, life is short and fleeting
it's all good
but for more people
People who have gone through a divorce
or those who have been married
their values in love generally remain quite stable
most people after a divorce
are less inclined to remarry
there are still some who want to get married
so overall
to put it in the current context
if you're looking for someone around 30 years old
People over 35
From my current romantic experience
Everyone generally knows what they want
What they themselves want
However
When it comes to the opposite sex at different age groups
What’s needed is just one thing in common
And that’s money
There’s really nothing wrong with that
We've talked about how men deceive for affection and women for money.
This is quite a common thing.
My partner,
Many of my friends have gone to YC,
There are more female streamers,
So their perspectives on life,
Actually resemble mine from over a decade ago,
Similar to what I saw in the 'mistress training classes' twenty years ago,
There's no difference compared to those college classmates of mine.
Society is constantly moving forward.
So, as many men get older,
they use money to buy youth,
spending it on young women.
This is a natural rebalancing in society.
It’s not necessarily a vile phenomenon.
It existed in ancient times as well.
It’s just that modern people might face more constraints.
Modern people can find substitutes for sex and love.
There will be a bit more of that
So when facing a single life
He won't be particularly bored
But from the perspective of companionship
You need to be realistic
I think the most practical point is
You should look for someone with a lower appearance score than yourself
But that doesn't necessarily mean there will be love
It's about you thinking you're reaching down
Just like for a long time
Due to the unstable income
Because I was always taking shortcuts
My life was moving back and forth between different countries
I often dreamt of being abroad
Spending the whole day looking for a place to rent and a job
Begging on the streets all day
Or committing theft
Dreams like these
It shows that I am deeply afraid of this impoverished life.
I am truly terrified and scared of it.
In reality, I have never been so desperate
that I had to resort to stealing or begging on the streets.
Throughout different stages of my life,
there have been times when I lacked money,
and times when I didn't lack it.
But in most cases, it hasn't come to the point of being in debt,
or having issues with basic necessities like food and clothing.
So it affects life and normal protein intake.
No, it doesn't.
Right?
A lot of times,
we might over-analyze things,
pushing them into the subconscious part of our mind.
Later, I found out,
it really doesn't matter how you approach it,
no matter how much you lose yourself.
It's about self-deprecation
looking down on oneself
because I've always looked down on myself
even when I was young
and even as I grew older
I've been in a state of self-contempt
because if someone has self-respect
or is particularly narcissistic
they would present themselves with a flawless image to the world
And I always have a messy appearance
The reason for my messy appearance
is not entirely due to laziness
but because of my feeling of unworthiness
I believe I cannot provide a stable and happy family life
for a normal, excellent woman
In reality
this has proven to be true
as I find it hard to adapt to married life
Or, in terms of my material income,
it might be sufficient for you,
but when it comes to spiritual aspects,
it might not be enough for you.
This is a modest way of putting it.
Because you might not be able to satisfy my spiritual and lifestyle needs,
nor can you meet my material and physical needs.
So, this often leads to a significant discrepancy.
What is this significant discrepancy?
In reality, when you find someone compatible with you
you have to pretend
you have to act like you really care about them
but everyone has different requirements
for example, the people around me
the working women I interact with now
they hope they can work less
and be supported by someone so they don’t have to work so hard
but in fact, they wouldn’t truly seek out such a life
But what if I seek out a female entrepreneur?
In terms of wealth, the income is equal.
But female entrepreneurs,
are often unwilling to be dominated by men.
They've reached this level,
they've already made their money,
why would they want to be dominated by men?
I'm being quite modest here,
I don't mean they don't listen to men at all.
Instead, they want everything to revolve around him
using his ideas as the starting point
this person
no matter how much effort is made to look after his interests
I often tell you
Sister Cayenne often tells me
Let’s go somewhere to play
Your flight is booked
and then everything is arranged
I said I still have a son, you know.
Right?
I can't just leave whenever I want.
So, a lot of the time, he won't care about you anymore.
What's your situation?
Are you willing or not?
If you can stay with me, then do.
As long as you look good.
If you don't look good, that won't do.
You're going to the gym, right?
But for me,
Do I really need to bother you?
Isn't that right?
The biggest issue is,
Once you become an entrepreneur,
You're less willing to help others,
That's the state of affairs.
If you talk about my current state,
Content with a modest fortune
Let's just say yes
A bit more upscale middle class or slightly less wealthy people
So no matter what
If you do the math
This is a freedom of choice
You're less likely to follow the conventional path
Because first, I don't work
I don't work
This gives you more free time to observe life
to observe people like that
to observe business models
and more time to earn more money
It's a positive cycle
When it comes to emotional needs
I can't just be there to accompany you back and forth to work
We'll be there to take care of your emotions
to take care of your needs in life
Because we no longer have anything in common.
So, when it comes to finding a girlfriend these days,
Actually,
Whether it's finding a girlfriend or a boyfriend,
It's quite a challenging time.
It's because my lifestyle and values have changed.
If I were still working a regular job,
I would just look for someone else who also works a regular job,
And go on a blind date.
or find someone who works at the same company
like my parents, they work at a company in Yiyang
they have many colleagues in common
and share the same living environment
the same boss
it's a public institution, after all
so a public institution is a place like that
that's why my parents are employees of a public institution
they have a simple personnel relationship, like those at a publishing house or bookstore
So for me, it doesn't have much reference value.
There's not much that I can apply from their life experiences to mine.
This is quite rare.
So I tend to be a rather cautious and solitary person.
I don't really like to socialize with people who are in similar situations.
I avoid socializing much.
Now, most of my social interactions are with other UPloaders.
And I'm particularly proactive about it.
People might even question my motives.
Actually, I just need social interaction.
I don't need social interaction.
They are two different things.
But for me, they are the same thing.
Right?
So, ha ha.
So, for others,
My social interaction is social in the sense of being social.
Not that other kind of social, right?
So, that's how it is.
Your needs don't match your actual situation.
It's actually that your living conditions have changed.
But when you were young, you never thought so.
Because during the school years,
as a student, you don't have to bear the financial pressure.
Once you enter the workforce,
sudden heavy social and financial pressures,
along with family pressures, come crashing down on you.
You don’t have the time to date.
It becomes a quick pairing.
So, ultimately, what determines the quality of your romantic relationships,
is your income and your actual social status.
In other words, the more money you have,
the more time you have to think about it,
how to deal with the opposite sex and such things.
Of course, in your work,
and during your studies
Academics and work should be your top priorities.
The issue is that you don’t have the time.
So you don’t have the time to think about these things.
But when you do have money,
and the time,
you’ll find that you’re old.
People’s good looks fade,
so you might look for someone younger,
but younger people may see you as an elder.
It depends on who you're looking for.
People who work in the same field.
They all have families.
As for those who don't work, well,
That would be different from you.
For example, if you ask me to find other female content creators,
Finding other female entrepreneurs would be quite normal.
The issue here is about female content creators.
They might think of different solutions.
How do I deal with the top patron?
Why do I just exploit my employees?
So our thoughts are completely different.
Successful women like this are sure to have more than one male partner.
So why should I bother competing for that position?
That’s why my relationship with many so-called successful women is
like this,
I am a good friend of theirs,
but not a male pet for their entertainment, right?
But I also want to be their male companion
But I'm neither young enough nor good-looking enough
However, as a close friend
I haven’t been able to resolve the issue of sexual life
So this is quite a dilemma
So you often see me on Steam
Or logging into various games
It becomes a need that isn’t met
So often, the fulfillment of needs is unequal
It's all a process of rebalancing.
So I've noticed that all entrepreneurs, in the end,
as they get older,
their income increases,
and the final outcome is always the same.
So I won't spell it out; you know what it is.
Often, social choices are not entirely up to you personally,
and they're not something you can specifically envision when you're young.
When you're older, you're left with only two options.
One is NTR
The other is keeping a mistress
Well, there's nothing we can do about that
Perhaps you could participate in both
But similarly
If you approach other entrepreneurs
It's unlikely
Because they also want to hire male models
They also want to keep male companions
It's the same.
They also go after young boys.
I also want to find young girls.
So, it’s essentially the same.
This society also takes your money,
and channels it in a fresh way,
feeding it back into the criminal underworld.
So, this is the imbalance in human desires.
So, pursuing love might be futile.
Because of love, if you set aside social class,
income level,
and the person's lifestyle, it’s just talk.
It’s all just talk.
The only thing I’ve asked all the girls I’ve liked is,
two are homemakers,
and two are career women.
The career women mostly work in offices,
one is a civil servant.
One is a career-oriented woman
The two homemakers are both very capable
But now they are abroad
So they can only manage the household
They really hope to return to the workforce
So all the people I used to admire
In the end, didn't actually do as well as me
So when I pursued them back then
I wasn't the right match for them
The person they ultimately match with will certainly not be someone like me.
So in my life, I want to tell you this:
Love and career are separate things.
You might far surpass the person you once liked.
You might find yourself in a better situation than anyone else.
So focus on living your best life.
Just live your best life.
As long as you acknowledge your current state.
Solving the issue of love can actually be quite simple.
I mean, speaking frankly
I'm already an entrepreneur now
I can leverage all sorts of administrative measures
and use the various powers at my disposal
to acquire more sexual resources
whether it's through money or power
or influence
so what should a man ultimately strive for
first and foremost, it should be a career
When you can't pursue your career,
then go after your leisure time,
like fishing,
or modifying cars,
or playing video games, and so on.
When you truly have a career,
your life becomes the most fun game you can play.
It's that simple.
So my view on love changed later on.
I used to be on the lookout for someone who loves me or someone I love.
But later I realized that the people I love actually don't deserve me.
They just have high looks.
However, as we age,
our looks fade too.
I've dropped from a six to a four.
They've gone from a seven or eight down to a five or six.
No matter how good-looking someone is,
how good can they look in their thirties or forties?
So my pursuit back then didn't really mean much.
People who liked me,
I actually knew there were many.
And often, I missed out on them.
But those who liked me usually had one issue.
They sought a stable emotional connection and a spirit of commitment.
But I tend to be someone who enjoys taking risks.
Someone who prefers the unpredictable.
So my greatest sense of achievement comes from winning them over.
a challenging target
so for me
a goal that has already been achieved has no appeal
this is also a common misconception among men
that's how it is
women tend to be more
attracted to the object of their affection
men, once they succeed in achieving something
once they have succeeded
He gradually stops valuing this person.
The relationship becomes increasingly distant.
I always complain about not having a stable and fulfilling sex life.
But if you look at my life from another angle,
with so many different partners,
you'd realize what truly matters is,
after getting these people into my life,
I failed to maintain long-term relationships,
and soon turned them all into ex-girlfriends.
So, if someone has a stable relationship,
does that mean they definitely have a stable sex life?
When long-term cohabiting partners are together,
or long-term married couples,
some people really do,
Well,
there are those who can't get enough,
the bold ones,
and those who are too timid to even try.
And some people, indeed.
Complete asexual marriage.
While others are all about fulfilling their duties daily.
Exhausted to the bone.
So no matter what.
When it comes to that point.
It's always a matter of supply and demand imbalance.
Our desires in life are endless.
So I later realized, was what I needed to release actually desire?
Or is it the feeling of outsmarting others that I'm after?
The sense of conquering others?
What am I really pursuing?
What is desire itself?
Isn't desire just a factor produced by my body?
Should I spend more money on these things just because of it?
Should I invest more time and energy?
Generally speaking,
If you spend a lot of time on romantic relationships
Flowers are above.
When it comes to pursuing love,
you will lose most of the crucial times for focusing on your career.
So, no matter what,
if you encounter love,
go with the flow,
it’s all good,
no matter what,
at that time, you might want to get married.
You'll naturally get married.
If you want to have children, you'll naturally have them.
It's okay if you don't find love.
But no matter what happens,
the quality of your love life is determined by your values,
your values,
whether you have money or not,
you'll still be who you are.
You are a stable person.
You will eventually seek a stable life.
You are not a stable person.
Ultimately, this kind of relationship tends to be short-lived.
So, this is a very normal thing.
I once really wanted to transform myself into a Chang Ze state.
In the end, the marriage ultimately failed.
My girlfriend of two years,
eventually fell for someone else.
So when I myself am in a fleeting state, like a transient person
I am someone who plays the game of life
I naturally adapted to this kind of lifestyle
I insisted on turning myself into a love-struck individual
a family man with strong family values
This is a fixed pattern that is bound to fail
So recognizing oneself is crucial
If you are Masami Nagasawa, you are who you are
You are Masami Nagasawa
Right?
You're the kind of person who likes short things, right?
You, Seiji Ozawa.
No matter what, though,
you should understand that there isn't much difference between long and short.
It mainly comes down to your values.
Your outlook on life, where your core beliefs stand.
Of course,
I believe my core beliefs have had a significant impact on me.
For instance, at every pivotal moment in my life
it's often been due to the opposite sex
regardless of whether they are older
or younger
their support has been instrumental
leading to changes in my worldview
and even where I live
these changes are usually sparked by someone of the opposite sex
so this has been a positive thing
So, maintain a polyamorous relationship
or a balanced dating status
to ensure you are in an open relationship
in this regard
which is beneficial for your career
entrepreneurs do this as well
of course, many people have a happy family
with a supportive wife
but I find that kind of life really boring
It's really boring.
You wake up every day to the same face.
It can get pretty annoying.
So we believe that if a person wants to take a certain path in life,
then they should take it.
If you want to live a certain way,
then live that way.
Don't fall in love just for the sake of love when you're young,
or worry too much about personal gains and losses.
For a certain way of life
The person you truly love is yourself
In the end, you are all you have
Love for yourself is a constant
The ideal you pursue
Is merely
An idealized and self-deceptive version of yourself
Their actual lives might not be worthy of your admiration at all
They might have nothing to do with you
So you need to understand this point
Break free from the ego in love
Break free from those illusory realities
And you will gain something genuine
You will realize
If you're not doing well
Your love life won't be great either
If you're doing well
You can have as much of this as you want
Sexual resources increase with your power and wealth
It's different
When you reach a certain level of capability
You can have as much as you desire
Do you want to invest a lot of money
A lot of time
A lot of energy in this?
My choice is not to
Everyone
But if I wanted to invest a lot of money here
To talk about it
For me
Finding four or five is not a problem
I'm talking about young ones
This is how it is
So no matter what
Men should focus on their careers
Women should use their youthful beauty
To quickly earn their first pot of gold
This is the general value I uphold
Of course, the premise is that you want to create a career
If you just want a normal life
Paying off the mortgage
A nine-to-five lifestyle
Then this should be your pursuit
You should aim for a stable life
If your goal is to make a name in business
Or to live a free life as an individual
Or to live like a writer or artist
Then
A polygamous life might lead to loneliness in old age
It's a kind of punishment
But no matter what
These interactions with the opposite sex
Can bring you significant advantages in resources
That is to say
Whether you're a male or female content creator
Whether you're a male or female influencer
Believe me
You will never truly find love
Even if you do, it's a fleeting illusion
It will eventually end
So
Many celebrity marriages ultimately fail
Because marriage is about mutual support and protection
A kind of mutual safeguarding
Once you have money
You don't need this kind of protection
You don't need to care about these societal norms
Or legal and social contract agreements
Because you are strong enough on your own
At that point, others can only depend on you
So as you've shown
Live to the fullest
And then consider what kind of partner you should look for
Not based on family or social status
But adapt to the image of a partner
When others suggest matchmaking
When others suggest dating
A true man never worries about finding a wife
If you understand this principle
You will live a very carefree life