it still has a slight reflection
but I'm still me
you know
Today, let's talk about
the issue of TikTok refugees flooding into Little Red Hill.
Actually, this Little Red Book issue has been widely discussed by many bloggers recently.
I feel that it's because I got into the internet relatively early.
I remember back when I was using the internet,
it was mostly a group of young people who loved computers.
I first went online on Silver Sea Web Space.
Back then, I played Diablo I on Battle.net,
and used the earliest version of GameSpy.
Most of the players in this game are foreigners, so you can chat with them in English.
Because you can communicate with them in English, after all.
That's when I realized the internet knows no boundaries.
As the internet has gradually developed over time,
and with the existence of social media now,
there are also firewalls in place,
you'll find that often,
people are living in their own information cocoons.
But due to the U.S. actions against TikTok,
This ban
suddenly led to so many people flooding into Xiaohongshu
I find this phenomenon quite interesting
I think whether it's those studying international relations and politics
or those studying sociology
they would all verify such a well-known phenomenon
and conduct research and analysis on it
I have a friend who wrote a piece for me
It's really good
I think what he's talking about is very fitting.
In the past, you wouldn't notice these kinds of things.
Because so much has happened recently.
For example, Hangzhou isn't just Hangzhou.
This new sixth-generation aircraft flying between Shenyang and Chengdu.
It just happened all of a sudden.
The mountain doesn't see me.
I see myself.
We have become the mountain.
We've become the so-called 'other people's child'.
We've always been envious of others' technological advancements.
We've admired others' various achievements.
Suddenly, the tables seem to have turned.
And often, it's a complete and utter...
Staying still, not moving...
It gives a sense of responding to all changes with no change.
In fact, we haven't done anything at all.
Actually, the U.S. has done a lot in this regard.
He aims to reduce China's influence in this regard.
Regarding his cultural impact,
this is understandable for a country.
It can be understood.
However, promoting such exchanges,
you will gradually realize that the lies spread in the media,
will fall apart on their own.
Just like last year's China travel campaign,
many things are like this.
Once everyone starts to spontaneously appear with visa-free travel
More and more things will start to emerge
Many things actually stem from the exchange
People will discover the real stuff
When it comes to the locals
They don't even want to use Facebook
They're not keen on Instagram either
All sorts of apps
Not just ByteDance's
It's about Xiaohongshu
Anyway, it doesn't matter
No matter how you put it, it's still a
But after he gradually got used to using this kind of thing
He slowly became dependent on it
Of course, I think it's a bit of a pity
Bilibili didn't manage to capitalize on this wave of traffic
But I think it's Bilibili
Because it's positioned to compete with YouTube abroad
When it comes to YouTube,
the ecosystem is quite similar to Bilibili,
Bilibili now feels like a mix of YouTube and OnlyFans,
with some paid content as well,
but to be honest,
Yang Dou can post photos,
and the Little Red Book where you can share diaries,
are actually more similar in many ways,
Americans have now gotten used to these kinds of platforms.
These products under our brand
So asking users to suddenly change their habits
You think that's really tough
Cultivating users' shopping habits
It takes a long time to develop usage habits
You need to have an excellent product
Just like the electric vehicles we see today
These people are only now starting to catch up in terms of technological accumulation
But they can't catch up anymore
In addition to the issue of raw material production
China will definitely take the lead in the future
and lead by a wide margin
Others lack these strategic conditions
leaving them in a forced world
moving
from what is called a multipolar state
back to a bipolar relative state
Let's also discuss the long-term issues between the Chinese and American people
Burst a lot of bubbles
Many people will find out
Who really isn't doing well?
It might be worse over there.
If we calculate using the average purchasing power,
What’s the term for purchasing power again?
Is it GGP or something?
It doesn’t seem to have much to do with GDP.
Because we often suffer from these conversion losses.
Because their currency is more valuable than ours
Our currency has depreciated
So, regardless of how we look at it
But just from the perspective of purchasing power
And living conditions
You will find
When comparing the accounts of Chinese and American people
Many people really struggle with the cost of living
It’s not like we imagine, earning 340,000 yuan a month
He is converted over.
But in reality,
it's a life of three or four thousand dollars.
That's the life of three or four thousand people in the country.
There are many things you can't just calculate like that.
So once these things start to be exchanged,
it becomes really interesting.
Once a person enters the other's information echo chamber,
the walls between the two groups come tumbling down.
Suddenly, the accounts started to match up.
This would create a rather interesting phenomenon.
In the past, when it comes to countries around the world,
especially during World War I and World War II,
they mainly relied on newspapers and mass media.
So this is what we call mass control.
Ah, this MASCO,
the media in Japanese is 'musk',
this 'musk' thing.
It is essentially a means of mass control.
Propaganda has been around since World War II in the Soviet Union,
and during the time of the German Empire in World War II,
when it began to take shape.
It was only after the Cold War that the United States continued to use this approach.
There will always be issues of ideology between countries.
But in reality,
people are divided by language,
and by the media.
Because the means of communication are different
when we talk about it
there hasn't been a bridge for communication
now software can translate directly
there are many things
as long as there's no technical barrier
we can actually get things done pretty quickly
so when we talk about these things
this time it's about China's technological advancements
Winning in the algorithm again
So many things actually have their pros and cons
The other party will take the initiative to come and get some information
This thing gradually levels out like water
It will gradually balance out
It’s indeed interesting
Sometimes when you keep talking on one side
About how good things are abroad
We usually refer to the wealthy
What's life like for the wealthy?
Later, they also showed us more of these things.
But what about the everyday life of ordinary people?
Maybe they have a cat,
or a dog,
sitting on the couch, unwilling to move.
And a lot of the time, they just scroll through Douyin.
Actually, we're all the same.
From this perspective,
you'll often find that
This global village is truly very small.
In the future, we might rebuild our information cocoons,
the walls might go up again,
and Douyin will try to delay this as much as possible.
So they might end up as refugees on Xiaohongshu in the future.
There might not be as many on Xiaohongshu,
but they might gradually patch up the technical loopholes.
So no matter what,
please remember, no matter what happens in the future,
to cherish this beautiful, fleeting process.
After all, you and I are just different by nationality,
but fundamentally, people are the same.
We all have a heart full of passion.