to attack others
to criticize others
to accuse others
but once it affects their own vested interests
they won't hesitate at all
We must crush and destroy the other side.
Of course, that's not what we mean.
You intelligentsia
Rather, we are the intelligentsia.
And that includes me.
You'll find that in many cases,
people's discrimination, insults, and attacks on others,
seem to have a surface-level reason,
that the other party brought it upon themselves.
It's because the other party did something wrong
that he should never be allowed to redeem himself
I want to bring him down
and step on him with ten thousand feet
so that he can never turn things around
but in reality, there hasn't been a court trial
no cross-examination by a lawyer
no involvement from the prosecutor
and yet you've sentenced him to death
Is this the right way to do it?
But you'll find that in many cases,
when we criticize others,
we ourselves are not much better.
So why does Brother Long keep recommending it to everyone?
read books on Machiavellianism.
It's really fascinating.
Because Machiavellianism views everyone as being untrustworthy,
and indeed, everyone is untrustworthy.
When you stop assuming the worst about everyone,
you can actually start acting like a genuinely good person.
When you admit to yourself that you're flawed,
and acknowledge your own bad thoughts,
you can truly understand
what's really influencing you.
For example, in Shanghai,
if you feel discriminated against in Shanghai,
what do people say about you?
People will say you
a country bumpkin
Rong from Northern Jiangsu
often searches on Baidu
Do Shanghainese discriminate against Beijingers?
Of course, some answers say yes
some answers say no
and some answers are
as long as your economy is thriving
He doesn't discriminate against you
That's just it
But when it comes to this
Brother Rong put himself in it
Because I'm from Beijing
A noble Beijinger, right?
The treaty of mutual non-discrimination between Beijingers and Shanghainese
The non-aggression pact
There might be something to it
But you need to know
The reason I agreed to
Shanghainese don't discriminate against people from Beijing
But they discriminate against people from other places
Does that mean I condone it?
Ah, so this is where my hypocrisy lies.
It means as long as you don't discriminate against me
If you discriminate against others
I don't really care
This is where my hypocrisy lies.
You're a racist.
You're a white racist.
You discriminate against Indians.
You discriminate against Jews.
But you don't discriminate against Chinese people.
You don't discriminate against Asians.
Then I'm okay with you.
I think what you're doing is right.
I won't provoke you.
Sometimes it's just like that.
But look at all the people who get attacked online.
Guo Youcai,
Jiang Ping,
and Sister Feng,
so many people, ha ha.
Of course, there are many more people.
There's a long list of others.
You'll find that all those who are attacked
without exception, are from the countryside
or, in other words, from impoverished areas
or rural kids
I once said
about this world
if there were an apology system in society
the ones who should be least apologized to
are these rural children
These are the left-behind children.
They are the ones who have paid the highest price in the course of development.
Their parents' generation paid a price.
The children were separated from their parents from a young age.
And as they grew up,
due to a lack of knowledge,
a lack of funds,
and a lack of connections,
they still have to engage in heavy physical labor, unable to break the cycle.
So I think left-behind children are among the most disadvantaged in China.
When I say this,
do I include myself?
where do I place myself?
Actually, I'm somewhat hypocritical,
a bit of a phony.
Everyone, especially the intelligentsia,
You'll find that everyone,
Of course, now they're saying Jiang Ping cheated.
Someone deserved it, right?
Was it Guo Youcai who had all his singing muted?
Or was it the auto-tuning?
He hasn't had professional training.
I once, after a few drinks,
This was during a chat with a few of my friends.
who are all in the music industry,
because I used to be in a choir when I was a kid.
They all do music.
Their words are a subtle insult to Guo Youcai.
None of them have had formal professional training.
And none of them have been to school.
And they rely entirely on sound cards to fix their vocals.
I have no idea how this jerk became famous.
Why is that?
Because my friend is a singer.
He really enjoys it.
And he has received professional training.
When he was a kid, his mother spent tens of thousands on him.
She found him a teacher.
When he grew up, he went to the UK.
Then he studied in Germany.
So he definitely has had professional training.
I just don't understand him.
And then I said,
You just envy that he's popular, don't you?
Then he said something
that left me speechless.
He said, 'Didn't you also dislike Wang Baoqiang back then?
I said, 'Yes, that's true.
Wang Baoqiang comes from a humble background,
How did a kid from a village near the Shaolin Temple in Henan end up here?
Isn't that right?
Did he ever study acting?'
Did he attend a film academy?
What kind of qualities does he have?
Is his professional competence really that good?
If the audience likes it, it's good. It's good that he's out there.
Mr. Tree's performance is really good.
Right?
It's about whether I like it or not
I respect him.
What does it matter if I don't respect him?
So this is the academic approach.
You mean the other side.
Without professional training.
What you're saying is that I have had professional training.
You think the other side is uneducated.
I went to school.
I am educated.
But actually, this is all about family background.
If someone had the same upbringing as you.
Having a family like yours
With the kind of money you have
They might also be able to receive professional training
Right?
Their foreign language skills aren't good
You deliberately speak English to them
Because you know they can't respond
Just like those shopkeepers in Hong Kong
Knowing they won't be able to answer
Can you say it to me?
I can damn well curse at you in English
And in French too
Then in Japanese as well
No matter what
I will definitely curse at you
Are you trying to play this game with me?
You're trying to play this game with me
So this is about adjusting your approach based on the person
It's that simple.
It's all about playing to the crowd.
So we say the intelligentsia can be quite despicable.
And the intelligentsia tend to look down on others quite easily.
Look down on others.
And they have a bit of power.
One day, they finally gain power.
They will definitely use it.
Is it really necessary to use it?
Going to any lengths
And the intelligentsia's favorite thing to do is to cheat.
Breaking the rules
Look at what Brother Rong says, so much
Talking a thousand, talking ten thousand
Always telling you how to break the rules
How to
It’s all about morality, it’s that simple
So, to put it this way
At the end of the day, I am a member of the intelligentsia.
but I just want to tell everyone
When you are part of the intelligentsia,
it's not a big deal
but you need to be familiar with
you need to understand that our group has its flaws
often, we are unable to empathize with others
you think you are a student
But often, you are also part of the intelligentsia.
An intellectual.
Often, you might find yourself thinking, oh,
you have some inherent prejudices against others,
for example, as Brother Rong said the other day, I've tipped you,
and you didn't give me priority.
This is the limitation of class.
I've tipped you,
and you didn't give me priority.
What's the hidden meaning?
The hidden meaning is,
Look, you don't study properly at all.
So you ended up delivering food, right?
So you see, these things have a deep class character.
Brother Rong always criticizes others,
When criticizing others,
He always includes himself too.
He always includes himself.
If you don't include yourself
then you're just attacking others
mocking and criticizing them
and that's fine
it doesn't affect you
when you can truly analyze yourself as well
when you break down your own motives
you can understand the real issue
where the real damage lies
Others can't counterattack you when they speak.
What's wrong?
Because you're such a smooth talker.
You know so many languages.
You come from a well-connected family, right?
You have a public reputation.
Others have no choice, do they?
Right?
You have a lot of followers
When others speak, they carry little weight
But do you really think people are just like you?
Sometimes you're not like that
You, with your narcissistic personality like Brother Rong
In many cases
You respond to others' attacks in all sorts of ways
You say they're not capable
You say they're not skilled
You say they're not in the right mental state
But is that really the case with the other party?
So sometimes, we might need to ask ourselves sincerely.
Often, in many cases,
we keep saying in our hearts about people from Shanghai,
looking down on people from the countryside,
looking down on people from other regions,
looking down on people from rural areas,
looking down on people from poorer places,
do we ourselves look down on them?
Do we look down on people from the countryside?
Ah, do I only look up to my college classmates?
Do I look down on farmers in the outskirts of Beijing?
Do I look down on those who come from different backgrounds than me?
When others speak English poorly,
Do I not mock them?
How often do I mock others?
Many times, it's exactly like this.
Many times, once you criticize someone,
Take a moment to think about it.
When you point a finger at someone else,
the other four fingers point back at you.
Sometimes you need to reflect on whether
you might be criticizing others
while being hypocritical yourself.
My intense hatred for Fengjie
isn't just because he got American citizenship,
couldn't I get American citizenship too?
I hate Guo Youcai so much
I dislike him so much
and I criticize Wang Baoqiang so harshly
seeing him being cheated on
and wearing the green hat
makes me so happy
isn't it just because of jealousy towards others' talents and achievements?
so many people bully Guo Degang
saying this and that about Guo Degang
Of course, public opinion is different now.
They criticize or even insult Cao Yunjin,
or various other crosstalk performers.
But when he himself faces such situations,
he can empathize with Cao Yunjin.
It's only when he himself encounters such issues that people speak up.
Others come from humble beginnings,
and if he is part of the crosstalk community,
he also dislikes Guo Degang.
So that's how it is
When you dislike something or not
It's related to your personal interests
It's related to your field of expertise
I don't hate Guo Youcai that much
But the core reason I dislike Wang Baoqiang
Is because I'm not in the music industry
The same goes for those in the art field
Or those in mathematics
Is that how it works?
When someone is not in your field,
whether they are cheating or not,
or whatever they really are,
it's about your attitude towards them.
it's about your attitude when the world is unclear.
your attitude towards them,
can you tolerate someone with a vocational degree?
can you tolerate someone from the countryside?
Can you tolerate a rural person being better than you?
Richer than you?
More famous than you?
When you can't get what you desire,
But others have it,
Wouldn't you feel angry?
So this is the limitation of the intelligentsia.
It often happens this way.
But why do we need to analyze this issue?
In today's Chinese society,
who do you want to make money from?
What are the lives of the underclass like?
The middle class,
What is the intelligentsia like?
what are the lives of the working class like?
the wealthy,
the established interest groups,
what are their lives like?
You need to understand
people from every place
people from every social class
people from every background
what their characteristics are
who is insecure
who is narcissistic
who is arrogant
who is conceited
It must be crystal clear.
There must be a thorough analysis and understanding of human nature.
You can't just say that.
Everything is for the people.
How could I have done that?
Take off those high-sounding whistles.
Take a look at your true thoughts.
Why did you pursue fairness and justice when you were young?
Why don't you pursue them anymore as you grow up?
Because you've earned the right to mate
Because you've acquired property
You have some assets now
You have people to care for
When you were young
People would say you talk about fairness and justice
And then say you hate this and that, right?
You can't get it
So you want to take it, right?
Do you think robbery is justified?
You think robbery is wrong.
But do you need to give yourself a noble reason?
Right?
Otherwise, wouldn't that be illegal, right?
But you're not like that.
You say this is a struggle.
I'm different.
So I have a noble reason.
I have my moments to speak
Everyone must take the time to look into their own hearts
to see what direction our sense of shame points to
When you're condemning others
check if your own arguments hold water
if you're being hypocritical
At this point, when you speak
If you view good and evil as something so simple
that can be easily distinguished
Then your life becomes an idealist's paradise
When you truly step into the realm of realism
When you see that everyone has their emotions and desires
When you find that managing people is no easy task
When you truly take on a managerial role
You'll realize that all these people are not easy to handle
All these people based on their backgrounds
Based on their categories
Based on their income levels
You'll find that everyone has their own way of doing things.
Of course, comparing ordinary people to monkeys isn't safe,
nor is it appropriate.
But you must understand,
each social class has its own limitations,
and each class has its own characteristics.
You should also understand,
as a member of society,
you also belong to a certain social class.
You might think you belong to every class.
But that's not the case.
You have the flaws of every class.
Of course, you may have more flaws from certain classes.
However, no matter what,
when you criticize others,
make sure to include yourself.
This way, you won't be a completely evil person.
You'll just be a bit evil.
Of course, many people don't understand why.
I am a good person.
I don’t get the good I deserve.
Are you a good person?
Think about it carefully.
Do you think you are kind?
Do you think you are harmless?
You don’t bully others.
But that’s not enough to be good.
Would you throw a cat off a building just to cut a paper box?
Right?
Often, that’s how it is.
Would you run over a child because of road rage?
Many times, that’s how it is.
Many times, you think you’re not the one who does evil.
So you think it doesn’t matter.
But if you change your perspective many times,
You might also be the one who does evil.
You can also be the evil person.
So, in many cases,
We say that cultivating the mind and being sincere,
Being good and persistent is never about focusing on others,
But rather focusing on yourself.
What problems do I still have?
Where am I still being insincere?
Where do I still need to discern the truth from the false?
Not pointing fingers at others,
Oh, I need to spread the word,
Oh,
I need to preach,
This world is so what, you know,
I need to release life,
I need to organize a Crusade
I need to kill this and that,
The worst person is actually yourself.
You yourself are the source of all evil in this world.
Of course, to some extent, you allow yourself to forgive yourself.
People are just that hypocritical.
So when you truly commit heinous acts,
You will also forgive yourself,
Let yourself off the hook.
How else would the Japanese live?
So, many times, that’s how it is.
You will always find a justification for your actions,
You will always find faults with the other party,
Find faults with the other party,
So what I want to say now is,
Is it enough to always think you’re a good person?
Many times, you need to put yourself under a microscope,
And see what kind of person you really are.