Bro Rong just doesn't buy houses or cars
Can't afford a house or a car
No quotas
But now there are indicators.
So Brother Rong found himself in a dilemma about buying a car.
In this episode, I mainly want to talk about
some of my personal spending habits and the challenges they pose.
So I’m here to give you a little warning.
Especially to young people.
You’ll notice that one thing that really bothers me now
is that no matter what platform it is,
you can always borrow money.
And they all want to borrow money from you
We won’t mention the names of these platforms
To avoid getting lawyer letters from them
But we’re talking about all shopping platforms
Food delivery platforms
And also
Financial platforms, which go without saying
Banking apps
As well as social messaging apps
They're all trying to borrow money from you
Would Brother Rong lend money?
Brother Rong wouldn't lend money
He lends money to those young people
People who need to borrow money are those who don't have money
People with money don't need to borrow
Wealthy people lend money
Wealthy people gather together
They pool their money together
What makes money?
What brings in cash quickly?
Right?
Doing research is so demanding.
Isn't it?
But look at the same period.
We're not talking about being overly fond of foreign things.
Nor are we saying anything specific.
Look at Amazon abroad.
Google
might not have as many
it’s not very convenient to borrow money
right?
it’s not very convenient
I think the financial innovation and reform in our country
has really been fantastic
you can borrow money from all kinds of platforms
that’s a good thing
This is a good thing.
It's a good thing.
So often, it leads to a lot of young people
borrowing money
spending on consumption
you could say many people are spending
boosting the economy
not spending
how can that work?
No one's spending money
How's the economy supposed to work?
Are you willing to go into debt?
I'm asking you.
You're the one spending money.
You're boosting the economy, right?
You're getting drained dry.
You'll be done for.
Isn't that right?
So, most importantly, it's about growing the pie.
It's about giving everyone the means to spend.
Not about encouraging people to borrow to spend.
Then fall into high-interest loans.
And end up paying exorbitant interest rates.
Is that what you mean?
In today's society,
I want to tell everyone that borrowing to consume is the least rational thing to do.
Even when you have money, don't borrow.
Don't spend at all.
Often, we talk about
where we should be spending our money.
This is crucial.
You see, Rong never takes a taxi when he goes out.
We don't take the bus either.
We always take taxis, right?
Support our Didi app.
After going out, eat when you need to eat.
Enjoy the vibrant street food
Street vendors
Or the stores in the mall
I go to Vargas every day
I often spend money there
Bro Rong's spending helps boost the economy
Right?
I'm often willing to spend
But I do think some spending is unnecessary
For example, Wen often buys from overseas platforms
like games on Steam
Today, EPIC is giving away Civilization VI
Everyone remember to claim it
I frequently buy games on Steam
and books from various platforms
I often purchase them
These two items are typical examples of Long's excessive spending
In reality, I buy a book when I think it’s useful
I think the future will read
so I bought it
But when you actually flip through the book
you might forget why you impulsively bought it in the first place
you might forget why you bought it
I've bought a lot of books on Douyin
Books on Douyin can be quite expensive
But if you switch to other platforms to buy books
you'll find they are much cheaper
Even buying e-books
But to be honest
You see, a lot of the time
You don’t really need that many books
Even if you’re a knowledge influencer
You can’t read mountains and mountains of books
I’ve bought around 500 books that are now stored at home
On top of that, I already have over 1,000 books on my bookshelves at home
It’s almost like having a bookstore
And there's no place to put them.
This could be a fire hazard.
It's really not good at all.
I always place the fire extinguisher before I go out.
Fortunately, I don't have the habit of smoking at home.
So, you know, it's still pretty concerning.
You know the games on Steam.
If you add me as a Steam friend, JAMESR61,
You'll find I have way too many games, way too many.
There's just no end to it
But I still buy them, especially when there's a discount
That's my weakness
One is books
The other is games
I always feel that I'll need these things when I retire
But it's actually completely unnecessary
Actually, I should have done it when I was younger
Taken more trips while I was in good shape
Some people say, Rong, you don’t recommend traveling every day, right?
Ah, I don’t suggest it if you’re a white-collar worker
As someone
who is working for a capitalist
and has just saved up 100,000 to go traveling
I should travel, shouldn’t I?
Because I don’t just have 100,000
I have many, many 100,000s
So if I go traveling
Especially as an UPloader,
traveling should be like Brother Feng and Lan Zhanfei,
get out and enjoy more often,
that's what we should do,
but I have to take the kids on weekends,
so sometimes I'm just not willing to go out,
but actually, occasionally not taking the kids,
is also fine,
you can hire someone temporarily, you know.
Whether it's a nanny
or
my parents
if they are in better health
of course, it's possible
so I'm actually tied down by my child now
but the child isn't an excuse
young people should still go out more
I would have more opportunities at 40 than at 50
Going out at 60 is strong
It's better than going out at 70
Right?
By then, you might be in the hospital
Your body won't be as good when you get to the hospital
So, you should still have fun when you can
But I mean, if you spend the same amount of money to buy
A luxury car
Or a house
You might as well go out and have fun.
Because for me,
going out to play means making money.
Every time I go out to shoot, I get ads.
It can boost the traffic of my videos.
It can also gain new followers.
Of course, when you’re browsing all this on Bilibili today,
I particularly love watching travel shows in Japan.
Although I won’t really travel to Japan.
But I really enjoy watching travel shows about Japan
And I've even got a five-year visa for Japan
I always think that once my Japanese reaches N2 level
I'll go to Japan again
I mentioned that I have this lingering concern
But a lot of people tell me
You don't need to
Just speak in the noble accent of Abe ICA
Has Brother Rong also lived in North America?
Just speak to him in English
and you'll enjoy premium service
but I think that's not very polite
you know
in some small places
like I want to go to the Kumano Kodo or something
I want to go to that place, what's it called
what's the Dan Road 88
that's the Buddhist pilgrimage, right
It's basically hiking, which I really enjoy.
What I truly want to do is a road trip in America.
I can't go on a road trip in Japan.
But I can do it in Europe.
There are actually quite a few things I want to do.
I actually find it easy to get a French visa.
A Canadian visa,
and a U.S. visa are all quite easy to obtain.
Right?
I've already got my Japanese visa, right?
But the only place I don't want to go is Southeast Asia.
I don't want to go to Africa.
I don't want to go to Central America.
I don't want to go to South America or the Middle East.
I don't want to visit South Korea either.
I'm not really fond of these places.
But when it comes to Europe,
and North America,
Including Japan
I still quite like it
Of course, this is considered an American colony
Right?
Um
But anyway
You'll notice that my spending pattern is that I don't spend big
For example, buying another apartment in Beijing
I wouldn't do that
I won't just throw money around.
I won't buy property anywhere, either.
Of course, I take that back.
I wouldn't say that.
I won't buy property anywhere in the country.
That's what I'm saying.
That's about right.
From an investment perspective,
Well,
Let's talk about the car.
Look, I'm currently pondering between the BYD Dolphin and the Seagull.
I'm really trying to decide whether it’s the Seagull or the Dolphin.
Actually, it’s also about saving some money.
Because I have to buy something for this festival.
But in fact, all the other expenses are where I actually spend my money.
Actually, I had a method for calculating this before.
It’s a simple principle.
If you haven’t used it in 12 to 18 months
You should just throw it away.
Of course, if you follow that line of thinking.
Then you'd have to get rid of way too many things.
So sometimes you can't completely adhere to that.
But I once wrote a program myself.
It was a home inventory software.
What is inventory software?
Some people call it a household accounting software.
I use it to keep track of items in my home.
I recorded the position based on this 3D location.
What's actually at this spot?
Do you know the coordinates?
And there's a little coordinate system inside the house.
And there are things placed there.
The goal is to avoid buying duplicates.
But later I found that managing this inventory was
Such a tedious task.
There are so many items to buy.
But I really feel like I'm buying too much stuff these days.
It's because there are so many things at home,
I have about 20 unopened packages or so.
I'm just too lazy to open them.
I know what they are,
but I don't need them now, so I'm too lazy to open them.
This is something characteristic of our time,
it's really an issue that everyone encounters.
Many people mention Brother Rong.
You tell others not to buy a house
not to buy a car
and to avoid debt, rationally opposing consumerism
but in fact, Brother Rong has also been deeply harmed by consumerism
I just don’t have any credit card debt
or any internet finance debt
I don’t have any debt
but to be honest, this spending habit isn’t good
it involves buying a lot of stuff
What is this even called?
This is called taking advantage of the poor with low prices.
Low prices are making people poor.
Pinduoduo's items are all about cheap prices that can impoverish people.
Things that cost ten or twenty bucks.
You might think it doesn't matter.
I also bought some things from JD today.
But they're actually things I don't really need.
They're also items that cost ten or twenty bucks.
Get some health supplements for a hundred bucks or so.
Pick up some gadgets.
Spend a few dozen bucks on some games.
Around fifty to sixty bucks.
Buy all sorts of different things.
All sorts of Japanese books.
Russian books.
Why don’t you get them?
Maybe a few dozen bucks.
This is called taking advantage of the poor by cutting small expenses.
He has you figured out.
He has you completely figured out.
So if you want to save money,
the real method is,
not just to save on big expenses,
but to save on small expenses as well.
Save to the extreme.
Save to the utmost.
You usually shouldn’t open shopping apps just to browse.
You’ll find that a lot of the time,
you don’t even know how your money gets spent.
Especially if you have a credit card.
Of course,
Bro Rong mentioned earlier,
don’t buy a house,
don’t buy a car,
but he didn’t tell you that in the second half.
Small payments can include buying books
buying games
buying clothes
buying all sorts of tools
but these things are actually not necessary
what white people really need is the 2,200 calories a day
it's important to learn how to cook
get the meals prepared
eat a bit simpler
Then this will make you very happy.
Life should have some happiness, after all.
These are the kinds of happiness that adults enjoy.
Adult happiness.
Like having a little drink.
Having a small smoke.
Taking a little walk.
Riding a small motorcycle.
These little joys.
Let's talk about these little joys in life
the life of ordinary folks
and often you need to know that you are just an ordinary person
you're not someone special
not someone like Zong Qinghou, a renowned people's entrepreneur
not the type who always travels in economy class
not a moral showman
you're not that kind of person
right?
So, to talk about it,
you are just like Brother Rong,
Brother Rong is just an ordinary person,
an old man from Beijing,
an old man with this level of understanding,
so let's talk about the purpose of being frugal,
frugality can truly slow down your steps to work,
it can help you join the ranks of individual entrepreneurs and small business owners,
this particular group.
Don't let Brother Rong's talk fool you, as if he's in a terrible situation
Many people just take a look at the live stream
When they come to the live stream
They see Brother Rong's place isn't decorated
And they start to judge
Assuming I must be broke
Concluding I must be broke
Yet I'm teaching others how to make money
But I haven't really been teaching others how to make money
Right?
I'm just teaching people how to save money
how to avoid falling into the trap of consumerism
and then save that money
to do more things
but as for what these additional things are
whether it's investing in real estate
buying stocks
trading futures, or purchasing U.S. stocks
Trading Bitcoin
or making various value investments
is your own business
I don’t have any recommendations
I’m just telling you to save this money
don’t go into debt
so that’s the logic
but in reality
in this regard
I'm not doing a great job either
So we're telling you
There's nothing at all
It's useful before it becomes a product
It means the money is in your hands
Having your own cash flow is the safest
When you hold onto something
You have to bear the cost of holding it
For example, buying these books
These books have just been moved from the store's collection.
The games I bought,
I just bought some licenses,
I just have the right to download them.
If I don't play them,
it's like the money was wasted.
Right?
All these things, the stuff I bought from Taobao,
the things from Pinduoduo over the years,
I didn't use them at the time,
or I only used them once,
and a lot of the time, the money was wasted.
Like people like me,
buying the Pocket 3,
the Action 5 Pro,
the G9,
the G100, the M50,
these are all cameras,
and I can truly use them as productivity tools.
Most people buy drones,
buy cameras and only use them a few times,
buy the G7X2,
right?
They're for taking beautiful American-style photos,
where the girl holds the camera, which is a beauty camera,
my ex-wife had one,
my ex-girlfriend had one, and several others had them too,
I bought two myself,
they're for taking beautiful photos of women,
and they're quite expensive,
Xiaohongshu has made them even more expensive,
originally a two to three thousand yuan item,
now it's being hyped up to four to five thousand yuan.
That's what it is.
So you might think that in many cases, holding cash is better,
you know,
spend money where it counts,
save up your money,
and if the economy goes bad in the future,
or if you're not in a good position for work in the future,
you can sustain yourself long-term,
keep yourself alive,
until you find the secret to wealth.
This is very important.
So everyone should reflect on themselves,
and see if you're like me,
often falling for cheap deals,
and buying unnecessary items to stockpile,
that's a rat behavior.