I disregarded the public opinion
And ended up going against the mainstream narrative
And empathized with this guilty individual
This person's actions
What's often being spread around is
stigmatizing many of our fellow citizens
This is utterly excessive
The school's punishment is entirely justified
It's reasonable, effective, and measured
The public's supervision and criticism of me
has been extremely timely
and very enthusiastic
So, the video was taken down.
And I want to sincerely apologize to everyone here.
We, as content creators, should frequently self-examine and correct our mistakes.
And we should be proactive in doing so.
To align with the mainstream views of our audience.
We shouldn't seek attention by being overly unconventional.
That would be very inappropriate.
I apologize sincerely to everyone here.
I got a buzz cut today.