and then come back to watch this batch of videos.
Because in this video, I posted four statuses on my Moments in the middle of the night,
complaining about two girls I know.
These two girls are from wealthy families,
and both of them claim to have depression.
Then these two people both wanted to make money through creating media content.
Monetize
They came to me for advice.
Sigh
That was their biggest mistake.
Because asking me would only result in harsh criticism.
Many people say,
Brother Rong,
My cyber godfather
You're my soul massage.
You're the ultimate sleep companion.
That's a trait I have.
But in reality, I have an ENTJ personality.
What irritates me the most is stupidity.
Before putting in the effort.
When someone just scratches the surface.
Wasting my time.
Draining my energy.
Then go and ask some pointless questions
You’re putting your self-esteem on a pedestal
Your pride can’t be touched at all
They’re all from wealthy families
With a mindset of trying, they also want to do media
I can manage eight accounts in one go
I want to update my grandparents' life
I don’t think I’m someone without a career
That’s how it is
Let me read these few WeChat Moments.
They're all insults.
You'll get a real sense of my personality after this.
Each one is harsher than the last.
Even though it was midnight,
it still got over 50 likes.
In other words, the people around me are all night owls.
Woke up from a nightmare,
I asked Deep Sick two questions.
Ask him to provide the best investment advice given my current asset status
and the best operational strategy for the development of my current career
Most of the answers I got were within the average range
and didn't offer very specific actionable advice
but rather a pile of common information and negative numbers
talking a lot of nonsense that even beginners know
but the core of the issue was never addressed
and no one would feed him with useful information
even if it were provided
It won't be the mainstream information
It seems that relying on large AI models for business advice is still premature
Fancy talk is utterly useless
What truly works isn’t written in books
It’s not taught in classrooms
The real business wisdom often comes down to a single sentence
Most of it is about how to cleverly bend the rules
To profit from loopholes without getting caught
These are all pretty dark practices
Let AI help you analyze accurate information
It's like finding a needle in a haystack
The premise of intelligence analysis is to listen to more sources
and dig deeper
to truly distill useful information
I now spend over ten hours a day reading books
and watching long videos
Only by consuming a large volume can you sift out the valuable information
not those who don't quit their jobs to pursue a career in media
Look, the criticism is starting to roll in.
I can only say that your expertise can't match us full-time bloggers.
Especially those with a team.
This field is now saturated with fierce competition.
If your work is just average,
and your advice is too vague,
it’s just like Deep Seek.
You might as well not enter the industry and build a personal brand.
If you don’t put in the time,
Why should users like you?
This is the most mild one among my four WeChat Moments posts.
Let me read the second one to you.
Either go full-time,
or don't do it at all.
I'm just putting pressure on these two people.
There's no second way.
It's not about whether you're overworking or not,
it's about your intelligence being insufficient.
I never thought that all this blind effort would just move me
In the end, it’s all for nothing
Everything’s fallen apart
I’ll carry on
It’s your IQ that’s lacking
I never thought that all this blind effort would just move me
In the end, it’s all for nothing
Every single one of them
You guys who’ve been watching me do this media thing
Those who felt they could do it
A few of them were fully committed
These UPloaders around me
Regardless of which category they're in
As long as they achieve a significant scale
Which one isn't like a madman
Busting their guts for you outsiders
Crazy
How many of them aren't just trying it out
Serves you right for not being able to do it.
Damn, not even thinking about it.
Not trying at all.
Not using your brain.
Born both cowardly and stupid.
So you end up like this.
Don't blame others.
Blame yourself.
Only see the thief getting the rewards.
You can't just complain about the thief without doing anything.
It's not enough to just envy others' success.
While others shed tears all night and get back up to keep going, you need to do the same.
A few nasty comments in the comment section,
and your ego shatters.
What a load of nonsense.
You haven't even reached the point where you need to rely on talent.
See how others do it,
and give it a try yourself.
Getting a little success and getting cocky
Then working for three days and slacking off for two
Damn it
I even dream about it
What we’re shooting the next day
Taking notes all the time
Posting on social media like a madman
It’s also to document my feelings
Only emotions can truly spread
You might want to stay out of our industry.
It could make a lot of people think it’s all too easy.
Anyone could do this crap.
It’s the same story wherever you go.
This is the second one.
The third one is even harsher, though.
You’re not a kid anymore at 30.
Without your own career,
your life will get darker and darker.
What the hell kind of childish mentality is this?
There's a lot of Mom in that.
A few words and you're already depressed, wanting to take pills.
Often, it can only be said that human society isn't suitable for you.
Heaven's movement is healthy; the gentleman thus strives unceasingly.
You spoiled rich kids, living in luxury, are nothing but useless.
You wouldn't understand people like us who started from scratch.
To get to where we are today, on equal footing with you,
We've endured so much hardship.
The skills we rely on to survive in society
have been built through tears
and blood
pieced together bit by bit
What makes you think watching a video makes you an expert?
You're just protecting your pathetic self-esteem
When your parents are gone
you won't be anything
The more I talk, the more disgusted I feel
The more I talk, the harsher it gets
And the last one is ENTJ
Equally despising all scum, fools, and plagues
I have no obligation to cater to your emotions
That’s your mother’s job
The law of nature
Survival of the fittest
The survival of the adapted
I have no use for inferior genetic traits
Your empathy
You should be eliminated
Instead of gaining any emotional value
It's precisely because of your weakness
Your habitual avoidance
Chasing emotional satisfaction
That's what makes you extremely vulnerable
Timid and sensitive
Such a person doesn't have the qualifications to be an excellent entrepreneur
Or a qualified parent
cannot be considered a true adult
The internet has been too good to you
various information bubbles
making you feel great about how unique your personality is
very charming
Ah, I am a lover
I am the beloved
I have my own brilliance
Well, a defective product is just that – defective.
Of course, let’s talk about it.
To be honest,
I know what I’m saying might sound harsh,
but why do I say it this way?
Because in this world,
especially in society,
there’s no one who will truly feel sorry for you.
Many people will provide you with emotional support.
I'm here to provide you with emotional support.
But kids, I have something to say.
Providing you with emotional support
is meant to make you feel good.
After feeling good,
one should know shame and then become courageous.
If you don't even know shame,
and no one pushes you,
how can you move forward?
Watch food vlogs every day
See how to travel in Japan
Check out how to make money online
Watch a few very elegant videos
With a really nice background music
Isn't it
Then boom-chicka-boom-chicka
Sipping on bubble tea
Eating fried chicken cutlets
And so the day begins.
You haven’t even moved a muscle.
You haven’t burned a single calorie.
Right?
You’re just pretending to put in effort.
Then I got fired from my job, uh.
I’ve run into some unpleasant situations.
Oh.
A follower scolded me, uh.
Someone left a comment
Someone sent me a private message to insult me
Oh, what about my self-esteem?
Then I won’t do it next time
Oh
That’s it
So many times you’ll find
What has society become now?
The era of neoliberalism
It's often quite amusing
no matter what your sexual orientation is
no matter what your gender is
no matter what unique personality traits you have
there are 16 types in the MBTI, right?
there are 12 zodiac signs
Bro Rong even came up with 25 personality types
you're definitely special
You are unique
You are not weak
You are special
You are a unique individual
In reality
Many parents are very strict
Teachers are also very strict
Once they get away from this system
They will feel, honestly
Parents put all sorts of pressure on me
It led to my depression.
I have depression.
But is that really how others see it?
Many people are frustrated with you, wishing you could be better.
I really understand this kind of parent.
Of course, many parents lack education.
And they don’t understand psychology.
Nor do they know much about education.
They want to mold you into a different person.
Actually, that's not good either.
Because different people...
Each monkey needs a different approach.
But let me be frank...
Who gives you emotional support in this society?
Who provides you with emotional value?
Who would give you emotional value for free?
When you come to me for consultation...
Aren't you paying for it?
When you're not spending money
would I provide you with emotional support for free?
You added me on WeChat
which means you're my friend now
No way
Right?
In this world, nothing is free
that truly offers emotional value
Ah, watch my videos
You've received encouragement
And then?
What would you do to truly make me happy?
After you power up
When you become a super fan, the words 'Enterprise Owner' will appear next to your name
Isn't that right?
That's what I genuinely hope for you
Now, when you do a little bit
Behind it all
Bro Rong gave me a mental massage.
What's the point of that?
After you get a mental massage,
you receive healing.
I'm of course very happy.
Because so many people have really worked hard.
Many people need this encouragement.
But what can truly change your fate?
I ask you, buddy.
Let's lick our wounds
Give each other a lick on the behind
Comfort each other
Pat each other on the back
Then shake hands
You're good, I'm good
Everyone's good
Society will start to favor us
Society will start to allocate more resources to us
Can the rich just give away their interests so easily?
You, as a child of a commoner,
can just sit back and get everything without effort?
Do you think that if I say it, a million-dollar mansion will just appear?
Is that how it works?
Is that really how it is, buddy?
Think about it carefully, is that how it is?
Why is it that in many cases,
I actually don't have such a strong sense of empathy?
I don’t actually want to cater to your emotions.
Although, to be honest, a lot of the time,
people say I provide emotional value to you.
But in reality, most of the time,
I’m actually a lot like your parents.
I feel the same frustration when you don’t live up to your potential.
It’s just that I tend to be more patient and guiding in my approach.
I break things down for you,
and explain them in detail.
But when you really have to face life one day
When you have to deal with not being able to pay the rent
When you have to handle a boss who’s pushing you to the limit
What are you going to do
Is it about emotional value
Buddy, I ask you
I really admire you guys
Generation Z
The creativity of the Millennials
the ability to search for information
but to be honest
you guys are not as resilient emotionally
as the generation before us
we've encountered so many of the worst things in this world
things that are hard to even talk about
sometimes they're just unspeakable
our mortality rate is so high now
to be honest, a lot of times
The kind of Japanese-style education we experienced as children
That corporal punishment
Physical punishment was simply too much
It's completely different from what kids experience now
You can't hit or scold them now
Actually, many of you can't be hit or scolded now
You can't even say a single bad word
If your emotional state collapses
I'll go straight to Xiaohongshu
You just straight up posted me on Tieba.
Right?
Girls post on Xiaohongshu,
guys post on Tieba, right?
Sun Xiaochuan was completely roasted.
That's when we met.
But does it actually work?
Buddy,
I'm asking you, is it useful for me to provide emotional support?
Take a moment to think about it.
When I said those things,
To be honest,
Actually, these two individuals,
These two people I'm educating,
They don't know I'm talking about them.
I just let off some steam late at night.
Their schedules are different from ours.
They need their milk tea in the morning.
I want to have a great emotional value.
I want to watch an American drama at night, right?
Watch a Japanese drama.
Do something for myself.
Make myself feel better.
Right?
First, I need to please myself.
Then browse Xiaohongshu for a bit.
Ouch
Let's check out what new cosmetics are on sale recently
Let's see what new clothes are worth buying this season
So in many cases
Let me tell you
If you, a girl, want to go for a masculine look
you have to be even more
The masculine route is incredibly cool
Really, really cool
When it comes to what men have,
what they possess is a capacity to endure.
A very focused kind of
ability that isn't swayed by emotions.
Women, on the other hand, are too easily trapped by their emotions.
This can be quite detrimental.
So, who nurtures your emotions?
Who takes care of your feelings?
The harder it is to soothe your emotions.
Once someone has calmed you down
and patted you on the back
smoothed things over for you
put you at ease
you feel comfortable
then they might take advantage of you
it's that simple
so don't let your emotions get the better of you
even if you're in turmoil inside
Don't let it show
Look at those strong female leads
Those real-life female CEOs
How many of them casually exhale towards someone's nose?
Not many
When you take care of someone's feelings
When you let your boyfriend cater to your emotions
That's actually the worst time
That's when you're giving away your power
A man should focus on his career.
A man should provide financial support.
A man should offer emotional support.
Now, let me ask you something.
If your husband constantly provides you with emotional support,
how weak would you have to be?
Look at all those examples.
My husband brings me toilet paper.
I’m thirsty, honey.
Honey, I want to eat something.
How weak are those people?
I'm asking you.
Is this the life you want?
Is this the life an independent woman like you wants?
I'm asking you, it's the same for guys, right?
You always think girls need to rely on me, don't you?
What do you think girls should be like?
What do you have to complain about?
You're Claude, aren't you?
You're Tifa's boyfriend, huh?
What do you have, Claude?
Is Double Guan Yu playing with words?
What do you have to talk about?
You have a car.
You have a house.
You have cash flow.
You have a career.
You have shares
You've got style
Or are you 18 centimeters tall
What do you have that's worth salvaging
Why are you so mutually hateful
Why are the emotions so opposed
Gender opposition
Aren't they just low-level men
Low-level women opposing each other
Someone who is a bit more good-looking
Who’s stirring up conflict?
Think about it carefully
Can you blame others?
I take care of your emotions every day
How exhausted I am
Think about it carefully
Actually, I’m just as tired of foolishness as everyone else
There's no difference
What can truly change you
The sky is strong
A gentleman should exert himself constantly
Is it about rising from a peasant in the morning
To standing before the emperor by night
You need to have a heroic spirit
It needs to be in your body
It needs to be in your heart
It has to be a flame that never goes out
Otherwise, you’re nothing
Taking care of emotions every day
If a girl’s emotions are taken care of every day, that’s one thing
A girl’s bad mood needs to be soothed
You’re a man, a real man
A tough guy
Why should you be the one to take care of emotions?
Look at the delicate men nowadays
All kinds of people directly dress up as male idols
Of course, I really like male idols
But is that what a real man should be like?
Well, I ask you, if a man doesn't even have masculinity,
How can he protect his country and family?
I ask you,
You'd better join the military,
Go and get some training,
Especially to strengthen your willpower and character
Many people say, to be honest
we are now being greatly pampered by the internet
entertainment to the death
everything is just what it is
it seems like if you hear about a way to make money tomorrow
you could get a handle on it
there are many ways to make money in this world
the question is, are you the right fit for it?
can you take the hit?
Can you handle that?
You're not that kind of person.
Even if I gave you the opportunity,
you wouldn't take it.
You don't have the guts.
So in this world,
what truly needs to be honed is your willpower.
Your willpower is crucial.
What the military teaches you is
It's about your willpower and character strength
Of course, it also trains your physical fitness
But more importantly
You're not afraid of hardship
And you're not afraid of death
A fearless revolutionary spirit
A fearless spirit
This is crucial
Fearlessness in the face of death is crucial
So, let's talk about the boys later.
And the girls.
What do you mean, you're my followers?
I really take care of your feelings.
But you know you have to be strong.
You must be confident and strong.
Love and respect yourselves.
But we can do without that pride.
We can humble ourselves to learn.
To acquire a skill
it’s fine to practice obsessively
because in this world, use it or lose it
there’s no one who truly cares about your feelings
but algorithms will cater to all your preferences
if you want to improve
take advantage of opportunities as they come
it’s bound to be a painful process
if you want to make money
That’s absolutely against nature.
You want to leap to the end.
That’s a once-in-a-lifetime event.
What kind of world will you be facing?
What kind of terrifying future will you be facing?
I can’t even imagine the era I lived in.
Competition was relatively less intense compared to what you face now.
You are now facing several major technological challenges.
There’s only one possibility: to replace human work.
Your job market is far more competitive than in our time.
Compared to when we were young.
It's on a completely different scale.
I can't even imagine.
What it would be like if I were a young person today.
How I would make a living.
I have no idea.
Because I just don't know.
Back then, it wasn't as challenging.
I'm not really tall
This is 20 years later
When I was 21, I wasn't as anxious as you guys are now
It wasn't as hard to find a job
I don't know
If you're not putting in 120% effort now
How will you face the world in the future?
So I'm actually quite anxious now
Very nervous
I'm very happy
I still have a bit of money
I still have some assets of my own
I still have some passive income
Enough to keep me from bowing for a bowl of rice
Otherwise, I'd be driving a ride-hailing car
Or delivering food, which is quite common
Just like millions of others
I don't know
If I were like that
What would I do?
Because I don't want to face this era
So you must train your willpower
Your character
You need to harness your energy
You need to strengthen your willpower
You need to push your abilities to the limit
You have to work your ass off
I worked really hard when I was young
I was very dedicated
But if you always look at the internet for
These negative things
Things that calm your emotions
You'll end up achieving nothing
So sometimes, harsh advice is the best advice
Cyber Godfather might comfort you sometimes
And sometimes push you
You need to be scolded
You need to hear these things
You need to confront your weaknesses
You need to face the cowardice in your soul
Those things that you use or lose
You must have a very strong competitive spirit
I'm not telling you to compete for a civil service position
I'm not telling you to compete for a postgraduate spot
I'm telling you to compete in your career
I want you to compete in your basic skills
In your will and character
You can't give up easily
You can't quit easily
You can't admit defeat before you've fully explored your potential
And feel satisfied with yourself
Feeling quite pleased with yourself
Taking a few photos here and there
Posting two videos today
One tomorrow
None the third day
Doing live streams only when you feel like it
That's just not acceptable
You might be completely
Relying on these skills for the next few decades
Many people will only be able to rely on social media
As their sole source of income
What will you do then?
You need to practice well
Because not being able to make a living is terrifying
You can lie flat
But are you content with that?
Aren't you discontent?
You're not willing to give up