First, let's look at Western countries.
I'll use a Western country I'm very familiar with as an example.
For instance, Canada.
Canada is a country that has gradually achieved
You could say that it achieves a society where warmth is evenly distributed everywhere.
A society where everyone stays warm no matter where they are.
And then there's France.
France is also where I received various subsidies when I was there.
It was incredibly, incredibly fulfilling.
In these two societies,
the main feeling I had was that being a worker is truly a blissful experience.
But you need to understand that in both of these societies,
being a worker
As a middle-class individual,
you bear the majority of the welfare expenses in society.
This means that in this society,
your tax contributions are fixed,
including consumption tax,
sales tax,
payroll tax,
income tax,
and a variety of other taxes.
You'll find that every country
has its own national anthem
but they all tend to target the middle class
Japanese society also targets the middle class
who has read enough books
who takes on white-collar jobs
he is the most stable petit bourgeois
the middle class is the most stable
because they have a certain amount of property
He has his own little house.
He has his own little mouse nest.
He needs to maintain this little mouse nest.
He also pays the mortgage.
And the car loan.
Living his American Dream.
That's how it is.
America also exploits the middle class.
You'll find that the middle class bears the most responsibilities.
The children of the middle class go to war
The children of the middle class
spend this money to pay the highest taxes
The middle class pays the greatest price for the school districts in Haidian District
You'll find that the middle class is in every country
is the most underappreciated class
has no social status
has no political power
There's nothing that compensates the middle class
And the middle class pays the most taxes.
It's often not the rich.
The rich, well,
People say you should pay more if you earn more.
But does earning more really mean you should pay more?
Bro Rong paid his this month.
Well, how do you put it?
What kind of income tax is being paid?
It's the personal income tax being paid.
Corporate income tax and value-added tax
Issued invoices are subject to value-added tax
These three taxes have similar rates
But the issue is
The threshold for corporate income tax is quite low
For personal income tax, you need to pay yourself a high salary
Which makes the tax rate quite high
In so-called developed countries
Like the United States
a country like Canada
a country like Japan
your personal situation
if you earn more money
you have to pay a substantial amount of taxes
to be honest, in our country
many people constantly criticize China online
but from a taxpayer's perspective
China, whether for the middle class or entrepreneurs
Especially for small businesses
Policy incentives
Tax breaks are real and substantial
Unlike some Western countries
Full of sweet talk
Praising our system in all sorts of ways
But if you underreport or make a mistake in your tax calculation
You'll get audited
They'll investigate your taxes
Then this method could make you lose everything
or even land you in jail
In a high-welfare society
most people talk about the benefits of such a society
but rarely mention the class barriers in a high-welfare society
or the high taxes in such a society
Actually, to avoid high taxes
many people in the U.S. often move around
relocating to states with lower taxes
Moving to states with relatively higher incomes
It’s essentially a lifetime of constant relocation
Being deeply rooted in one’s homeland
is not a common practice for them
It’s quite normal for people to move for economic opportunities
So many people are hesitant to buy homes
They prefer renting
Because buying a home ties you down to a specific place
So if you rent, you have more flexibility
There's a lot of freedom to move around
A lot of times, earthquakes, tsunamis, and fires occur
You can just pack up and leave
Right?
What can they do, withhold my deposit?
Ha, what can they do?
One month deposit, one month rent
One month deposit, three months rent
Aren't you also on a one-month deposit?
Is that right?
So, a lot of the time we say,
Even though we often don't appreciate what we have,
But we also say that every country tends to exploit the middle class,
As an educated and cultured person,
You have been shaped by society,
By an educational system that has conditioned you for decades,
You would realize that for society,
It's quite easy to take advantage of you.
Because you follow the rules
Because you are particularly rule-abiding
Because you have a strong tendency to avoid mistakes
If a person can't learn to separate issues
Then they are doomed
And over the years, this kind of education
The school system
Parents will tell you all sorts of things
Making you say 'Oh'
You just need to focus on your studies.
Don't worry about anything else.
Don't start dating too early.
Oh!
Your parents are scrimping and saving for you, you know.
They just want you to go to a good university.
Get a good job.
Find a stable job.
Go for a master’s degree first, then consider a public service career.
The last one is just like a green onion.
Is it exactly like that?
So he has a lot of things.
He uses all sorts of things,
the guilt trip uses all these things,
You fear making mistakes.
You have to take responsibility.
So the educated middle class,
in various countries, are the most severely PUAed group.
Whether it's the middle class in Canada
the middle class in the United States
the middle class in Japan, or the middle class in China
you'll find that the middle class is the one truly burdened with mortgages
and car loans
paying the real price for consumerism
whether you have children or not
you will bear the economic cost
because you don't have children
You enjoy life.
You travel abroad.
You buy all sorts of cosmetics.
You buy all kinds of clothes.
You buy Xiaomi Sochi 7.
Because the Xiaomi Sochi 7 for you,
is like an Android phone in the world of cars.
Right?
You think you like the Xiaomi brand.
You buy a graphics card
You buy all sorts of grains
You buy all kinds of flash cards
Right?
You buy all sorts of models
Right, you go get a foot massage
You're contributing to society in your own way
And the grassroots are the ones not to be messed with
They are the genuine manual laborers
The uneducated among the underclass are the hardest to pacify.
So, at the bottom of society in various countries
whether in France,
whether in Canada,
or in China,
the underprivileged are taken care of,
they are the ones receiving welfare.
Where does the welfare for these recipients come from?
Could it be from the rich?
It's not all brought by the middle class.
So you need to understand that the most unfortunate group in society is the middle class.
The most unfortunate are those who have received the most education.
the audience in front of my television
These followers
You are the most unfortunate people.
Because you're not at the bottom.
You've been to school.
You've read books.
You won't randomly bring good movies.
You won't do anything particularly embarrassing.
Because that's not what a scholar would do.
You think the story of Fan Jin passing the imperial exam is about Fan Jin.
But in fact, you are Fan Jin.
Is it K'ung I-Chi?
It's you.
See, Fan Jin is you.
Because you won't do what scholars wouldn't do.
The real street vendors and peddlers
often have a higher chance of becoming small business owners in the future
your so-called reliance on material things
what do you really know
all you know is taking the civil service exam and joining big companies
attending prestigious universities like Tsinghua and Peking
right
what do the Japanese really know
getting into Tokyo University, right
Get into Tokyo University
Then go to Tokyo, right?
Similarly, the French know that going to Paris means attending the Sorbonne
Right?
And Americans know that attending the Ivy League is the equivalent of going to the Sorbonne
And then in the future, head to Silicon Valley
Or various financial districts in New York
That’s how it goes
So all these middle-class individuals
have a significant income dependency
and a great deal of responsibility
this sense of responsibility
responsibility is something that has been created
there was no middle class in the past
because the commercial and industrial sectors were not well-developed
it was mostly workers and peasants
craftsmen and farmers who didn't receive education either
Craftsmen just need to pass down their skills.
Farmers, on the other hand, have those things.
The productive force is also low.
They don’t even need to operate the lunar calendar.
Machinery back then was completely different from now.
And now these intelligentsia
to be honest,
The intelligentsia can indeed be easily manipulated.
Because the intelligentsia are the most responsible
The intelligentsia uphold rites, justice, integrity, and a sense of honor.
These things are particularly effective.
The intelligentsia must fear class decline the most.
They must not be like manual laborers.
So they are the easiest to control.
A little intimidation goes a long way.
So the intelligentsia fear being intimidated the most.
Then, like the intelligentsia in Japan
what they fear most is being ostracized by society.
By these etiquettes,
and those moral codes that guide and belong to them.
So, to put it simply,
the truly wealthy don’t pay taxes.
The truly wealthy don’t follow the rules.
The lower class also don’t follow the rules.
Those who follow the rules,
are these poor and pitiful economic slaves,
also known as the middle class.