But most importantly, never be an extra.
Many people say,
You don’t have experience,
Don’t you have to start from the bottom?
Why can’t you be an extra?
Don’t look down on any dream.
Let me tell you,
there are shortcuts in life’s journey.
If you don’t know where these shortcuts are,
it’s best not to take that path.
Many things have shortcuts.
You might be putting in effort,
but you’re only impressing yourself.
Just look at the recent news, all sorts of stories about how job opportunities are decreasing.
Actor XXX has started delivering food.
How things have turned out.
Actor XXX has started driving for a ride-hailing service.
Borrowing money from friends.
And I didn’t really want to be an internet celebrity.
I’m begging everyone to give me a chance.
But the truth is, I still want to act.
Or maybe it’s because there aren’t as many long series nowadays.
Now I’m working as an actor in short series.
Short drama actors really have it tough
Making money is so hard
Let me tell you
It's what I've been telling everyone
Don't have this idea
One day, everyone will see the plays I act in
And then I'll become a star
I'll earn more money
That's the fantasy of the emperor plowing the field with a golden hoe
Many extras, to be honest, are kind of
people with dreams
I can't say they're not focused on their main careers
they are very serious
about being extras
always wanting to add a few more lines when they can
hoping for a chance to fulfill their dreams
but let me tell you
most people in their lives
The mistakes you're making are the same as these extras.
It's impossible to get rich or famous by doing a regular job.
First, let's talk about how the entertainment industry is extremely pretentious,
extremely conservative.
You'll find that most popular actors nowadays are second-generation stars,
or rich kids,
or a large number of them are children of mistresses.
Why children of mistresses?
Because the big shots don't want to show their faces.
Because he's not the legitimate eldest son
not the legitimate eldest daughter
she doesn't have the right to inherit the family business
the best option for her is either to go to Vancouver and have Rong help her with her homework
or to enter the entertainment industry
because with a lower score, she can still get into university
this is the best way to inherit the family business
turning wealth and power into fame
so those wealthy actors often set up production teams for filming
Get some veteran actors to play alongside him
Once they become popular
These people come from wealthy families
You, through wanting to learn acting
And then by working as an extra in the future
Or by taking on minor roles to enter today's entertainment industry
With so many fan circles around
If you want to go against the grain in this situation
It's virtually impossible to become famous
Unless you're looking for trouble
Or you're exceptionally smart
As smart as Liying Zhao
Or as tough and capable as Baoqiang Wang
Then you might stand a chance
But apart from those two
Can you give me a third example
Tell me, how many graduates
From the Central Academy of Drama, Beijing Film Academy, and Shanghai Theatre Academy each year
The Military Art and Media University
Nanjing Arts and Zhejiang Media
Let's calculate how many graduates we have
Over the years, how many graduates each year are more attractive than you
In the end, didn't they all end up at KTVs
Or at business KTVs
Or as streamers
How many of my students are now out of acting jobs?
Still doing streaming
Is that right?
Of course, there are those who get roles.
But for those who do get roles,
I'm asking you, what's their family like now?
What was it like before?
And what is it like now?
It's impossible for them to achieve social mobility through the entertainment industry and the money they earn,
In other words, they might make a few hundred thousand a year, but that's as far as it goes.
Of course.
The teacher has a few hundred thousand
What's not to like about that?
But you need to understand the price he has to pay for that money
He has to constantly entertain
Dine out with guests
It's incredibly complicated
Maintaining those few friendships is already tough
And in the entertainment industry
There's no social security
There's no invoice
No contract
A lot of things are essentially fly-by-night operations
All sorts of completely
In reality, you're making money for others
For the assistant director
For the producer
You're not making money for yourself at all
You're just earning this small amount
you have to grovel to others
so this is just not normal
so in China
if you want to do this
if you want to put it this way
unless you're one of those who take shortcuts
those who dare to take the risk of breaking the law
these people can make money
but they're actually committing embezzlement
Of course, let's talk about it.
There are also some operators involved in money laundering.
They can make money.
The rest are idealists with dreams.
They barely earn anything.
So you need to understand one thing.
You might get a few more lines on set.
You might show a bit more skin.
But it’s highly unlikely that this will lead to a class leap for you.
The actors you see now make a lot of money from endorsements.
They earn a lot from variety shows too.
And making a film can also bring in a lot of cash.
Those people are already wealthy.
It’s easy for a rich person to get even richer.
But a person at the bottom
or in the middle,
it’s really hard to climb up.
It’s best not to have the idea that you can move up by doing ordinary jobs.
The best way to climb up is to go into business.
Doing business is a viable option.
The scope of business is broad.
You could be an investor.
You could be an entrepreneur.
You could be a sole proprietor.
All these options are feasible.
If you think you can make money just by your looks,
you'd better go into business instead.
You'd be better off being a streamer
Or even a social media influencer; the money comes in faster
Let's be honest
There are still people with this kind of mentality, waiting for opportunities to fall into their lap
And your so-called connections
Today you meet an assistant director
Tomorrow you meet a cameraman
The day after tomorrow, a producer
They'll just end up spinning you around and taking advantage of you
I wouldn’t let you sleep soundly if I didn’t want you to.
They wouldn’t let you out otherwise.
And they have a ton of resources.
I’m just a small-time director, you know.
I’ve only directed a couple of plays.
Even with a web movie, there are so many people who come to me for no reason.
It’s really frustrating.
When it comes to filming,
who do you think I’ll choose?
I’d definitely go for the cheaper one
Absolutely
The ones who are close to me
I’d definitely choose
The young people I know now
I wouldn’t pick someone who’s from Kashgar
And they’re all in their thirties
And they’re past their prime
Then they ask you to act in a movie
I should give you a few thousand dollars?
Is that really necessary?
Why wouldn't I use newly graduated college students?
It can be settled with just a few thousand dollars.
Why not?
So in many cases,
Don't think that just because you've studied acting,
Or that you've made achievements in this field,
You have acting skills and you'd be making the same mistake I did back then.
I just didn't get it back then
But I figured it out pretty quickly later on
So in the end, it's better to stick to your own path
You can try being an actor and drifting in Beijing
Sure, why not
Earning a few thousand a month is decent
Living that kind of life
Spending some time in Hengdian
Or staying in Xiangshan
Go and hang out on the left side.
Visit Universal Studios.
Or the Starlight area.
You can spend some time there as well.
It's all good.
Go and experience this lifestyle.
You see, I used to be an actor too.
Being an actor gives you a feel for this life.
And then you can become a performance teacher.
Go ahead and write a book about acting
Go ahead and pursue a master’s degree in acting
Sure, you can do that
Consider it as a way to experience life
But if you want to make money
If you want to change your social status
It’s better not to waste your youth here
Many people just don’t understand
You can’t improve your social standing by doing ordinary jobs
You can only accumulate your initial capital through some
very
how to put it
things that are not to be told to outsiders
Once you've accumulated your initial capital
you need to enter the business world and compete
your child might be able to join the circle in the future through your investment approach
he or she can enter this circle
but we say that the children of mistresses tend to be good-looking
The children of the official wife don't look good.
The mistress herself is attractive, though.
That's why their kids tend to go into performing arts more often.
So if you want your child to pursue this path, it's possible.
But it's best to finish your acting studies first.
Then try something else.
Like getting into business.
Or becoming a live streamer.
Or a social media influencer.
Going into live streaming as a beauty influencer is totally an option.
Because nowadays, fewer people are watching full-length films and TV series.
Short dramas also have limited appeal.
These forms of entertainment are gradually fading away.
No matter how you look at it,
the future is still the era of self-media.
Regardless of how you put it,
AI will also become incredibly powerful in the future.
Acting is a profession that will gradually be replaced.
Just like the status of Peking Opera actors today
Just like the status of theater actors today
For the sake of art
Music, dance, and visual arts are all options
You can pursue art
But getting rich from it is almost impossible
So many people want to become famous
Want to get rich
In today's era, it's becoming less and less likely
It's not exactly impossible
It wasn't exactly possible in the old days either
In the studio era
it wasn't exactly possible either
Your looks are off the charts
Even 14 points wouldn't help
The key is whether your family is wealthy
Your family isn't wealthy
You can't score over 100 to get into the Drama Academy
If you can't score over 100 to get into the Beijing Dance Academy,
then you have no chance at all.
When it comes to taking those exams,
the actual level of these art students,
their academic abilities are generally quite poor.
Now, the bar for art students to enter undergraduate programs has been raised.
But let's be honest,
if you are someone who has had a lot of training in this area, like a vocational high school student,
or if you're from a vocational high school,
or a student from an attached middle school of an art institute,
your academic performance really isn't as strong as that of regular high school students.
But regular high school students might not be as skilled in this area.
Looks and skills,
they might fall short.
They might not have had professional experience from a young age like you did.
So it's really tough.
Let me put it bluntly,
the reason I can make a living online today is that
I started working at CCTV when I was 12,
specifically in the Youth and Children's Department.
I spent three years there,
right?
From 12 to 15 years old,
I hosted countless shows during that time,
radio shows,
live events,
all sorts of shows,
TV recordings.
So to speak,
it's only because of that experience that I can make a living in this field today.
A lot of things can't be replaced by just a few sessions of learning.
You have to have a rapport with the audience,
and that's not something that comes easily.