and often, fate is unpredictable.
You never know when you might lose your life.
When that day comes and you lose your life,
would you feel regretful?
You know, like yesterday in the live room,
I was saying that after living for so many years,
I gradually feel that it’s quite rewarding.
Because when I was in my teens, some peers passed away,
and in my twenties, some classmates in their thirties also went.
A lot of people have left us.
Many people,
so over time, I’ve come to realize the unpredictability of life’s length,
there’s a sense of unpredictability about it.
This turns into a survival anxiety.
But this survival anxiety,
after a while, you'll find it diminishes,
you won't be as afraid anymore.
I think that's how it is.
Often, it's dialectical.
I believe in living life,
If there's anything that's essential,
I think it's that you must keep living.
There's a reason for you to keep living
It has to be important
Many people just can't find this reason
Because life is unpredictable
When one day
You truly understand what life is all about
You'll realize that life is unpredictable
It might even be meaningless
In many cases
You realize that things you once thought were so important
like buying a house or a car
getting married
living in a big house
or holding a high-ranking position, might not be as easy as you thought
It’s not always that simple to achieve them
The reality is that sometimes just finding a job
and maintaining your own survival can be really tough
This is the true nature of human society
But one day you'll find
that your life keeps moving forward
and some of the old troubles gradually fade away
replaced by new ones
you spend your life constantly solving problems
and generating new ones
when you're young, you have the worries of youth
and when you're old, you face the pains of aging
for instance, I'm 40 now
No matter what
losing weight has become a really difficult task
I've never been worried about my weight before
I've never been concerned about how much I eat
but now I find that even eating a little bit makes me feel full
and yet the weight won't budge, which is quite a peculiar situation
and now, I have to take several breaks throughout the day
otherwise, I can't maintain my energy levels
otherwise, my energy just won’t be sufficient
Unlike before,
you can't stay up for days at a time anymore.
You might find yourself gradually losing
the meaning of life.
At this point, I'd like to remind young friends,
why not take the opportunity to explore famous mountains and rivers?
Why not read some biographies of historical figures?
Or watch some war dramas?
We're talking about some old films, for instance.
You need to find the meaning of your existence.
Actually, I think it’s something you gradually discover.
Finding the purpose of my life.
There are actually two key points.
One is why I used to be so eager to act.
Why I was so passionate about making movies.
At that time, there was a line from the Big Bang Theory.
It was HOWARD WOLOWITZ who said,
He said he was performing magic when acting.
He realized that in that brief moment,
his mother had actually forgotten some of the pain in her life.
He felt that this was truly precious.
It was then that I saw my classmate,
and my teacher, smiling at the play I was performing.
They all shared a knowing smile.
Everyone was so happy.
Especially when I was in France,
and in Canada.
These two countries don't even speak the same language
they aren't even from the same ethnic group
nor do they share the same culture
but everyone still cheered when I came on stage
it was just this play
it might not have been anyone else's business
it might not have been my own work either
but I was just helping a classmate perform in a play
the moment I stepped on stage
Everyone started laughing
Then I realized
I have this ability to bring joy to people
And everyone acknowledged my acting skills
So from that moment on, I began to
I was determined to pursue this path
I committed myself to this career
Later, after gradually returning to my home country
I found myself in the entertainment industry
It might not be as ideal as we once imagined.
But this isn't just a domestic issue.
Initially, when we started making web films in China,
and even now with short dramas, they can generate a lot of money.
With the potential to earn a lot of money,
it’s possible to achieve social mobility.
This is actually a positive thing.
In contrast, the market abroad isn’t as large,
and doesn’t have the same scale.
It might actually be harder to do.
So, to be honest,
It's not that the films I made abroad were very pure,
and I can't make them back home.
That's not what I mean.
Rather, I've noticed that my way of living is gradually changing.
I want to make a living,
and to achieve my artistic aspirations,
that's not an easy task.
But I did mention it.
This idea, this concept of mine,
if we think big, it's about serving the people,
the intention to alleviate the people's pain and worries hasn't changed.
I still believe my art has value.
I want to help the audience who watch my shows,
to take away some of life's worries.
But later I found out,
since I started making short videos,
Doing this kind of chat show with everyone
At first, I thought it was a way for me to express some
Things I wanted to say
But as I kept doing it, I realized
It has a certain aspect of serving others
Benefiting the public
And this aspect
Also helps alleviate my anxiety about survival
Through various explorations
Because he can make money too
So earning money motivates me to do more
So I gradually found my direction
And the key reason why I particularly love this career at this time
Is that it's more enjoyable than when I was an actor
More enjoyable than filming movies
Because I truly feel the impact on so many people
The shows I produce boost their confidence
I feel encouraged in life
I feel that life has meaning
Things are gradually getting better
I've been encouraged
So, this thing
It's about inspiring people to do good
What we call helping others
Being able to help oneself and others
This is a really great thing
So I feel like I've found my true purpose in life
I wasn't actually into acting at first
Of course, acting is great too
Becoming famous and making a lot of money is good as well
But that wasn't my original intention
My original intention was to help people
To help people alleviate the hardships in their lives
So for me, performing crosstalk
Doing talk shows
Telling stories or acting
Acting in movies or making short videos?
Voice-overs are the same.
It’s all about serving others.
This quality and spirit of serving the people is what matters.
I’m not just flattering myself.
I genuinely have this mindset.
For me personally,
When I act, people follow me,
And my performance can bring joy to everyone.
This has been my consistent life goal since childhood.
This is what I care about.
This is what I strive to hone.
That's why I went abroad to practice this.
It takes a long time.
It costs a lot of money.
It takes my youth.
To practice this skill.
To control my emotions.
Shaping characters and such things
So over the years, my investments have finally paid off
That's what I feel really good about
And as I've mentioned before
Actually, what I focus on more is
For instance, accidents involving children
All sorts of things
Like leaving your child in the car during summer
Or something like that
I went out to play by myself
The elderly stayed at home to take care of the child
The elderly person passed away
Then the child was left to starve to death
Incidents like this had a profound impact on me
Especially the deaths and injuries of minors
All sorts of cases involving illnesses and suffering
It made me think
I started from 2022
Starting in 2002
I became an 18-year-old adult
So anyone who wasn't an adult before 2002
is a kid to me
which means I have a natural affinity for children
and I pay special attention to their growth
and I'm particularly concerned about the impact of such accidents on young people
so back then I made a vow
that if I were to die
It would be great to become something like a guardian angel.
For instance, if a child is locked in a car.
When they call for help,
I could step in like a superhero to help these kids.
I have this simple and heartfelt wish.
Bro Rong managed to complete Silent Hill using only cold weapons.
You know, in Mute Village.
Throughout the series, I mostly avoid using firearms.
I just go through with cold weapons.
Because I think a horror game
loses its fear when you can fight back.
So every time I play a horror game,
the second line says you're terrorizing the people,
and the third line says I'm here to uphold justice.
Just these three lines,
three golden truths,
once you enter the game, you're basically invincible.
Once you get into this game, you're basically invincible.
an indestructible body
because we who practice swordsmanship
as martial artists
have quick reflexes
can easily dodge the opponent's attacks
when playing games
right?
it's not like in real life
in real life, we can dodge attacks too
Let's not talk about this kind of thing.
So, it has had a tremendous positive impact on my life.
A positive and significant boost, you might say.
Why am I saying all this?
I'm saying this in response to a request from our audience today.
There will come a day when you find the meaning of your life.
Once you find it, your life will no longer be aimless.
The meaning of life is the reason you're willing to die for.
A cause, a mission.
A great cause
Indeed, a great cause
My great cause is to save children from suffering
And then to uphold justice for the people
To engage in righteous causes
And then to do things that harm others and are not beneficial to oneself
Not to harm others and not be beneficial to oneself
To do things that harm oneself but not others
Things that harm oneself but benefit others
At the end of the day, it's about serving others
serving the people
walking the path of serving the public
whether your career is in comedy
being a clown
entertaining everyone
or being a trusted older brother
a trusted uncle
helping everyone ease their pain
For me,
this achievement is definitely spiritual.
no matter what you do,
you'll find that as long as you are serving the people,
it's a significant matter.
because I believe, as part of a community with a shared future for mankind,
I chose to be born in this country,
I feel it's, how can I put it,
A great honor indeed
Because from one perspective
When we talk about our country
From the Machiavellian standpoint
Including the stance against neutrality
Neutrality often leads to the greatest loss
One should support one side
You'll find that our country has a sense of conviction
A commitment to doing what is right
I mean, in this chaotic world,
I've endured so much suffering myself,
and the people have endured so much suffering,
I absolutely cannot let that suffering happen again.
I can't let it happen to myself again,
and I must do it for the enemy country as well,
so we always stand on the side of justice.
Considering the gains and losses,
and from the perspective of this strategy,
From a political science perspective
we are definitely at a disadvantage here
but because of our strength
we can afford to take this hit
it's like I'm wielding a cold weapon
in a world full of villains and evil spirits
wandering around
you'll find that horror movies are scary
because what's truly terrifying is the evil in human hearts
These are the things, right?
Of course, when we talk about it,
In reality, one needs to have a Machiavellian mindset,
Because you have to understand that human nature is complex.
When you adopt an idealistic approach,
A persistent attitude towards goodness,
You might find yourself overlooking things,
You might be misled by those who don’t know the full story,
Or, how should I put it,
The little villain will drain your energy.
This is the true believer.
A common mistake made by the purest and most benevolent idealist warriors.
So, speaking of the current dozen or so aspects,
I am working towards a reconciliation in this life.
Promoting a form of realism.
One must also have a conscience.
Idealism should also have some strategy.
That's the idea.
Gradually guide him towards a more comprehensive direction
So, speaking of that
How should we navigate our lives
What kind of beliefs should we establish in our lives
You are who you are
And you should establish beliefs that reflect who you are
Not everything has to be the same as mine
It’s all good
What I’m saying is essentially abstract and intangible
But in reality
I think living each day
when you open your eyes
you must know what you're living for
what beliefs you're living for
when one day your beliefs collapse
you feel that life has less meaning
speaking for myself
I'm definitely not living for material enjoyment
Material desires are basically nonexistent for me.
To be more precise, it's not that they don't exist.
They are just meaningless.
So what if you have everything you desire?
So often, you might wonder, am I really that lustful?
If I were really lustful, I would—
I wouldn't say things like 'little sister' and 'WeiWei'.
I wouldn't push people away.
Are you really that concerned about these things?
What if Mi Su Qi gives me one?
You're not a Ferrari, after all.
Right?
So, what's the point of enjoying it?
Are you really willing to spend tens of millions,
or even hundreds of millions, to build a grand castle?
A huge house,
and then have no family members,
or friends living in it?
An empty room with just one person
Even going to the bathroom requires leaving the lights on
afraid of the dark
and needing to hire a bodyguard
Do you really want to live like this?
Since you don’t want to live this way
then why strive so hard
to accumulate so much material wealth?
accumulated so much material wealth
And for what, exactly?
Oh, you're doing it for freedom.
To avoid bowing down for a living.
You're doing it so your family can have excellent medical care
and living conditions.
You're striving for these things.
You're doing it to have enough time to reflect on yourself,
to ponder life.
Especially someone like Brother Rong.
Now I'm reading some books
I really enjoy reading these days
Why is that?
Because I have a very strong belief
That every bit of reading I do
Every bit of growth I gain
For everyone else
It has a compounding effect
I have 670,000 followers
There are 800,000 across the web
There are a million
No matter what
Regardless of the actual number
It doesn’t matter
My thoughts
I have so many slices
It will eventually spread out
So I’m now very focused on rebirth
It's one's own thoughts
We need to frequently correct our thoughts
For instance, sometimes I have certain values
Frankly, they're not worth spreading
But I find that followers tend to imitate me
They mimic the way I speak
They mimic how I insult others
They even copy some of my crude language
Actually, to be honest
You know, sometimes
the live stream gives me a warning
or the review team provides feedback
I always accept it humbly
because I believe once someone has value in spreading information
and has influence
they need to be cautious
especially when their content might reach minors
so it's important to set the right values for everyone
What kind of values
What kind of outlook on life
What kind of sense of mission is truly useful
I think in this regard
My country is always at a disadvantage
But when it's at a disadvantage
There's always a saying
That goes like this
Those who sow in tears will reap with joy
You'll find that we mostly spread good deeds.
When it comes to gains and losses,
we are definitely at a disadvantage.
If we look at it from a business perspective,
right?
You're not selling Trump-branded watches,
nor are you selling Trump phones,
you are definitely at a disadvantage.
But many things can't be measured by business standards.
In most senses,
it was precisely because when our country was founded,
there were many idealists,
who dedicated their lives,
sacrificed themselves,
that we have today.
However, idealism alone is not enough.
Idealism alone cannot address the realities of
a very harsh world.
So, it's essential to have strength.
In reality,
the prerequisite for upholding justice is having strength.
This is crucial.
That's why,
it's precisely because Earth has a mixed polarity presence,
right here,
just being fixated on goodness isn't enough.
Besides having love,
You still have wisdom.
This is crucial.
You have a knack for seeing through everything.
Sometimes you need to wear a bad guy's mask.
To be a good person.
Just like many bad guys wear a good guy's mask to do evil.
So, in many cases,
In this world,
Who is the true angel?
Who is the real demon?
You can't tell, can you?
Great deceit appears as truth.
So, let's go back to today.
Go back to the last day.
Go back to the final day of your life.
Go back to the first day of your life.
What have you been striving for in your life?
You need to keep refining it.
The current answer might not be the right one.
Perhaps one day when you're older,
as you continue to grow,
in a few years,
even a decade or so,
your thoughts will change.
But no matter what,
please find him.
I once found this feeling while acting.
I'm currently in the process of making videos and writing books.
I need to gradually find this kind of feeling.
I believe that every effort I make will benefit someone.
Although I've simply been working on my own for these two and a half years,
or more accurately, these two and a half years,
or even from four years ago,
since June 2020,
I've been making short videos for these five years.
I've basically never left my bedroom during this time.
But to some extent,
it differs from the physical distance in reality,
How can I put it?
it's because it can connect this room to everyone's bedroom,
from one bedroom to another,
from one heart to another,
it has an amplifying effect,
these things are incredibly meaningful,
what truly matters in life is what has real significance.
It's about being there to sleep alongside everyone.
I can be by your side when you need help the most.
This is the essence of the internet's existence.
It's also why I've been lying low for so many years,
Enduring so much hardship,
The very reason for my existence.
So I feel that the hardships endured for everyone's sake,
The tempering of one's character,
Cease to be hardships at all.
Reading for the benefit of everyone
and establishing certain values
the values that are spread
have a multiplier effect
so when I read a book now
it's as if everyone is reading it
when I establish a good concept now
I help everyone establish a good concept
if I were to take advantage of others unfairly
extremely selfish
everyone will also follow my example
so this creates a kind of
it has a significant impact on me
it requires being very cautious about one's words and actions
when evaluating one's own behavior
this is also part of being an internet celebrity
an influencer's self-discipline
in this regard
When talking with comrades from the United Front Work Department,
it's really a meeting of minds.
Let me tell you,
our country's internet regulators are actually quite humane.
They often have heart-to-heart talks with you,
and frequently sit down for deep conversations.
They will try to advise you,
of course, when it comes to many people,
most internet celebrities are still primarily motivated by profit.
It's more individualistic
Although on the surface it seems very cooperative
But in reality
They don’t really take what others say to heart
But Brother Rong takes these words truly to heart
Because you have to have the people in your heart
That's how it is
That’s what I mean
It’s about the span of your own life
Your personal material enjoyment
compared to the long-term interests of the people
the interests of the nation
the interests of the ethnic group
the moral and progressive development of humanity
the advancement of Earth's civilization
is insignificant, right?
and your personal gains and losses, loves and hates
emotional reactions
All sorts of things
are insignificant compared to the evolution of the universe
so this is not about self-sacrifice
it's hard to put into words
the grand meaning of life
how you should live your life
you should offer your small self
to achieve the greater good
this greater self is what we call the higher self
What is greatness?
I am one of the countless yous.
Countless people just like you.
Even though they may look different from you,
Speak differently,
Or have a different gender,
They are, in essence, you.
Why bring up this philosophical question today?
To discuss it with everyone.
What's the deal with this thing?
Like, these are the rockets being launched now.
These missiles.
Whether it's the people in Israel or Iran.
You have to see that.
No matter what you say.
Some people are digging their own graves.
But you have to think about Israel.
Not everyone supports Netanyahu, right?
Not everyone is a restorationist, though.
There are ordinary people as well.
Right?
Iran has ordinary people too.
Every time a missile is launched,
you'll find that many people don't distinguish between right and wrong.
People,
when they die, it's like the march of war chariots.
It's like the Battle of Shi Hao.
In a state of war
many things are harsh
there's no distinction between good and evil
it's a calamity for humanity
time is universal
we can't say an earthquake in Japan is a good thing
or a tsunami anywhere else
is right
you'll find that Chinese people have a deep sense of kindness
and doesn't hold grudges
but also thinks about revenge
This is a mixed mindset
Actually, it's quite good
Chinese people have a good nature
Look at who treated prisoners of war and their children well
It's the Chinese who did the best
Because we Chinese know our own hardships
We extend kindness to others
It's hard to know others' suffering
I mean, most of the time
we see many people bring it upon themselves
but after they do
when you really see women and children bleeding
when you really see soldiers on the front lines of the Russia-Ukraine war
in those moments of separation and death
you still feel sad
it still feels different
So this is what they call humanity.
The existence of conscience.
Conscience.
Many things, these things, are considered the most precious.
This aspect.
I believe,
the reason we are now,
able to be one of the important forces for peace on Earth,
lies in our profound understanding of human nature.
This kind of tolerance for people's suffering
This kind of reflection
How should I put it
Being able to consider things from others' perspectives
Rather than being like many people
Who have this mindset of racial differences
Or rather, this kind of prejudice
Your way of thinking
Of course
We say that people with a conscience around the world
Actually
regardless of their nationality
ethnicity
or cultural and linguistic background
we all share a common connection
Good people admire and respect each other
which is different
while bad people engage in power struggles with one another
This is the ultimate choice between good and evil.
You'll find that all the good people in the world,
in the end, no matter what, will put down their weapons,
lay aside their prejudices,
and unite together.
But all the bad people have to go through power struggles.
This is the ultimate test of good and evil.
Because the bad people are self-centered,
serving themselves.
It's a place where only one person can exist.
In the end, he must establish a hierarchy.
This is the game of power.
This is also feudalism.
This is also religion.
This is also the order of ancient times.
There must be a hierarchy.
But good people don’t have a hierarchy.
Good people don’t have boundaries.
So, when it comes to being a good person
the cost of being a bad person
the initial cost of being a good person is quite high
the price of persistent goodness is also significant
you also need to distinguish between overly nice people
and foolish people
and those who take advantage of you
if you don't go through these rounds of tests
if you don't experience being wronged
Without being wronged,
or being falsely accused,
you don't deserve to be a good person.
Your kindness isn't steadfast.
When you act as a bad person,
you might also consider acting badly,
starting to take what isn't yours by any means,
being selfish and self-centered,
feeling particularly satisfied when taking advantage of others.
But later on, you'll realize
no matter where you are, there will be people with more power,
more wealth, and higher prestige than you.
You must be the little fish that eats the big fish,
not the big fish that eats the little fish,
but the little fish that eats the big fish.
So, the prerequisite for being the little fish that eats the big fish is that you have to eat other little fish first.
You need to eliminate many fish that are just like you,
and you must bully those who are weaker than you.
That's how it is.
You must take advantage of the weak.
Only then can you finally eat the other medium-sized fish.
Only then can you become a big fish.
Only then can you ultimately eliminate everything.
In the end, you'll find that if there aren't bodies lying around,
then the one lying down will be you.
So this is the path of the villain.
On the path of the villain, you have to be the prettiest of all.
Who's the wisest
Who's the most capable
Who's got what
Your lifespan is limited anyway
So let me tell you
In this world
Being good
Being bad, both come with a price
Being purely good
It's hard to find purely evil people
Most people are a mix of improvisation
Most people are neither good nor bad, really.
Sometimes, one's conscience kicks in.
I've witnessed a human tragedy.
I saw the promotion saying that.
He got better.
Sometimes, we encounter issues of interest distribution in reality.
Feeling annoyed again
Then again, I have to play the bad guy for a few days.
When disaster strikes,
I go to the temple to burn incense,
to pray and worship the gods,
bowing my head like a pestle pounding garlic.
When I’m feeling on top of the world,
I take pleasure in killing,
and indulge in my harem,
today I want to get rid of this one.
Tomorrow, think about the day after, and the day after that, it’s all about people.
It’s about challenging humanity.
It’s actually a very complex matter.
So, I still recommend that everyone
if you can spare 10% of your time,
5% of your wealth,
then give back to society.
There are many ways to give back to society.
I believe that being poor and being impoverished are different.
Being poor means having no money
Being destitute means having absolutely no ability to earn money
It could be due to a disability from labor
Or it could be due to a congenital illness
There are many pitiable people in this world
They can't move freely between good and evil like we do
Or choose their own way of life
Or escape from economic hardships
In this world
Many people might say
that our so-called first incarnation in this world
has been filled with so much pain
its initial settings are quite challenging
so as an experienced veteran player
you need to help them
this is a crucial moment
so in your life
spend some time volunteering
This thing is actually very meaningful.
Like myself, I've been a volunteer for two years.
I was very happy when I was a volunteer.
You don't earn money,
but you are happy.
Because you find the meaning in your life.
Life itself has no inherent meaning,
but you discover meaning.
This makes it incredibly meaningful.
This is one of our joys.
So, no matter how society changes,
Every day you have to take in a lot of information,
How to make money,
How to make friends,
How to handle your career,
What medicine to take for what illness,
How to lose weight,
How to protect your liver.
How to take care of your skin
You'll be bombarded with a lot of information
You might find that for your own survival
Sometimes you're already giving it your all
At this point
You might realize
Besides needing these worldly things
These materialistic things
You also need to seek out something eternal
When it comes to eternal things
Like what Rong often talks about
I discuss worldly matters
Eternal things
As for today’s episode
I’ve talked so much
Also to tell you about eternal things
The principles behind them
When you establish some eternal beliefs
When it belongs to the beliefs of lifetimes
it follows your consciousness
it delves deep into the depths of your consciousness
it conducts profound explorations
so in many cases
you need to cultivate your focus
you can try meditation
you can try physical exercise
this is a crucial time
you have a robust body
a strong mental power
it sustains your physical form
your consciousness does not perish
so no matter what
a person cannot stop thinking
sometimes you might
due to illness, enter a prolonged state of thought
you'll find that life's stages are like peaks and valleys
they pass by like this
so this kind of thing, which belongs to the brave
you need to invest in it
the time spent on my videos
is an investment
essentially speaking
what I discuss with you today
might be the meaning of life
might be a philosophy of living
might be the ultimate choice between good and evil
or it might be nothing at all
it might have no practical significance
but when I feel the need to talk about these things
I will definitely talk about them
because once they are released
you never know
who they will touch in life
who they will ripple in destiny
that's how it is
so in your life
what you do may seem meaningless
or it may seem spontaneous
you don't need to delve into the reasons
when you decide to do something
you never know where it will ultimately spread
you create a video
you never know if you will ultimately help others
where it will spread
what impact it will have on others
you won't know
so just leave it to the void
or leave it to nature
leave it to the universe
leave it to the balance of yin and yang
leave it to the cause and effect
that's enough
but when you work for the universe
while working
you maintain a positive mindset
having a good intention is enough
so many times what we do
the choices we make in life
as long as your belief is right
you don't need to worry about the actual outcome
you won't be the observer of the results
but you are the one who plants the seeds of cause and effect
when your cause and effect are good
when you sow with tears
there will surely be a day of harvest
the one who reaps might not be you
but you will definitely contribute to the universe
definitely have a positive impact on the progress of human society
this is the meaning of your existence
for the progress of human society
for the great unity of the world
for the great solidarity of the world's people
you are living a very meaningful life
our bodies will eventually perish
our wealth, power, and fame
our mating rights
all those fancy sports cars
beautiful men and women will fade with youth
with life, they will ultimately pass away
the pain we bear will completely vanish
as if we never existed in this world
Completely vanished without a trace
As if we had never been in this world
But our impact on the world
It has existed for all eternity.
When you come back to this world next time
You will also witness the fruits of your previous life's labor.