I sleep during the day to avoid the heavy, hot air.
I definitely won't be out there during the morning rush hour,
or the evening rush hour, fighting for a spot on the bus or subway.
Or trying to grab a ride-hailing car.
I just ride my little electric scooter.
Just like Liu Huaqiang, wandering around everywhere
This is truly the start of my retirement life
Although I'm 41 years old now
But as an old Beijinger
As someone who runs a business
I should understand what I really need to do
What does it mean to understand what you should do?
Speaking of our country
The reason why our country can thrive and prosper now
To support such a large economy
To become a moderately developed country
Let me repeat that
I think at this point
The country is already a moderately developed nation
Of course, everyone has different ways of calculating it
That's not the issue
But those young people who are eating takeout in their rented rooms
While crying
Those who come to big cities to work, often referred to as small-town test-takers,
were the left-behind children of yesterday,
and they are, how should I put it,
the backbone of China today.
Why do I say that?
I've mentioned this multiple times,
there's no such distinction between old and new Beijingers,
you'll find that Mr. Lu Xun said something similar many years ago,
he said it.
Whenever I watch a long-distance race,
I often think this way:
the winners are certainly admirable,
but those who, despite their physical exhaustion,
insist on reaching the finish line are the true pillars of China's future.
It's the flowers and applause
that are usually given to the winners,
while the internet giants
often receive less attention.
Those celebrities
Those stars
Those wealthy people
All the flowers and applause go to them
And they actually can't really empathize with ordinary people
But from my perspective,
Frequently see posts about Jingye online
About how Beijing is so authentic and all that
You'll find there's a lot of humor and satire around these topics
There's a lot of self-deprecating humor
This is Jing Ye
This is Hu Ye
Jing Ye for a quick snack
Hu Ye for a quick snack
What about us, the so-called outsiders
People often make jokes about themselves too
But to be honest
All the people around me who are living in Beijing
And those who have struggled or are still struggling in Beijing
These young people are truly the most adorable
This is absolutely not a joke
Because when you're in a city
Let's talk about the basics
I have four apartments in Beijing
Your place remains unrented
Leaving you with zero income
Is it that no one is renting your place?
Your city doesn't offer many job opportunities.
There isn't a good cost of living.
Young people wouldn't choose it.
Like many times before, to be honest,
A city's service industry needs to be well-developed,
There should be places selling breakfast,
There should be food delivery services,
And package delivery services.
Where do these people come from?
They come from the left-behind children of those days.
From 10 years ago,
20 years ago, when their parents were migrant workers.
We often say,
all the various infrastructure projects that sprang up overnight,
were actually supported by that generation of migrant workers.
But now,
it's the children of those migrant workers who are delivering food these days.
Working in basic service industries
As a junior staff in restaurants, you know
The young girls, they are a generation
They were among the best learners of their generation.
became a small-town problem solver
Came to the cities
Whether it's a few hundred dollars for a room in an urban village
Or the various places in the city
Including shared or private apartments
You'll find that truly
even those who start working after middle school or high school
or those who graduate from university but can't find a job
or those who do find jobs
and get into smooth-running companies
they are actually the core talents of the city
as the providers, you'll realize that just saying you want to help the people of Beijing
or the people of Shanghai
can you really fill all these numerous job positions in Beijing?
You can't fill the gap
with just you and these people
you're not enough
right?
so your economic scale
will be quite small
and everyone will be short of money
that's why so many people come to live in rental houses
and tell their parents
Honestly
We hardly saw each other when we were young
And as we grew older, we only meet once a year
Why do we have the Spring Festival travel rush?
There are so many people
Their parents’ generation contributed to the country’s development
They went to various places
And then came to the cities
To work
Tasting the bitterness again
The child has only tasted this dish twice
So, talking about China's urbanization process
Why has it progressed faster than in other countries
Why has it been so steady
Why we have over 600 cities
More than 6,600 counties
All these various counties
It's because these people have been the backbone of the economy
Just the people in your city?
So you should be grateful.
There are so many students coming from all over the country.
From all sorts of counties.
With all sorts of experiences.
They come to your big city.
They contribute their energy.
They dedicate their youth.
All these top 20 major cities
Actually, we all benefit from it.
It’s just a matter of how we put it.
Thanks to these migrant populations.
So, in fact, there’s no such thing as migrant populations.
They are still part of the registered residents.
Many people say 110.
I say 310.
Actually, don’t be so proud.
These things you have are just the legacy of your parents’ status.
Due to our unique household registration system
it's a continuation of yesterday's system into today
But fundamentally speaking
who brings vitality to the city
who supports the city's service industry
who drives the city's economic development
just look at the people in Beijing's Tiantongyuan now
how many are actually from Beijing
Huilongguan community
These major internet companies in Changping
how many of them are actually from Beijing?
We have actually achieved the most effective talent diversion, with the most capable individuals
making significant contributions at the C9 for the country
and contributing to the major internet companies
those programmers, right?
coding all sorts of beautifully crafted apps
that you can use
and enjoy the benefits of the internet
That's all thanks to their hair density.
Those food delivery riders live in various urban villages.
They reside in densely populated residential areas.
What do they provide?
They provide essential urban services.
And there are also the barber Tony guys.
All these people,
They dedicate their most precious years in their twenties to Beijing.
To be honest,
All of you, the original residents of Beijing,
whether you're from the suburbs or the city center,
should be grateful for their contributions.
Thanks to their contributions,
there is the Beijing you have today.
But all you can feel is the traffic congestion,
which is mostly due to people from other regions,
and it's getting harder to find work,
again, mostly due to people from other regions.
So you're competing on a level playing field.
Right?
And besides,
Why shouldn't people come to the capital of China?
Right?
Now it's the holiday season,
and they want more people to come and liven up the tourism market in Beijing.
So it all depends on whose perspective you're looking from.
From the perspective of an ordinary citizen,
You feel like they're encroaching on your personal space
But the reason Beijing has become a megacity today
To have such a vast space for development
Is due to these people, these migrant populations
And these people are not from other countries
They are migrants from other parts of the country
Not legal immigrants
Illegal immigrants
We don't have that many immigrants
These people are our own flesh and blood.
They speak the same language as us.
Fellow countrymen with similar language, culture, and customs.
It's that simple.
They come from different places.
Your city attracting people is what ensures your property values.
The fundamental reason you can collect rent.
You get to enjoy a variety of services.
All of which are made possible by others' sacrifices.
Although you exchange money for these services,
it's important to realize,
if there's no one in your city,
you'll find many cities competing for residents.
if your city lacks people,
labor will become extremely expensive,
and you won't be able to enjoy various services.
you'll be forced to move,
after you move
You'll find that these assets of yours
your properties will gradually become like those in Hegang
you'll realize your house isn't worth much anymore
so by then, you'll be left with nothing
and you'll be forced to relocate
so it's a good thing when people are willing to move to your city
to your hometown
to help develop your hometown
you should feel grateful first
It's really these people who are holding up your country.
The economy of your hometown is being fueled by their youth.
Using this kind of energy as fuel,
they are burning their passion,
providing you with these services.
So every time I get a delivery from an out-of-town courier,
when it comes to these things the delivery guy provides,
if it's hot weather,
I always give them a bottle of drink.
This is the bare minimum I can do.
The least I can do is not to give others bad reviews.
But you'll find that many people are like this.
I'm in this city.
I'm a white-collar worker.
So I take advantage of those who work with their hands.
I'm a security guard.
They say I bully food delivery people.
So that's how it is.
You'll find that those who truly bully others
It's the struggle for living space among the poor.
So, if you have this kind of regional prejudice
it shows that your quality of life is relatively low
So you might feel that others are encroaching on your space
while your income isn't high
and your job performance isn't great
that's why you feel
you know, you drive a car
So I'm already semi-financially independent in my daily life.
Who would care about my affairs?
Right?
No one will stand in my way
Others provide services for me.
I should be grateful to them.
If your status is lower,
You'll have to compete with others for survival space.
That's why some people have regional prejudices.
It's because his social status is relatively low
His income level is relatively low
So he ends up competing with those who have just moved to the city
For these people
Among my classmates, those who are the most regionally prejudiced
And strongly emphasize their Beijing identity
Without exception, are those with lower incomes
They are all at a lower rank
Holding lower positions
So he genuinely developed conflicts with these people
in real life
which is why he harbors such deep resentment
and such strong prejudice
and emphasizes his identity as a Beijinger so much
This is because he has truly experienced friction in the competition
Only those who ride the subway
would feel that there are so many people from other regions coming now
During the Spring Festival, it finally feels a bit less crowded
A bit more spacious
Since you take the bus or subway every day
It’s that simple
You have been genuinely squeezed out of your living space.
These spaces were originally meant for you to do other things
Right?
So, let’s talk about it
If your assets are well allocated
If your family knows how to handle you
How should we work together?
Regarding the future path,
You won't spend too much time in a basic space.
which is why many second-generation city dwellers are so anxious.
Poor performance by the next generation can lead to a decline in social status,
that's the reason behind it.
So, if your social standing is higher,
the higher you stand,
the farther you can see.
You'll come to understand
that conflicts between people aren't as common as you might think
but the lower your social status
the lower your level
in a very low position
struggling for limited survival resources with others
that's when competition arises
that's when discrimination occurs
and there's opposition
It's just that simple.
So, it's your heart that isn't broad enough.
It's your level that's too low.
That's why you have prejudices against others.
That's why you discriminate against others.
It's just that simple.
So, it's really like those rednecks in America,
those lower-class white Americans who feel so whatnot,
those upper-class white Americans,
those elites,
do they feel it?
They don't feel it.
So, that's how it is.
This is the truth of society.
So, whether we talk about regional discrimination or not,
or anything else,
it all stems from your social status not being high enough.
That's why you feel this kind of pressure to survive.
Outsiders sense these things from you.
So, we say, who is the most valuable today?
Who is the most valuable?
Those who dedicate their youth to a city are the most valuable.
This is also a city's greatest appeal.
So, when it comes to it,
from the perspective of propaganda,
we should try to promote this idea,
to eliminate the differences between regions,
everyone, like the people of Beijing,
everyone's ancestors came from all over the country,
it's just that you arrived a few decades earlier,
there's no such thing as a special status,
and it hasn't existed up to today anyway.
So, we say,
these are the things we want to convey today,
whoever contributes their youth to a city,
is the greatest person in that city.