I saw him go to Huixian Yaxu
Right?
There are also symptoms
There are also patients
Isn't this just a given?
Exactly
But we need to broaden our perspective
Let me tell you
People in their twenties
Because your mindset isn't fully developed
Look at me, I'm over 40
I don't care anymore.
Who cares about finding a handsome guy?
It doesn’t matter.
Let it be.
No one belongs to anyone.
No one should restrict anyone.
No one should be confined by this.
Since you two aren’t in a marriage.
It doesn’t involve any children.
It doesn't involve property
Got it?
It doesn't involve legal issues
That's it
You can date freely
Be together freely
There are no binding rules between you
That's it
No need to worry about it
Let me tell you
the person who truly cares for you
won't ask you for a hundred male models
and won't do anything out of the ordinary
the person you're thinking about
the one you want to know more about
won't hide things from you for a lifetime
sigh, won't keep secrets from you forever
you wouldn't know how to deceive someone who doesn't want to deceive you
You give him a chance
he wouldn't think of deceiving you like that
You wouldn't hide it from you for a lifetime
or keep you in the dark
or keep it a secret from you
Oh
or keep anything from you
I don't really care about my cat
it's not mine anyway
Which one of these nine cats is mine?
You see, my goodness!
I can't take it anymore.
I feel so terrible.
Is that how they were born?
Aren't they all born from mother cats?
Right?
These nine kittens are all the closest to me, right?
Isn't that so?
So what?
Right?
Is that it?
Don't overthink it.
Oh!
You can really give birth to Mother Nature and all that?
We're just passersby.
You only have the right to use it.
You don't have the ownership.
His parents don't have the ownership either.
The ownership lies with the heavens.
When the heavens decide to take it, it's taken.
He doesn't even have the right himself.
I said, eh.
I said, are you being formal today?
The heavens say it's not your turn yet.
Not eh.
You mean it's just like that
So, this thing, once you figure it out
No one owns anyone
No one should own anyone
No one should dominate anyone
No one should dictate to anyone
If someone is charming, they spread their charm around
It's just perfect
This is for the survival and continuation of human society
For the better development of future generations
This is also a natural human inclination
To be higher, faster, and stronger, right?
It's quite normal
I'm getting old
Others might want something younger
What's wrong?
From my perspective
Oh, you betrayed me
From a natural perspective
quality birth and upbringing
shouldn't it be like this
shouldn't this be encouraged
you just pretend you don't know and that's it
do they still care about you
they don't tell you, right
I'll keep it from you in the future, won't that be fine
that's how it is
You need to see it clearly.
That's how it is.
Don't take yourself too seriously.
I'm not joking around with you guys.
We are telling you,
As you get older,
When your looks can no longer rule the world,
In many situations,
It's impossible to be the protagonist of someone else's story.
How should you adjust your mindset?
You should take things as they come.
Take things as they come.
Do whatever you want.
Don’t bother me while I’m ascending to immortality.
I’m working on my own path.
It’s not related to anyone else.
You need to have this kind of mindset.
Don’t let gains and losses get you down.
Oh, worrying too much
Worrying too much
Hey, why did you go out drinking?
Hey, why did you come home so late?
No way
I have to manage your money
I have to keep an eye on you
I need to back up your phone
I need to have a tracker
I need to install a GPS in your car
Are you tired?
Buddy, are you tired?
Is life tiring?
Are you tired?
Do you think you're tired?
It's just that thing, isn't it?
It's just a small matter, isn't it?
Really?