It will be divided into two parts
The first part mainly highlights the phenomena
It only presents observations
So this video is about my reflections on the past year.
Because I believe 2024 is a pivotal year.
It has seen many iconic symbols.
A world full of meaning.
I tried to connect them with a thread.
Everything I observed and thought about throughout the year.
Then I put it together.
I'll share my observations and thoughts with everyone
As for 2024,
If I had to pick just one
The event that best represents social trends and sentiments
What would everyone choose?
I would choose the Zhengzhou night ride.
On one evening,
nearly 200,000 college students
spontaneously embarked on a carnival-style bike ride.
They rode shared bicycles from Zhengzhou to Kaifeng, over ten kilometers away.
Police cars
blocked the six-lane road that night.
The 100-meter-wide Zhengkai Avenue was completely jammed.
The traffic stretched for several kilometers.
It created a uniquely spectacular scene.
However, I think the incident itself is not significant.
It appeared and disappeared without a trace.
It was absurd.
Coincidental.
Irrational.
An unrepeatable one-off event, right?
And I don't think this matter is over and done with.
I don’t believe it will have any particularly significant impact on what follows.
But the Zhengzhou night ride is like a symbol,
showing us the young people's sense of drawing their swords and looking around,
feeling lost and aimless,
this scattered passion and vitality with no outlet.
It points to a very timely issue,
and for the year 2024,
my thoughts for the entire year of 2024.
An entry point for observing and reflecting on public opinion and social hotspots
That's also what this video aims to convey.
Following the era of significant growth
The narrative void or narrative crisis in the hearts of the new generation
Let's take a moment to reflect on human nature
Are we beings that live in reality?
I think both yes and no
I, of course, live in this physical space.
But let's imagine for a moment
A patient who has received a terminal diagnosis
The second before he got the report and the second after he received it
His own body
The environment around him actually remained unchanged
You can't unreasonably claim
That his condition worsened in that second, right?
But why is she in hell in the second after?
While he was in a normal state of mind just a second before?
What exactly changed?
This change is because
in the next moment, he has entered a new narrative
with the new identity of a terminally ill patient
he believes his days are numbered
leading to extremely pessimistic expectations
we humans are creatures that live within narratives
as long as we are alive
we will inevitably step into a narrative
taking on and playing a role
This is how we understand ourselves and the world.
Narratives encompass the past.
They include where I come from.
Why I am the way I am now.
They also point to the future.
The path I am on.
What lies ahead for me.
Thus, they shape my perception of myself in the present.
And my view of the surrounding environment.
My level of satisfaction now
and how I express my emotions and behaviors
Narrative has a dual nature
If a person is completely immersed in a narrative
they can't see any other possibilities
and if they completely lose the perspective and ability to step back
they will be confined
they will be consumed by the role
We see many Chinese-style parents
Having a child is certainly wonderful.
But they might be consumed by the role of father or mother.
This role can overshadow everything else.
Apart from being a father or mother,
they don’t know why they are living.
So they get swallowed up by this role.
They lose their sense of self.
We see this happen a lot.
However, on the other hand,
Narratives also provide people with a sense of value.
They allow individuals to have their own social roles.
They can give people a sense of belonging.
Sometimes, we can see that narratives unrelated to us
can still provide a sense of value to some people.
Why has Li Ziqi's return attracted so much attention?
Messi's championship victory,
Why does Zheng Qinwen's championship win inspire people?
Why does the era's boy band, TFBOYS, have such a large following?
To some extent
it's due to their tumultuous personal growth stories
they have at least in front of their audience
they've gone through hardships
they've achieved growth
in the end, they've crossed a mountain
reached the other side, right?
it's a personal narrative
I even think it could be said
The consumption logic of the entire modern sports industry
is built on storytelling.
Of course, that's a bit of a stretch.
If someone can't form a strong, personal connection
with a stable narrative figure,
they can't define their own role
and place in the world.
They might end up feeling lost and disoriented.
If at this point they are actually doing well, though
He's living quite comfortably.
That's not much of a problem.
Because this is just a state of being for modern people,
a common sense of confusion and emptiness among contemporary individuals, right?
But if he's really not doing well,
living in hardship,
then a person might become more vulnerable,
find it harder to get through tough times,
or even more likely to become extreme.
Within a cycle in our society,
there are primarily two prevailing narratives,
one of which is the collective narrative,
which is essentially the Chinese version of MAGA,
a narrative many people believe in,
the vast majority of people,
who believe that our compatriots can work together for a common cause,
and that this effort will ultimately benefit us all,
and we are even willing to make significant sacrifices for it.
Concessions and sacrifices in personal interests
This narrative
I still believe that after many twists and turns
This narrative will ultimately prevail
But in recent years, due to cyclical reasons
It has faced some challenges
It's hard to provide the same level of intensity as before
In terms of setting strong goals
And a sense of power
I won't go into too much detail about this today.
But I think there's a fundamental principle.
That is, all love in the world actually comes with conditions and logic.
Unconditional love,
is rare in this world.
The post-90s generation,
Why is this generation, born after 1995, so patriotic?
so trusting of collective narratives,
largely because from the time they can remember,
We were already doing well
After the Reform and Opening up
Almost 20 years of development
The foundation was already quite solid
And during their growth
They witnessed everything around them and their families improving
Right?
The development of society and their personal interests
Were highly aligned during this period
This is a crucial premise.
Now the growth rate has slowed down.
More and more people are realizing
that many things may not necessarily benefit them personally.
the enthusiasm and intensity of this collective narrative
have also diminished.
I won't elaborate on this.
If you don't have a strong sense of it,
you can check out the last three Olympic Games.
The curve of the audience's enthusiasm and public opinion foundation
has undergone a change
We can also look at the enthusiasm of the younger generation
towards topics like deep space exploration
and the changes over the past one or two decades
I think this can reveal broader trends
and the changes behind it
In the previous cycle, another popular narrative
was the individual narrative of superiority driven by growth
Let's imagine two young people who are equally impoverished
and living what is generally considered an ordinary life.
One of them believes that this is how his life will always be.
He sees no possibility of improving his situation.
His life will not get any better.
The other person, however, believes in his grievances,
his discomfort,
his sadness,
seeing them as only temporary.
As long as he firmly believes he can rise to prominence in the future
the next person will have a good life experience
Why?
Because he has something to look forward to
I was born in 1988
When we were in our twenties
It might be hard for you to believe now, but
anyone around us
almost everyone believed it was a given that things would get better next year
It will be better than this year.
Or take a step back.
Or step back a bit.
Even if next year might bring all sorts of changes.
But in three years, my life will definitely be better than it is now.
And we assume that our salaries will naturally increase every year.
Even if my work doesn't advance further.
Even if my performance doesn't improve.
But isn't it only natural for salaries to rise by 5% each year?
And my spending power and wealth will naturally rise accordingly.
But now, do people still believe
that their lives will definitely be better three years from now?
Everyone might have their own answer.
But the answers I get from my observations and those around me are
people are not as confident anymore.
A significant proportion of people even think the opposite.
That is, they just hope next year will be the same as this year.
I would already be grateful for that.
Especially for those who have entered society
they might be more inclined to view it this way
Now, the two narratives of the collective and the individual mentioned earlier
one is a Chinese version of a mama
the other is a superiority-driven personal narrative
these were the two main narratives popular in the last cycle
whether it's the collective or the individual
from a certain perspective
they are both part of winology
I believe in myself
We can win
And keep winning
So I'm on the winning side
Of course, I can build a narrative that satisfies me
a narrative space that provides value to oneself
This space is quite large.
When I can win
But the issue is winning
The issue with learning is what to do if you can't keep winning
This is the problem with competitive learning.
It's the value it gives to people that is not inherently generated.
Its value is based on comparison.
For example, if you are part of a group that emphasizes competitive learning,
you must believe that Chinese cuisine is the best in the world,
our culture is the most advanced in the world,
our language is the most beautiful and melodious in the world,
and we are on the rise.
Others are reducing it
That's why you would fall in love with this land
Not just because of our food
Our culture and our language
Don't just make you feel close and delighted
But rather, you come to love this land
There's a difference between these two
Just by watching Bilibili, we can find many people
If you talk to him
There are many languages in the world that are truly beautiful
French is also very beautiful
Tell him that
There are many foods in the world that are delicious
Then it might break down
Why
Because his sense of value is not intrinsic
It has to be based on comparison
You have to win
Only then will you truly love this land.
This is even more so from a personal narrative perspective.
Our entire education system is built on the foundation of meritocracy.
The atmosphere of UG has seeped into our very bones.
Although Europe and America also have their quiet and secluded charm,
this game is played at the highest level here,
most widely,
and penetrates every corner of society, especially in the three major East Asian countries.
I believe there's little doubt about this.
Old Zhong always felt that he was never good enough.
It was a life of never being acknowledged.
From childhood to adulthood,
we were all taught
that we shouldn't seek comfort,
or indulge in pleasure.
We should focus on the bigger picture,
look to the future,
born in adversity.
Death from comfort
Better to prepare for the rain before it falls, right?
This is something we often hear.
You have to memorize ancient poems even in kindergarten.
Learn English.
You need to win from the starting line.
Study to change your fate.
We see slogans on the classroom walls.
The fragrance of plum blossoms comes from bitter cold.
Today's sweat
Tomorrow's harvest
So any fun you have while studying feels like a crime
You end up judging yourself internally
And even if you rank in the top 10%
You're already quite outstanding
But you can't afford to let your guard down
Why
Because a single point in the entire province can mean a whole playground of people
You'll always feel like you're not good enough
and once this mindset becomes a habit
it's likely to accompany you throughout your life as you enter society
and start working
you may still feel this pervasive external judgment
along with the pressure of responsibility
you can't provide yourself with enough support
to keep you moving forward
in this environment
You must be outstanding.
You must be ambitious.
And the definition of this excellence is not up to you.
It’s a composite score based on your education,
career,
marital status,
income level,
location, and various other factors,
resulting in a hidden score.
No one knows what this formula actually is
But when you go home for the Spring Festival
You can feel how much this hidden score is
Because your relatives and friends around you
The environment around you will judge you
Due to the reasons mentioned above
Whether it's a collective or personal narrative
From the previous cycle
It is built on comparison
It's not intrinsic.
So it requires a lot of prerequisites.
The many prerequisite standards are still in others' hands.
So when you can't win anymore,
both collective and individual narratives collapse in sequence.
This leads to a void in one's heart after the loss of values.
Let's look at young people today.
As I mentioned in one of my previous videos
his mindset is in a state of being neither up nor down.
There's no real way to not live on.
The kind of biological survival crisis where you can't afford to eat.
Because if you have this sense of survival crisis,
all narratives are just nonsense.
It doesn't matter anymore.
You would fight with all your might to stay alive.
This is an instinct embedded in our biological genes.
However,
we are now in the next era.
This sense of hunger amidst warmth and fullness
The fear of freezing to death is gone
Sure, you won't starve
But it's hard to feel like you're living a human life
It's hard to feel like you have achievements and dignity
Hope
Something beyond mere survival
A sense of purpose
It's hard to feel like you're truly living a human life
But just being alive is not enough.
It's actually insufficient.
No matter how pragmatic a person is,
living in this world,
you need to have something to look forward to.
Many people consider themselves entirely pragmatic,
but they still need something to look forward to.
Something that transcends mere survival.
Or as Fukuyama puts it in his work on identity,
the driving force behind human behavior,
besides the desires and rationality mentioned in traditional economics,
includes this passion for life.
When this passion has no outlet,
when there's a lack of value and a void in narrative,
it manifests like a performance,
creating many bizarre phenomena,
becoming a backdrop of the era's mood.
The popular crazy literature in recent years, for instance,
the omnipresent accelerationists,
the increasingly wild science,
the night riding in Zhengzhou mentioned at the beginning,
the dramatic passion of Fuhang this year,
and the deeply saddening events that occurred in the second half of last year,
in Zhuhai and Wuxi,
the extreme incidents in Wuxi,
individually, they all have various specific causes,
but they are also the cracks and fissures opened by this aimless passion.
This is my observation of social emotions and phenomena for 2024,
the first part of my series.
In the next part, I will delve deeper,
covering even more aspects,
still under the same theme.
I'm Lao Jiang,
So, I'm Lao Jiang.
If you found this episode insightful and helpful,
An UPloader who enjoys sharing their observations and thoughts
The next episode will be out within a week,
thank you all,
I hope you can give it a Triple Combo.
with good eating and sleeping,
and achieving your goals,
thanks.