With a very rapid growth rate
During the previous cycle
We actually had two methodologies
One was collective
One is personal.
The narrative of learning and growth.
As this growth phase comes to an end,
or reaches a turning point,
this narrative of learning and growth,
after bankruptcy, creates a narrative void,
We discussed this issue in the last episode.
And he provided for the new generation
primarily young people, in a widespread manner.
The issue of value loss
which is feeling lost, confused, or having energy
but not knowing where to direct it
In this episode, we’ll discuss this narrative void
this misplaced passion for life
this uncertainty about what to do
this confusion about who I am
this lack of direction on where to channel my efforts
this really uncomfortable feeling
Which direction should we take?
What kind of answer should we seek?
So, for this video, let's start by talking about uh
The framework is to briefly mention a few
Solutions I believe are unfeasible
For example, in the realm of collective narratives
There's a particularly simple and brutal answer
A very ready-made answer
Which is to respond to hatred with hatred
An individual can easily develop hatred towards other countries,
other cultures,
other groups,
another gender of public figures,
Regarding a certain ideology
a certain brand,
or even things they don't understand.
This hatred,
often stems from a sense of self-righteousness.
Then many people
a group of people can form a community due to a shared hatred
they call it a community of hatred
So this community of hatred
actually constructs a new
temporary collective narrative
as it seems everyone is together
and united for a common cause
like getting rid of someone
Or I need to determine who to harm or damage
Then gather together
This forms a temporary collective narrative
In my opinion
We have already entered an era
Where we form communities more out of hate than love
And find ourselves in such an environment
I think the generation born after 2005
The generation born after 2005
Those born in the 2010s live in this era
lacking a basis for comparison
which might lead to a lack of awareness
But from my own perspective
I can sense a truly chilling contrast
My middle school days
were around 2005
a time before the advent of mobile internet
I’ll use changes in the sports domain to illustrate this issue
Because it's incredibly efficient.
It's particularly noticeable.
Back then, sports fans were divided by their passion.
For example, what was everyone's identity?
You were an Allen Iverson fan.
I was a Vince Carter fan.
He was a Tracy McGrady fan.
This person was a Kobe Bryant fan.
Or, for instance, in the soccer world.
You're a Manchester United fan.
I'm a Manchester City fan.
So we might each have our favorite player,
team, or style of play.
And that can lead to conflicts between different groups.
For instance, Manchester,
whether the sky over Manchester is blue or red, ha ha.
This debate has been going on for decades without a clear answer.
There can be all sorts of conflicts involved.
various arguments
even quite intense
but at that time
the underlying logic among different groups was love and joy
love
a passionate love
so the conflicts were byproducts of that love
this might sound a bit abstract
but I believe those who experienced that era as sports fans
You should get my point
But in recent years, the situation has changed quite noticeably
In recent years, the sports community has been divided by negativity
In basketball, the biggest draw is the criticism of LeBron and Curry
In football, the biggest controversy revolves around Cristiano Ronaldo's critics
And Messi's critics
For example, we can see this on Bilibili
The sports section on Bilibili
I don't mean any disrespect
Respect
I'm a bit of a joker myself
I also follow these accounts
but I just use them as examples
So, which account has the most traffic in the sports section on Bilibili?
It's a professional actor
It's the real football fans, like Football Old Eight, who incorporate football elements, right?
On the surface
You might think
This phenomenon isn't much different from 20 years ago.
Because there were rivals back then as well.
Now, Zhan Ku is also a rival.
Melo is also a rival.
The mutual attacks between the two fan groups seem not much different.
But is that really the case?
Do you think all the audience at a real fan club meeting
really all like Messi?
or the audience watching professional actors?
Do they really all love Curry, Jokic, or Kobe?
Not necessarily.
Even my observation is that many people might not necessarily follow
They
aren't necessarily fans of soccer or basketball.
The more fundamental underlying logic
might be that people enjoy the emotional pleasure and sense of superiority
that comes from criticizing an idol,
even a sense of justice and power.
And then there are netizens who attack the opposing camp
To make them lose face and break down
The sense of power and achievement from causing harm
People gather together because of these things
Forming a certain dark group
But don't misunderstand
I have no issue with these UPloaders themselves.
I'm just using them as examples
To illustrate a bigger picture
The changes in the sports world
can more clearly illustrate this emotional mechanism
So, who mainly constitutes these hate groups?
Who would join them?
It's not me, Keqing
It's not that I like to insult my pen pals
But it really is these hate groups
that are primarily made up of students without jobs
Why is that?
Because full-time students haven’t worked for many years, they are quite young.
Then, they are emotionally rich.
They are also mentally active due to their youth.
With strong imagination,
and highly emotional,
they tend to transform into internet warriors.
Not just targeting the sports world,
but also a variety of different battle targets.
They consider themselves righteous.
The crazy Tatta opens up
Today I’ll go viral as an internet celebrity
Tomorrow I’ll become a public intellectual
The day after, I’ll promote a brand or platform
What do they believe in?
Fighting for a while feels good
Fighting all the time feels great
Then they tirelessly rush from one battlefield to another
The switching of enemy targets is very swift.
On a weekly basis,
they come up with a lot of new jokes,
and then launch their unicycle copy and paste attacks,
conquering one comment section after another
They've achieved many glorious victories.
This is their modus operandi.
Their time, energy, and passion are being drained.
And then
Personally, I think
this kind of substitute new collective narrative
doesn't bring any real value.
Why?
Because they are either built on extreme emotions
or on a rather narrow or radical perception
and understanding of the world.
Such a low-quality, crude, and piecemeal collective trend
is also quite gamified.
The people involved
I think many of them don't know themselves
what I want
what I want to achieve
how I can achieve it
it's not as serious as that
it's more gamified
so it can't provide people with
even a slightly longer-lasting and solid value structure
It can't be constructed
And we need to move beyond individual perspectives
To look at public hate communities
Clearly, this has posed significant risks to society and the public opinion environment.
Because affection can be satisfied
I like a particular soccer star
I can get closer to him
Imitate his playing style
And watch his matches
I can be satisfied
However, hatred fueled by resentment is never satisfied
They only sink to lower depths
Getting lower and lower
The scope of hatred expands
We see this on the internet
A few years ago, people would post hateful comments about an issue
Often, why was that?
Because the other party had caused them real harm
Only you would do that
It later turned into
As long as you dislike it aesthetically
You can freely insult and vent
Now I realize the main point is that it's fun
This meme is popular enough
To become a shared reason for joining the hate
This naturally greatly increases
The distrust between people
increased societal vulnerability
while you might say
it's no big deal
these hate speeches are just talk
not to be taken seriously
just for fun
but first, you don't take it seriously
there are always more emotional people
who are doing worse
Younger people tend to take things more seriously
followed by society
society is indeed not that easy
because of the collapse due to these internet comments
but the fragility of society will increase
what I just mentioned
the distrust between people will increase
the willingness to cooperate will diminish
this is a comprehensive negative impact on the entire society
What was it in the end?
In the end, it's what I observed in Weiquan.
I've mentioned this before.
I believe in this.
People are influenced by how things are expressed.
Language, thought, and expression are interconnected.
You criticize this today,
and criticize that tomorrow,
and you might feel like you're just having some fun.
But the words that come out of your mouth will flow upstream
and dirty your mind
turning you into someone with extreme conflicts
in your thinking and combative mindset
you will be permeated in this way
and such a state will shut down your potential for growth
making you a worse person cognitively, emotionally, and socially
So I’m not against being a fun-loving person
in fact, I’m a fun-loving person myself
But I do oppose everyone becoming a hater.
Being a hater is a terrible state to be in.
And I might say something that could really rub you the wrong way,
but instead of becoming a hater,
joining some hate-filled community,
in my opinion,
it’s better to join a fandom and chase after stars.
Because even shallow, specific love,
even if it’s shallow and specific, is still love.
It's better than shallow, diffuse hatred.
This is what I think.
It's a clear mistake or a poor answer.
Apart from this answer,
Besides hatred,
are there other ways out for collective narratives?
Yes, there are.
There are some alternative value propositions.
But few truly fit our land and system.
For instance, religion
Religion has been proven over thousands of years
to have a profoundly significant impact
in providing value
and a sense of belonging and meaning through its narrative system, right?
But we don't really talk about this kind of thing here
And even in the West, after entering modern society
God has been dead for many years
This religious narrative has been on the decline and is almost over
There are also some relatively smaller groups or communities
For example, the various NGOs that are sprouting up all over the United States
And then there are even smaller communities for alcohol and drug rehabilitation
But the situation in our country is quite different
The scale is different
The regulation is different
The culture is different as well
These kinds of things find it hard to thrive
Now that we've talked about collective narratives
Let's take a closer look at personal narratives.
In addition to growth-oriented learning, there's something else to consider in personal narratives.
For instance, before the reform and opening-up, we had a self-sufficient narrative of urban residents.
For example, before the Reform and Opening up
or 'The Long Season'.
I'm referring to the state of the workers in those large compounds.
They actually had individual values beyond the scope of learning.
They have stable production skills.
They maintain stable family and community relationships.
They have a job security that lasts almost a lifetime.
They also enjoy a fairly good social status.
Right?
These things make them people with dignity.
People who take pride in themselves.
They have their own way of life and cultural narrative.
But when we look at these things,
While it might seem beautiful or nostalgic to you,
you need to understand,
this narrative of the citizens has a strong historical context.
It was a time when the market
had very limited competition,
and the private economy had yet to emerge.
Social mobility was very low,
job assignments were fixed,
and the frequency of information exchange was also low.
These premises you have
have given rise to such a group of citizens
who can lead this kind of life
and enjoy a very enduring personal narrative
that provides them with a sense of stability
But with the Reform and Opening up
and economic restructuring
that era has passed
This is the price of development
I don't think there's much to regret.
Because history has proven that
openness is better than isolation.
Movement is better than stagnation.
Let me summarize the key points so far.
During the last major growth cycle,
we had two narratives, right?
Personal and collective academic narratives.
In addition to these,
What alternative solutions are there to what I mentioned earlier?
After Yingxu Xu Xu's bankruptcy,
we can have a community of shared grievances,
an alternative collective narrative in a loose form,
but I strongly believe that
this is toxic and not worth promoting.
Theoretically speaking,
on the collective side,
We might still have collective trends that are religious and communal.
But this approach doesn't fit well with our land and people.
Including individual aspects.
At an earlier stage in time,
The New China once had a static narrative of its citizens.
But this has evolved with the process of Reform and Opening up.
As the iron rice bowl faded away,
It has long since vanished.
The alternative narratives that emerged amid this narrative crisis,
Each come with their own set of issues.
We urgently need a new narrative, right?
What should it be?
I think it should be firmly grounded in individual values.
A self-actualizing narrative.
That is, why am I valuable?
Why am I satisfied with myself?
Not because of what I've contributed to society,
Some very different contributions,
Nor because I earn more than others.
I'm doing well
but it's because I'm different from others
I have my own unique intrinsic value
and I have my own precious
life experiences that no one else can replace
and personal journeys
such things either come from the construction of one's spiritual world
what exactly is this spiritual world
it varies from person to person
Its foundation can be a knowledge-based reflection
it can be an artistic aesthetic experience and system
It could also be a subculture or something ideologized.
It can also be the exploration of natural science.
If you think what I'm saying is too abstract
let me put it another way
it's like the culture of the second dimension
essentially, it's a spiritual sanctuary
where you can gain experiences that transcend daily life
Or
this differentiated individual value
It originates from creative practice
for example, I discover that I have certain talents
whether it's fixing things, drawing, or anything else
or running as well
My talent might not be exceptionally remarkable.
He might just be a loyal son.
but in this field, in this skill
I can achieve continuous improvement internally.
I can do things a bit differently from others.
I can create something that brings me joy.
Something that allows me to fulfill myself.
These two possibilities form a framework.
What I mentioned earlier is based on individual value.
A narrative of self-actualization.
I’ve said quite a bit.
It might still sound a bit abstract.
It might still be a bit abstract
hard to grasp
I think if you can't understand a particularly simple piece of content
you could give it a listen
from last year's King of Comedy stand-up show
The talk show where Fu Hang won the championship
rich in Fu Hang's delivery
it's a methodology built on differentiation
a personal narrative of self-actualization
He says I'm quite ordinary
I'm not impressive
But I won't get discouraged because of that
Why
Because I'm a unique individual
I can do things differently from others
When it comes to my own life
I'm content with who I am
And that helps me maintain a healthy and positive mindset
So he won the championship in this year's talk show
he concluded by saying,
as long as you dare to be yourself,
someone will always fall in love with you.
That's exactly what he meant.
This core message is the source of his appeal.
In my view,
Fu Hang has become a cultural sensation in China
in 2024.
Apart from the reasons related to talk show techniques and styles
he has tapped into the zeitgeist
ordinary people resonate with and find comfort in him
In my view
this is the most fitting narrative for modern society
and it's also a relatively healthy personal narrative
if we trace its origins
It originated with the beat generation in the United States.
Young people in Europe and America are dealing with the crisis of modernity.
a lifestyle and culture built over many decades
he achieved a diversified self-actualization
and replaced collective beliefs with psychological self-exploration
substituted clan and village ties with voluntary communities and new forms of intimacy
but it's unfortunate
in the current global right-turn context
this narrative of differentiated self-actualization
has faced significant challenges and obstacles in its implementation
For instance, I've observed an interesting mindset in recent years,
a rather intriguing attitude,
which is among many social Darwinism enthusiasts,
social Darwinists,
who are often from so-called lower social strata.
At first, I was completely puzzled by this phenomenon.
If society truly followed the law of the jungle,
with everyone engaging in ruthless competition without limits,
those with fewer social resources
a society with less information at the bottom
is absolutely much worse than now
but they easily fall into the trap of simplistic answers
And it might be even more extreme than the sophisticated egoism of social climbers.
they are quick to call for violence and aggression in their words and thoughts
they completely deny humanistic values
deny universal values
and promote the law of the jungle, where the strong prey on the weak
and that got me thinking
Why I had a few more interactions later
and even some live calls
After I tried to put myself in their shoes and see things from their perspective
I got a rough idea
about this psychological mechanism
First, why is social media wrong
A big reason is that there isn't just one path in this world, right
We are not
in fact, just competitors for a single resource
So, modern people can meet their living conditions in various ways
there are actually many ways to achieve satisfaction
such as family affection
romantic love
friendship satisfaction
romantic fulfillment
career achievements
self-expression
The satisfaction of literature and arts, right?
The satisfaction from sports
But indeed, these satisfactions come with certain barriers
I don't deny
That they require support from parents and schools
Provide a space for teenagers to explore and develop themselves
And to put it bluntly, if you truly want to believe deep down
That you are different from others
That you have unique value
You must know what you really like
What are you good at?
What do you love?
You need to know who you are.
Why are you different from others?
And it doesn’t come out of nowhere.
These things need to be developed from a young age.
It doesn’t necessarily require a lot of money.
In the internet era, developing a skill and a hobby
Leads to a richer spiritual life.
Or make some like-minded friends
It really doesn’t have to cost much
Like the students at Moon Forest
Playing in a band can be quite expensive, though
But if you buy a cheap guitar and write and play your own songs
You won’t need much money
At least you can play every day
These Bilibili users usually come from families that can afford it
So the main point is
Families and schools need to provide such a space for teenagers
and this is a luxury for many people
because once you're past your teenage years
and start earning money
you might have the means to develop yourself later
You have your Space
and time to play
by then, you might have become a hollow person
and it will be too late
At this point, if you haven't tried it
it's true that there are all sorts of wonderful things in the world
if you haven't seen them
you might fall into a dog-eat-dog world
I live in a world that's a spectator to a constant battlefield.
because you don't know what else is out there
What's next?
Next is human nature
the self-imposed limitations brought by human nature
Because I've already gone through my own hardships
If I were to acknowledge the value of diversity now
Diverse lifestyles
Then I would be no different from those who have been attending various hobby classes since childhood
Pursuing their interests
Watching plays
Traveling around
Playing tennis
Going skating
Compared to the kids of these middle-class and elite families
I must be even more worthless
I must be even more looked down upon
Rather than being a clown
I’d rather appear tough
appear a bit cooler and calmer
I’d rather say it in a cool way
say it in a very dramatic way
Society is a dog-eat-dog world
Whether through speculation or through windfall profits
I at least have the possibility of a comeback in my imagination, right?
I can imagine myself becoming suddenly wealthy
riding high above those who are now so arrogant
giving them a taste of their own medicine
See
this kind of thinking has a dark beauty, like a long-suffering wife finally getting the upper hand
the more I am bullied
the more my thinking is limited
It can only develop according to a single pattern
until I can take advantage of others
but it does align with human nature
ultimately, this is also a result of cyclical changes
this isn't unique to China
the world is now entering a downturn
almost all societies are moving to the right
if we look back at the long river of history
since modern times
Throughout history, every time there's a downturn in growth rates,
society tends to shift to the right,
with a tendency towards conservatism.
This shift often contains a considerable degree of rationality,
because in such periods,
risk-taking and openness
don't provide the same benefits to ordinary people as they do during growth periods.
Now, take a young person for example,
I'm open-minded when it comes to gender views.
I can't seem to find a partner either
which means I can't get married, right?
I have an open-minded approach to spending
but I still can't afford premium goods
so why should I be open-minded?
I might as well be conservative
That's why being conservative has become a collective aesthetic preference and lifestyle choice
This is also from the video I posted in May of 2023.
being right-wing on minor issues
So, what I'm saying is actually in line with this matter.
But what I want to say is,
the underlying logic of an aesthetic preference is rational.
it doesn't mean that the specific actions taken are always calm.
Because sometimes people might, due to disgust and hatred,
give up choices that are actually beneficial to themselves.
We see many people now walking into dead ends, right?
They can't find something that convinces them.
a collective narrative that people are willing to invest in
along with the trend of personal growth
it's also challenging to achieve in this era
we've gone over this many times
logically speaking
this is the time to focus on yourself
to find some affordable fun
make some friends
make life a bit easier, right
This should clearly be a better choice.
But some things that could broaden the horizons of life
Make one more relaxed and happier
And cost relatively less, are locked away by oneself.
Many people think live houses are just noise.
They believe bars are full of unsavory characters
Who come to get drunk and flirt.
They look down on these activities.
They consider cycling and outdoor activities to be bourgeois.
It's fake
They don't truly love themselves
They disdain even touching it
Then, can't they at least have a relationship?
No, they can't
Why are they held back by so many things again?
They wonder if they might be deceived
If their feelings might be used to scam money
Can it last a lifetime?
Do you have the ability to take responsibility for the other person?
Women get tired of men
think men are all greasy and disgusting
men are all tired of women
think women are all materialistic and calculating
both sides feel there are too few normal people
can't even talk a bit
then you watch a film
watching literature works, right?
It won't work either
Because there are so many things with skewed values
I have to guard against cultural infiltration
I also have to watch out for the director and author slipping in their personal agendas
In the end, it’s a big detour
Trapped in life, unable to move
Stuck in place
I can only play some games
Let's watch the video.
Still, we watch with a critical eye
Watch with a critical eye
And often get quite upset by the plot or some award
Easily falling into a new community of shared resentment
This is the current state of young people today
Feeling a bit boxed in from all sides
Such individuals find themselves stuck between life and their own beliefs
From a broader perspective
It reflects the overall society we are in
It's neither up nor down
It's stuck in the middle
If we're being rational
everyone can understand
from a long-term societal perspective
it's hard for a society to have it all, right?
it's difficult to achieve rapid growth
without environmental damage
and maintain high social mobility
The benefits are also high
This applies to any country
However, the awkward part is
We might now be in a somewhat opposite situation
The costs that should have been paid have already been incurred
And due to inertia, these costs will continue
Or this cost has been passed on to the younger generation.
But the benefits haven't arrived yet
For instance, it hasn't reached a high-welfare state yet
Liquidity has already decreased
Infrastructure investment is still increasing
The era of major maintenance has arrived
Hard technology is still catching up
We are still in the process of industrial structure transformation
County towns and new rural areas
The construction of new rural areas hasn't been around for long
The unique financial industry found in big cities
Internet companies are no longer hiring
including the lifestyle of the middle class
the middle-class culture has yet to be established
the middle-class is almost disappearing
do you think these issues will eventually be resolved
I believe they will
history always progresses in a spiral
but the problem is that changes over the past few years have been too rapid
imagine for a moment
if you were born in 2000
When you first started college
it seemed like housing prices would keep soaring indefinitely
and the old Chinese stocks were still overheated
young people were still taking out online loans
and spending in advance
but by the time you graduated, no one was starting businesses anymore
everyone was thinking about living a FIRE life in third- or fourth-tier cities
this rapid shift
has imposed a cost that should have been spread over generations
There's also this ideological shift that needs to be digested
Let a generation focus on consuming it.
This is what the post-00s and post-05s face
Including perhaps some of the post-95s who are enchanted by the magical UI
A reality that hits without warning
When we delve deeper into this
The multi-faceted nature of the physical world and real life
It is also reflected in ideology or mental outlook.
It embodies something quite peculiar and unique.
I often feel that the new generation is wearing the skin of pre-modernity.
while using a postmodern core to counter modernity, which might be hard to grasp
it's like everyone is engaging in this weird and wacky spiritual cosplay
this kind of differentiated self-actualization
personal narrative
seems great
but it requires an economic foundation
it needs a certain level of inner inclusiveness and openness
and the same goes for society
It requires a certain level of aesthetic and knowledge.
So for young people,
He might seem like a Moon in the Water.
Thus, another way to make oneself feel better
is to deconstruct modern life.
Since I can't have it,
I use various methods to convince myself
that I don't want it.
Therefore, some people choose to retreat back to
Pre-modern moral norms
including those traditional norms
criticize the hypocrisy and emptiness of modern life
people lack the virtues of the past
social morals are declining
critiques of modern life
some criticisms of modern society may hold true
but ultimately, it's a form of cosplay
for contemporary youth
I'll be blunt.
I absolutely don’t want to go back to the pre-modern era.
Whether it’s the arranged marriages in personal relationships,
or the uniform distribution,
or the cultural and aesthetic uniformity,
if these were to really happen,
no one could endure it.
So behind the anger of the new generation
what we see is frustration and disappointment.
Behind their aggressive words lies a sense of self-defense.
This then forms a kind of large-scale, collective avoidance.
Let's talk about attachment styles here.
I feel that I've shared most of what I've observed over the past two years.
I've pretty much described and analyzed the prevailing mental state of our times.
This is something I've really wanted to do.
I'm taking the opportunity of the year-end review in 2024,
I'd like to share some of my thoughts with you all seriously.
and some of my thoughts
This process was quite challenging.
Writing the script also took a considerable amount of time.
Because the topics we discussed were quite broad.
I can only share my perspective from the corner of the world I've seen.
And perhaps in a rather limited way.
I'll try to elaborate on my personal understanding and descriptions.
Theoretically speaking,
After describing the phenomena and analyzing the causes,
we should then predict trends or propose solutions.
It formed a great self-media article
But I found myself struggling with it for a long time
That’s why this episode was also delayed for so long before being released
I realized I couldn’t do it
Because various issues were all converging at this moment
At this particular juncture, they intertwined
It became a mess
Trying to make sense of it was already a challenge
Let alone coming up with any reliable answers
I've been thinking about this for a long time.
I'll provide it for you at the end of the video.
A preliminary step to solve the problem.
The idea is to provide such a perspective.
It's about depersonalizing responsibility.
Just think about it.
Clocking in and out on time at any workplace in the world,
Working diligently,
Supporting one's parents.
Those who abide by the law
and pay their taxes
can be regarded as the pillars of society
and can enjoy life with a clear conscience
but in our case
this is what we call lying flat
if you think about it carefully
this is a seriously distorted situation
what is the truly reasonable approach
In such a situation
if we can't get what we want the most
we might as well lighten our load a bit
and it will feel better
Contemporary young people are generally under intense pressure, like being in a pressure cooker.
if you add more pressure
it will only lead to a systemic mental breakdown
in recent years, it has become somewhat like Japan
showing signs of a low-desire society from the past two decades
The path is very similar
Japan experienced a sharp decline in growth rates
Then the benefits for young people drastically decreased
But the pressure hasn't eased up
So individuals can only disconnect from society
To maintain inner peace
This generation of Japanese people
Several generations of Japanese have not been consuming
Not socializing
No dating
No having children
Nonviolence
Not cooperating, right?
This is the spirit of the Heisei generation
The mental state and behavioral logic
It's like that
So Japan has actually already demonstrated
Society doesn't actively exempt this generation from responsibility.
Then this generation will spontaneously accomplish this step.
And they will do so more resolutely.
So I believe that families and society,
schools and businesses,
including the content industry,
should gradually and broadly change,
This mainstream public opinion environment and emotional atmosphere
with less extreme positivity being instilled,
and less anxiety about urgency being promoted.
Less emphasis on fostering hatred
What everyone can see
What everyone can hear
Starting from elementary school
Every year of life is crucial
Fifth grade is the most critical
Sixth grade is the most important
Seventh grade is key, and eighth grade is crucial
Freshman year is pivotal
The crucial third year
The critical internship
Each year is pivotal in your career
There's no need to be constantly on edge throughout each year
There's an important prerequisite for this
It's about legitimizing showbiz
From ancient times to the present
We have always placed great emphasis on meaning
And on light entertainment
It's not even about belittling showbiz
but rather restricting and being wary of it
I always feel like if everyone just lets loose and has fun
things will get out of hand
and joy will turn to sorrow
and indulgence will lead to the loss of one's purpose
The Disintegration of Ritual and Music will occur
I think it's time to change this mindset
the modern entertainment industry is not just about
Shaping values and spreading positive energy
It is also crucial
A societal pressure valve and stabilizer
I truly believe this
Even mindless, low-quality joy and relaxation
Is better than anxiety, hatred, and mutual attacks
And self-deprecation
These things are worse
Of course, we don’t need to be like South Korea
Cultural entertainment as a national pillar
That's not necessary
But it can certainly justify the entertainment industry
With algorithms
Regulation can reduce some of the hate
And lessen the adversarial nature
Then provide a lot more high-quality entertainment products
Because on the surface, it seems that there's an oversupply of content in Simplified Chinese
But this illusion hides what's truly engaging
It sounds good
It looks good
but not vulgar
and not flat
There's too little content with esthetic value and practical significance.
To put it bluntly, there are too few productions like Black Myth: The Long Season
Going a step further, even fewer works like Film Hurricane and Uncle Bing
So we should vigorously develop the cultural and entertainment industry
On a personal micro level, we also need to promote a culture of quality
And this step might be even harder
because after prolonged PUA
sometimes even when external pressure is gone
one still needs to put some pressure on oneself
or it feels uncomfortable all over
This is a kind of inertia
On the surface
it seems that many young people are now waking up
taking the initiative to reduce their responsibilities
However, my observation is
that deep down
many people still see this as a form of rebellion, a way to overturn the table
they still hope I'll overturn the table
Huiwen stops me
and gives me some fatherly love
but those who can truly stand up for themselves
and openly take responsibility are few
like the girl who loves cats that Vans mentioned before, right
Often mocked by young so-called new males against feminists
But if you think about it carefully
What's the real issue with being childless and loving cats?
The men who make such mocking remarks
Many of them are also cat lovers, right?
One shouldn’t choose a woman who loves cats without flowers
Instead of being an ordinary person
Loving harmless cats, is that wrong?
This is what I call the half-covered responsibility avoidance
Treating the abdication of responsibility as a tool
rather than genuinely accepting one's own responsibility
Many people feel the pressure is just too overwhelming
My mental state has completely fallen apart
but on the other hand
the lingering effects of previous emotional manipulation still echo in their minds
the aftereffects are still present
they can't bring themselves to accept who they are
to truly accept themselves
To de-responsibilize
Accepting oneself
Keep those things out
So in terms of behavior
The language becomes very twisted and awkward
They think one thing but curse at the same time
This is what I referred to as a grand exhibition of avoidant attachment
So I feel that one thing we can do
Is to work on separating various issues
Separate marriage from romantic relationships
Separate childbearing from marriage
Separate personal growth from the gains and losses of the company
Separate power and status from dignity
Separate the fun times with friends from long-term companionship
Even in extreme cases
If the family of origin is truly terrible
I think for some people
It’s possible to separate financial support from emotional connection
Doing this seems to come with all sorts of issues.
Because from a mature perspective,
it's impossible to avoid responsibility for a lifetime, right?
No problem.
You definitely have to take on some responsibilities.
And from a societal standpoint,
if you don't take responsibility,
someone else will have to step up.
For example, if no one chooses to have children,
Overall, we will face a significant population issue.
There needs to be someone to take on the role.
However, even so,
I still firmly believe in the need to reduce responsibility.
Why?
Because from an individual's perspective,
A person's mental space is limited.
A person's inner world,
if overwhelmed by anxiety and stress,
Responsibility has completely taken over
If it’s fully occupied
he is actually in a state of internal depletion
his psychological resilience will be very low
his state will become very numb
I’ve noticed in recent years
many people appear calm on the surface
but inside they’re like pressure cookers
As I mentioned earlier
I looked up a piece of data
an authoritative statistic published by the Chinese Academy of Sciences in 2022
the authoritative report
indicated the detection rates for depression and anxiety among college students
were 21.48%
and 45.28%, respectively
with an average prevalence of mental disorders at 22.8%
which is already quite high
but now, two years later
I reckon he might grow even taller
In this state
it's hard for a person to develop
even if you feel pressured by external factors and moral standards
to take responsibility
you lack the mental capacity to do so
so it's necessary to first relieve the burden of responsibility
and restore your sense of self-worth
and regain a sense of self-sufficiency
A relaxed mental state and vitality
This allows us to create mental space to embrace responsibility and truly take it on.
You have the space to do such things
So this is my answer that isn't quite an answer
If you can find a job
that provides a basic guarantee for your personal survival
And fortunately
for various reasons
you have something you like and are passionate about
even if it's a bit vague
In such a situation
you can explore different practices to find your own
better solution that I mentioned earlier
which is a differentiated self-actualization narrative
Another scenario is
if your current situation is difficult
and you can't find this personal narrative
I suggest you don't put additional pressure on yourself
Get rid of the clutter in your mind
the external pressures
imposed on you
by others
Including, if necessary
cutting off toxic relationships
It's worth it
Focus less on
Follow the grand and distant things
Stop blaming yourself
Stop attacking others and venting righteous anger
These things won't bring you happiness
It doesn't bring about Mental Spaces
or add value
First, focus on your immediate environment
handle specific tasks
improve your living conditions
get rid of the burdens and responsibilities on your shoulders
then see if you can find something else
This is all I can offer
It might be considered a barely acceptable answer.
I think it's hard to fight against the tide of the times
The video's conclusion, however, isn't particularly optimistic.
I'll talk about something that left a deep impression on me
something that made me happy
At the beginning of 2021
I was invited to attend a closed-door event for Thirteen Yao
Those familiar with me might know
Thirteen Yao is a dialogue program I've always loved
At the event
I met the production team of Thirteen Yao
I met Zhiyuan Xu
Then Zhiyuan Xu, as rumored, had a drink
his face turned red
Then we, more than ten people
including media representatives
bloggers
had a chat with Zhiyuan Xu
and the Thirteen Yao production team
sitting in a circle
Zhiyuan Xu said
why the world needs culture
art, and philosophy
why we need a humanistic spirit
Because in the spiritual world
in the realm of humanities, there are many paths
so people don't have to
squeeze onto the same narrow path
push each other aside
pull each other back
There's no need to run and fight on that narrow path
This statement left a deep impression on me
I've remembered it for years
At the time, I was in a particularly unique phase of my personal life
His words provided me with significant mental comfort
I'm also sending this to you, the viewers, at the end of 2024
So, by the end of 2024, we'll also be sending this to all of you who watch the videos.
That's about it for this video
That's about it for this video.
in my New Year's message video in 2023, I said
In my New Year's message video in 2023, I said
It will be live on New Year's Eve night.
So, I've reflected on the past two videos as well.
A lot of room for improvement
Enjoys sharing various perspectives and insights about oneself
an UPloader who shares ideas, observations, and thoughts
See you in the next video.