Friends,
I'm currently in Zhengzhou, Henan Province.
This is a place called Only Henan Fantasy City.
It's said to be a well-designed scenic area.
There are several well-organized performances inside.
I'm here to participate in
an event called Travel Transformation over the next few days.
During the day, we'll be experiencing what the park has to offer.
All sorts of attractions within the scenic area.
It's said that tonight
there will be a debate related to the daytime activities
but I have no idea what it’s about
I find this format quite novel
so I’ll check in first
and then start this journey
today we’ll tour all the attractions
we’ve arrived at the Only Henan Fantasy City Theater
and the staff just told me that this area is 100 acres
They really grow grain
Because Henan is one of the cradles of civilization
It's this wheat and sorghum that have nurtured our Chinese civilization
So now, this season should be for wheat
And today, we'll be at this grand venue
To watch all kinds of performances
Let's go and see today
Great, awesome
His hand
Bling bling
Spring
That feels so good
So, it's recommended that people don't sit in the first row
Then, sitting further back can help you avoid these issues
It happens
That's the self-blaming guy
I have a great older brother
You're messing with me on this
Did you get it working?
Let's do it this way.
Point to this like this.
Point to this while facing the camera.
And then?
Then smile at the camera.
The scene this afternoon seems quite complicated.
He said the three major scenes are packed with information.
The crew said let the wind blow.
This is not quite what I expected.
It's like a planetarium, with a surround view.
Our story should start with this person.
My name is Li 18.
I lived in 1942.
I was the station master at the railway station.
I have 47 minutes and 38 seconds left to live.
This is the first scene.
The play at the railway station theater.
He talked about a tragic story between brothers
Li Eleven and Li Eighteen
during the great famine in Henan in 1942
where the younger brother, Li Eighteen, was a guard at the grain warehouse
while the older brother, Li Eleven, was at a dead end
acting on behalf of the starving villagers to ask for seeds
Due to their different roles
the older brother essentially caused his younger brother's death
The plot of this scene is profound
And it possesses a strong dramatic conflict
At the same time, there are some thoughtful designs in the expression
For instance, it features a 360-degree circular theater
It employs a unique montage technique
In the train station scene
A net is used to convey the oppressive feeling brought by the starving people
It allows me to emotionally experience what hunger truly means
The horror of turning humans into ghosts
Dude, what can you do?
What are you doing?
What am I doing?
If you want the seeds, you'll have to trade my brother's life for them.
But without the seeds,
these people won't survive.
What am I doing?
Heaven above,
how could you be so cruel?
How are you doing? Are you okay?
Li, come out.
Come out quickly.
Li Shi Yin
Everyone's here.
Li
We know there's food in the house.
Come out, we're hungry.
Everyone's here.
Sure.
The second scene takes place in Lijiacun village.
It actually follows the story at the train station.
This scene is incredibly emotionally charged.
Many people were moved to tears on set.
It’s even a bit suffocating.
In this scene, the older brother Li brings back
the grain he obtained by trading his younger brother’s life.
After that,
He couldn’t let the villagers eat it
because it had to be used as seeds for planting
so that the whole village could survive next year
So the older generation of villagers in Li Family Village
collectively went to the nearby mountain and froze to death
leaving the chance to live for the next generation
This story is a bit too heavy
it’s making me feel a bit suffocated
What about this play?
Ultimately, it reinforced and elevated the Henan people's obsession with Empress Liu
It's not just about continuing the lineage for a small family
but also on a larger scale
a sacrifice made for the continuation of the Chinese nation
Oh heavens
have mercy
send a heavy snowfall
to poison us all
Actually, I think the background music is really well done
I feel like throwing up every time that suona starts playing.
As soon as the suona sounds,
my tears start to flow.
The old man's tears start to fall right away.
The second act is great.
Both the first and second acts are excellent.
He has already formed a complete story structure.
Actually, it can be said that
this part actually feels more like a story than the previous one.
Because it's simpler
He explained it more thoroughly
There are far fewer flaws
Yes, yes, yes
Who's looking for me? I'm Kǒng Qiū
What do you want with me?
It's not that I have something
It's these later generations talking about Confucius and Lǎozi
That is, you and I met in Luoyi, Henan
They said I should discuss some issues with you.
The third scene has a very different atmosphere.
It's a grand visual spectacle.
This scene actually answers a question.
If Henan was once known for its grain production,
grain production was what Henan was known for,
now our grain supply is no longer scarce.
What else can Henan represent beyond its grain production?
He uses a time-travel story to explore this.
Throughout history,
Henan's cultural luminaries have been gathered in the same time and space,
I think it's a bit showy,
like reciting a list of dishes,
but Henan's ancestors were indeed quite affluent,
poets, philosophers,
painters,
statesmen,
there are dozens of famous figures known throughout China.
It's still a feast for the eyes with substance.
It's done.
It turned into a sigh.
The battle scene was painted into this picture.
It's the Riverside Scene at Qingming Festival.
The Riverside Scene at Qingming Festival.
I hope you're satisfied with how you look in the painting.
It's alright.
The three scenes together gave me the strongest impression of professionalism.
Especially the first two scenes, which are so heavy and emotionally challenging.
They can easily put too much pressure on the audience.
Making it hard to watch.
And not very appealing,
But only in Henan, this place,
I feel that the creative principles are more respected.
The dramatic arrangement is excellent.
It’s highly complete and also includes some clever designs and ideas.
At the same time, it uses a constantly changing scene to create an immersive experience.
to enhance the sense of immersion
I think we need this high-level
comprehensive content product for historical education
we spent a day together in the Theater of Only Henan today
we watched several performances together
and learned about the disasters that occurred in the past
we watched three performances during the day
next, we'll debate topics related to the performances we saw during the day
specifically, the debate topic related to the Henan famine of 1942
One of the debate topics we drew is whether, when reflecting on hardships, one should be immersed in them or stand outside of them.
The question is whether one should be involved in the suffering or remain detached from it.
We are the affirmative side.
I will be the fourth speaker for the affirmative side.
You need to pay attention to me too.
I can do it.
I need to guard against you accusing me of agreeing.
But it is precisely because of social norms,
that the overall trust cost in society is reduced.
Everyone tends to think more about themselves
I'll still go over that initial point
We only set the rules
Dare you explain why this question is valid
Why it has become a debate topic
It highlights the emergence of this social phenomenon
We need to reflect on past hardships
Because of moral
We have entered a phase similar to a past hardship
In similar social contexts
or there's a risk
that something like this could draw us into the scenario
then I proceed to construct
why
because the first three have already
been established
to explain what value we can derive from it
I'll extend it further
I think we can approach it this way.
I've come to terms with the hardships of the past.
I've let them all go.
I stand outside the situation.
But that doesn't mean I don't act in the present.
It doesn't mean I'm indifferent to the suffering I see.
Or the hardships others might face in the future.
I won't hesitate to lend a helping hand.
These are two different things.
But what you're doing at this point is definitely wrong.
For example, I can give specific instances.
Like many people who haven't interacted with food delivery riders,
assume that helping them means buying insurance for them.
But if you have interacted with them,
you'd realize that none of them want to buy a phone.
If they don't want to spend money on it every day,
I know, I get it.
But his intention is good.
To put it bluntly, if you really want to help others,
you need to be understood by them.
Then, all the roles you play,
all the people you need to experience firsthand,
in order to help this rider,
what triggers it,
but what exactly is it?
I get it, I understand.
It means a person has so many things to do in their lifetime.
This family is writing down their memories
This article tells me whether I should lose the child or save the bear
He is perfect
Just
At that time, shouldn't we have had one
We should have a complete understanding of the world
There's also a preface that says
Suppose I have 100 dollars
Who should I save
It's just about helping the disaster area.
Or should we save the endangered animals, or the six gods?
Who is he referring to?
So it only affects your career and life.
That's having emotions, isn't it?
There must be current feelings.
Otherwise, it just means you have no issues.
You can manage to do things.
You might face it with joy.
I think you can tell the difference.
Let's rank them by value.
Let's say he is a 100, someone who should be rescued.
You are a 99, or an 18.
Here, I'll explain the rules for those who are not familiar with debates.
Let me explain the rules.
This postal debate format is relatively simplified.
There's no cross-examination.
No team free debate or other such rounds.
So, the actual competition format is
the first, second, and third debaters from both sides take turns to present their arguments
interspersed with rebuttal rounds where the first, second, and third debaters face off against each other
followed by the fourth debater concluding the debate
finally, the judges vote to decide the winner and provide comments
Hello everyone
I am the first debater for the affirmative side, Xiao Hong
my English name is Little Red
it’s great to meet all of you
Thanks for the benefits, everyone.
Little r
Hello everyone.
I am the second debater for the affirmative side, Grape.
My English name is Grape.
Hello everyone.
I am the third debater for the affirmative side, Yang Zijiang.
My English name is River.
I've seen everyone here.
I'm Old Jiang.
My English name is Reliable.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha
I'd like to ask you a question.
Were you just projecting your dislike of Huang Shengyi onto that man?
But I analyze this issue as
Because I have moved past the pain from my original family
You've moved beyond your own pain.
But you haven't moved on from the pain of Huang Shengyi.
Why should I care about his pain?
Because you look like Yang Zi.
Let me ask you another question.
Have you ever heard of sanitary pads that cost ten yuan for thirty pieces?
I have.
Then someone asked, ‘Hey’,
‘Why do you buy such cheap sanitary pads? They can't be good.’
Guess what the comments below say?
You'd think everyone would say, ‘Oh, these sanitary pads really aren't good.’
Why did you buy it?
You should explain to them.
The woman said she has difficulties.
Because you don’t know her difficulties.
So you would say why you have difficulties using this sanitary pad.
I should know better, right?
The difficulty he mentioned is financial.
It’s not about the usage.
Alright, let’s move on to the summary.
Zheng Tao three hundred
Everyone, pay attention to the timing
I think both sides have wasted a lot of time talking about
Whose suffering this is
You keep talking about your own suffering
This question isn't about your own suffering
We can't stand outside and reflect on our own suffering
This question is about someone else's suffering
And why
It's because it has value.
Two aspects of value.
The first one I also see in Jianren Si.
What I watch the most is the foreign community.
What exactly is the issue with prostitution?
I don't care if he's bad.
But how is his moral framework constructed?
How is morality constructed?
It's about how we navigate two dilemmas in a difficult environment.
We put this person in
and also that person on a scale
you go and measure
we go through the trouble of pondering and weighing
only then do we build our inner value system
Mailing doesn't have the ability to measure this
First, second
he doesn't have the ability to place another on the scale
he can only place himself on the scale
He doesn't have that capability.
So he can't be a fully moral being.
So he is bad and he is foolish.
If we could have such an ability,
to watch a lot of film and television from a young age,
what is its value?
It immerses you in such a scenario,
allowing you to safely empathize,
with someone else's dilemma.
Empathize with others' suffering
Empathize with others' past suffering
This cultivates your moral capacity
That's one aspect
The other is that I want to dismantle their trap
They keep saying
It's like empathizing with suffering
It's as if you have to empathize emotionally
That's completely wrong
I choose not to bring in emotions
What I care about is the situation
What I bring in is the situation
What was mentioned earlier is personal values
Now, I'm talking about public values
So why should our society encourage people
to consider others' situations more
Why
is it because if you don't empathize
You won't be able to make any correct decisions.
So, a while back,
I read a book called 'Why They Kill',
it's about an American sociologist,
named Ronni,
the specifics of the name aren't important,
anyway,
his research focuses on why there are so many violent criminals,
why they go around killing people.
People form gangs
Why was it him who achieved revolutionary results in the end
He grew up in a community filled with violence
His father was a violent man
He has already made a revolutionary achievement
It means that violent criminals are not inherently twisted from a young age
But rather, they make rational choices
Violence is his rational choice
Why is it a rational choice
Because he was subjected to various forms of violence from a young age
he felt a sense of powerlessness inside
his sense of order was shattered
he needs to rebuild the order just as he established it
the only power and order he knows is brute force
so we can use this process to help alleviate the situation
to prevent this from happening
why is this possible
because we can only achieve it by immersing ourselves in it
We need to understand his situation.
We need to see the solution.
And the one who was just mentioned, Teacher Yao, right?
Teacher Yao.
He just made a mistake by not joining the flag team.
He proposed a very incorrect statement.
Regarding this issue.
It's because there was no dry ice.
It's because dry ice wasn't available in that era.
So it seems that social resources are limited
But the issue of limited social resources
Exists in every era
What really needs to be addressed is
In situations where social resources are extremely scarce
How to prevent political issues from exacerbating disasters
It's because he hasn't put himself in the context
He takes a highly technical and rational perspective
He speaks from a very detached position
You have dry ice, don't you?
But the person involved isn't here.
So, what problem are we trying to solve?
I mean, how did the current famine come about?
There's enough food to feed the entire world.
It's due to political and distribution issues.
This was precisely the issue faced in 1942.
It's possible for the world's population to survive.
You need to get involved.
This is what drives social progress.
Do I still have time?
321 hahaha
Big brother, you stepped right on it!
So, combining the audience votes, nine votes go to the affirmative side.
Five votes to the negative side.
Congratulations to the affirmative side.
Then, the two panel judges also voted for the fourth speaker of the affirmative side.
Old Jia, congratulations, well done.
Everyone, let's stand for now.
We'll announce the rules for tomorrow's game shortly.
I've just finished the debate.
Today has been a very fulfilling day.
It's quite late now.
We visited Only Henan Fantasy City.
We watched three grand performances.
The shows were incredibly rich and diverse.
And in the evening, we had a debate related to this.
I think the last one is quite simple.
It's about everyone recommending that people buy tickets to watch.
With this money, you can see three high-quality performances.
Highly original ones,
even with techniques,
like innovative plays.
And they are closely related to us Chinese.
We inherit these skills and techniques.
Only then do we know who we are.
Anyway, if you have the chance, go and see it.
And then there's the debate.
Debating is something I really enjoy.
This is actually my
fourth or fifth debate experience, strictly speaking.
I've been thinking about why I enjoy debating so much.
While debating today,
I was thinking about why I'm willing to invest time and effort
and keep coming back.
There isn't much financial incentive, you know.
Debating is something
that gives me a sense of the charm of offline expression.
I might have tens of thousands of views on my online videos,
and there are comments and feedback in the comment section,
but it's still just a number.
But with offline expression, I'm actually a lover of it.
I'm not very used to
talking confidently in front of a large group of people.
I prefer more intimate conversations.
But these moments make me feel very stimulated
and excited.
There's a kind of excitement that you don't get from online expression.
Also, when you're forced to express yourself in front of so many people,
the feedback you get when you enter that flow state is overwhelming.
You get very clear and direct feedback,
even from just thirty or forty audience members.
You know for sure
that they are captivated by my arguments,
convinced by my points,
and listening to me attentively.
What I say influences their thoughts and feelings.
This is a great sense of value and achievement.
This is one of the unique charms of debating.
This is why I love debating.
So, that's it. I think this event is very valuable.
And I really enjoyed it.
If there are friends out there
who like to watch me debate
or are interested in following this event,
you can follow me on January 11th
as I participate in this novice debate competition, hehe,
the New National Debate Masters Tournament.
I'm Liang Qiuyang.
Our team will be debating two very interesting topics.
And on January 19th,
I will continue to participate
in the UPloader performance match of the New National Debate for the third consecutive year.
Alright, let's wrap it up and celebrate!
You saw how that criticism just cooled down the atmosphere I had heated up.
I came down and froze it.
But there's nothing I can do about it.
I just know how to move.
That's it.
This is the exterior