to do a review of their AI Super Box.
So, I'll be a bit more practical.
I might as well connect it with a few real-life tasks I need to handle recently.
to see how much it can actually help me solve this issue.
So, what’s the latest feature update from Quark?
It’s called Deep Search.
The design concept behind this feature is quite interesting.
Search isn’t new to AI anymore.
I’ve been using AI search for about a year now.
So, how does Quark’s Deep Search actually perform in use?
The experience really highlights distinct differences.
In my view,
Quark’s deep search is a combination of an agent and search functionality,
integrated with deep thinking.
When you ask Quark’s AI deep search a question,
it follows a three-step process.
The first step is to determine what you need to search for.
In this step,
Quark breaks down the problem much like a real exam question,
analyzing your actual needs.
It involves judging your search intent
Breaking down the question into several specific search points
I personally think this step is very human-like
I've always felt that
I've also made a video before about how to conduct research.
I've deeply pondered this issue
I've always believed the hardest part of research
May not be the specific search phase
Nor is it necessarily the final phase of organizing and summarizing to form insights
The most crucial initial step is how to formulate a good question
If you bring it up
the research is already halfway to success
but the paradox lies in where
many good questions in specialized fields
require a certain amount of information to be raised
but before you start searching
that information doesn't exist
so this leads to the research
the initial stage of searching being relatively challenging
especially for newcomers
For those who are relatively inexperienced in conducting surveys
This is also one of the main reasons
that makes in-depth research quite challenging
Quark’s innovative approach of breaking down vague questions into
specific and detailed sub-questions for in-depth searches
can significantly reduce the difficulty for ordinary people to conduct research
essentially simplifying the most challenging part for you
This step also sets Quark apart from other deep thinking
models in a significant way
making Quark’s search function more effective
The planning aspect is noticeably better.
The second step is how to search and where to search.
This step's foundation is similar to other AI tools.
But there are two differences.
The first one is that
Quark relies on high-quality sources from Alibaba.
This is a prerequisite for AI to provide reliable answers.
It can reduce the high hallucination rate of large models at the source.
I've mentioned in my previous videos
the high hallucination rate.
Actually, it hinders the current large models from becoming more practical.
It's a significant obstacle.
It can resolve part of the issue.
This point is crucial in many areas involving health, finance, and other critical aspects of life.
Only with a low hallucination rate can you trust it.
It’s reliable.
You’d dare to use it, right?
Another difference is that Quark doesn’t just perform searches in a rigid manner.
Instead, it’s based on Alibaba’s self-developed large model.
Adjust the search content dynamically based on analytical reasoning
This is actually quite similar to how humans think.
We do indeed search while
adjusting our search logic based on further information.
It's quite flexible.
The third step is deep thinking.
Which involves reasoning and fitting based on the search content.
Ultimately generating an answer.
The advantages of deep thinking have been experienced by many people.
I wonder if you've had this experience.
Apart from improving search quality,
it also allows users to see the AI’s thought process,
which helps better understand the issues.
My experience is
sometimes you can even discover some underlying intentions in your questions
by
examining the AI’s deep thinking process,
intentions that even you didn’t realize you had.
I didn’t know my questions had this underlying meaning,
but the AI picked it up.
This is indeed the case.
So, after comprehensive testing,
this methodology involves multiple mechanisms and processes,
while also being reliable in sourcing information,
it ranks absolutely first,
and the results align closely with user needs.
It can conduct very specific information searches,
as well as handle some rather vague,
and more complex daily life issues.
Now, I'll proceed to test a few scenarios.
These are all based on my actual living needs recently.
The first scenario was a few days ago when I participated in a debate in Guangzhou.
One of the topics I debated was about abstract culture.
Whether it is a poison or an antidote for the youth.
Our side argued that it is an antidote.
I wanted to see if Quark could help with the preparation.
First, I asked him to break down the topic.
To see if there could be some inspiration in terms of approach.
After asking Quark this question,
We saw that Quark took the first step.
He didn't start with a search.
Instead, he thought about the problem before searching.
He assessed the purpose of my search for this question.
Then he broke it down into several sub-questions.
For instance, in this question,
Kuake thought through it and
This broke down one of my major issues into five perspectives.
The first perspective,
for example, is the abstraction of culture,
the pathway of change from subculture to mainstream culture
The second one is to look into the psychological mechanisms of humor.
And the neuroscientific basis as well.
Then, investigate how teenagers use this abstract culture.
For identity construction, looking at research cases.
Also, gather some social case studies.
Including exploring postmodern culture.
I think these perspectives are quite good.
Some of them are even something I haven’t fully grasped.
I didn’t think of them at the very beginning.
So moving forward, as I mentioned,
He embarked on a genuine search.
Some of the web pages he searched.
Then, with his previous thoughts in mind.
These searches were also quite targeted.
Finally, he presented some results.
First of all,
I see this as the origin and development trajectory of abstract culture.
This part I found a bit challenging to grasp.
Because seeing someone like Yao Shui Ge and Chen Yi being so serious,
When they appear in the answers.
I feel there's something quite intriguing about it.
So, I'll get straight to the point.
I'll talk about the standout points among these.
For instance, in the breakdown of the debate topic and the theoretical framework,
I think they stand out quite a bit.
He talks about the solution, which is our actual stance,
What could be the core arguments?
One is the humorous stress-relief function,
This was played out in the debate.
Another is building a resilient social ecosystem.
There wasn't a direct hit
but it was mentioned
And it represents a postmodern resistance and reconstruction
This point was also truly brought up on the field
He pointed out that the opposing side's point about this toxic abstract culture
The side arguing for the toxic element
He suggested that the opposition might say
This abstract culture is not the antidote
But rather a numbing agent
What we actually put forward on the field was
I remember the side of Chen Ming and Luo Miao
They said abstract culture is a drug
not a cure
That's the point
Also, this abstract culture
leads to the dilution of entertainment and values
as well as generational conflicts and cultural fragmentation
Then he went on to predict some battlefields of attack and defense
including suggestions for the opposition's preparation strategies and so on
a series of answers
I think this answer is quite useful for reference.
So after the test,
I believe this question can provide some assistance.
Additionally, in the debate, there will certainly be a focus on this.
covert defense and offense.
For instance, our side argues that abstract culture can bring joy.
Since we consider it a remedy,
we will certainly provide examples that bring immediate happiness.
Positive and uplifting content,
examples of such abstract culture.
But the other side will definitely mention the particularly repugnant aspects of abstract culture
The disgusting ones
Those that violate public morals and good customs
On this issue
I also need Qu to help me search for some cases
Gather a few
Examples that might assist us in our arguments on the field
Qu still follows the three-step approach
As you can see
This problem breakdown
Then search
Then engage in deep thinking
Finally, give me an answer
So, to cut a long story short in this answer
I think there are at least two things
that we can truly put to use
One is that a platform turned the abstract into a selected term last year
as its platform's annual keyword
This point is useful for us
We indeed applied it to some extent in the field
Another point is
to view the chaotic behavior of young people
as a form of deconstruction and rebellion
which is also a more positive example
This is about how it's used in a debate setting
Though this is a bit of hindsight, right?
We didn't have Quark when we were debating
But looking back, it’s worth evaluating
what Quark provided is still useful
So what is the second life scenario?
It's a pet
I have a Maine Coon cat
I've had it for many years
His name is Guai
He is four years old now
I can show everyone
Super duper handsome
Oh, we've brought our naughty one over
Guai is really handsome
Maine Coons are the largest domestic cats in the world
But our cat
Our cat has been eating raw meat and bones since it was a kitten
Especially vigorous
It weighs about 22 pounds
I think that's a bit exaggerated
I know Maine Coons are quite large
But I didn't realize
If this weight is overweight
And whether it needs to lose weight
Regarding this issue
Let's ask Quark
He seems a bit upset
Because he was sleeping just now
And I dragged him over
Uh-huh
It's good to let it go
Regarding this issue
He'll start by thinking it through
And everyone is already quite familiar with it
A three-step approach
Then proceed with the search.
Then dive into a deep search, right?
The answer he gave was quite subtle.
It's about the size of an adult male cat.
Their weight typically ranges from 12 to 25 pounds.
But ours weighs 22 pounds.
He said it's at the upper end of the normal range for male cats.
So while it's a bit heavy,
it's not necessarily abnormal.
So he suggested I get some tests done.
Using a scientific approach
which is to see if you can clearly feel the ribs
whether there's no excess fat in the abdomen
and if the waistline is well-defined
So after my testing
I felt it all over
and I could feel the ribs
quite easily
but there is excess fat in the abdomen
and a bit of sagging
So I think it might be slightly overweight
but close to the normal range
and he also gave a body condition score
which is BCS
If time permits, I would follow up with Quark
to ask what exactly this BCS is
and how I can learn about it
But that's all for this demo video
But that's all for our demonstration video.
Including the choice of your cat's food
And how to enhance its exercise on a daily basis
The management of exercise
Also provided some suggestions for monitoring and adjustments
Finally, a summary was given
I think it's quite useful
Going forward, I might indeed encourage Guai Guai a bit more
For instance, slightly controlling its diet
Because eating raw meat from a young age has indeed made its frame a bit larger
And more importantly, ensuring it gets more exercise every day
It just lies there every day.
Spending the whole day doing that.
Actually, it's not very healthy.
There's another question about cats.
Maine Coons, this breed of cat, are quite brave.
And they are relatively more adaptable.
Able to adjust to the external environment.
So it's possible to train a domestic Maine Coon to go out and play.
There's a good chance of success.
I really envy those who can take their cats for walks.
But the amount of training for our pet from a young age wasn't enough.
When we take it out, it gets scared.
Sometimes it even shows mild signs of stress.
So I asked Quark.
Let's see what kind of answer Quark can provide.
Now let's look at the agent's section.
In the first step,
it accurately identified
that this is a practical issue related to socialization training.
Then it proceeded with the search.
Engage in deep thinking
So, what did he come up with?
First, he taught me how to interpret the behavior patterns of our cat
When it goes outside
Show me how to understand
If there are any underlying issues with its behavior
Then he provided a scientific training plan
It covers a lot of aspects
Including sound desensitization
And tactile adaptation, among others
It's divided into several stages
It's roughly divided into four stages
Then proceed gradually with desensitization
To carry out speaking practice
He also provided some key points to note
And an alternative option
Well, Shanghai is about to enter summer
Which is a good time to take your cat out
It's a season with relatively warm weather
I might follow this method and see how it goes
Can we add both summer and fall to the plan?
to groom our little one into someone others will envy,
someone we can proudly take out for a walk,
and it would be in a content and relaxed state,
I think life would be much more enjoyable.
And it would also bring a lot more joy to it itself.
The third search scenario is health-related.
This is a real situation,
I'm completely serious about this,
I wouldn't joke about something like this.
It was a condition my mom was diagnosed with towards the end of last year.
It's called macular degeneration.
This condition is not life-threatening at all.
However, if left untreated,
the doctor said there's a risk of blindness.
So, medical intervention is necessary.
That means surgery might be required.
I decided to use Quark to get some information first.
To understand what exactly macular degeneration is.
Fortunately, Quark does a great job breaking down the issues.
He broke it down into five questions as usual.
And I think he really got it, very accurately.
I just want to say that my understanding of medicine is not very strong.
I don't have professional knowledge.
He needs to simplify the jargon into plain language.
No problem.
Then there's the search function.
Including deep thinking.
You can take a look at the AI's deep thinking process.
Some steps are involved.
In the end, it generated an educational document.
Firstly, what is macular degeneration?
Then, the common causes.
It's explained quite accurately.
My mom indeed has something similar to a degenerative condition.
It's due to her advanced age.
Her retina has undergone changes.
And it includes some typical symptoms.
These symptoms match my mom’s quite well.
The next step is how to diagnose it.
The next step is the treatment method.
Then, the sixth section is about prevention and daily management.
He provided some suggestions.
Including the differences among various types of macular degeneration.
In my opinion,
If it's not the case right now that,
My mom was just diagnosed with this condition.
I have already gained some understanding.
But if you’ve just found out you have this condition,
I think such a search result would be helpful.
will give me a preliminary understanding
which will be a great help in learning about the disease
so the next step is to continue asking her
my mom is scheduled to have surgery in early June
I will also return to Beijing
and I’ll ask Qwen as well
about what precautions should be taken before and after the surgery
these questions are definitely better asked to the doctor
but the doctor is very busy
and may not cover everything
Discuss these matters with our family members who are patients
So it’s definitely beneficial to do some research yourself first
Fortunately, in this issue
I’ve asked quite a number of questions, actually
And they are rather complex
Then I said I want a comprehensive recommendation, right?
He is still thinking it over
This comprehensive recommendation of mine
What I actually want
It breaks down into five points
One is that he needs to look up the surgery for macular pucker and holes.
The indications for the procedure.
The main success rates and complication data of the surgery.
Also, which ophthalmology hospitals in the country are considered good.
And the preoperative preparation and postoperative care.
Some important points to note about postoperative recovery.
As well as various protective measures.
After breaking down the issue, he then proceeded to conduct a thorough search.
He carried out a detailed search.
During the search process.
We can see Quark's unique advantages.
Quark is backed by Alibaba's authoritative database.
Alibaba's authoritative database
has strong advantages in two areas.
The first area is health and wellness.
The second area is academia.
When it comes to the medical issue I searched for,
Quark has a vast medical database.
It collaborates with over 60 medical institutions for content.
Moreover, it has a three-tier review process to enhance content quality.
The review mechanism
In terms of academic standards, it also has an E level
It collaborates with both domestic and international literature databases, including CNKI, Wanfang, and Weipu
Therefore, its search results are quite reliable
Let's see what it comes up with
After deep consideration by Quark
It provided several modules
The first module is treatment recommendations
The second module is the recommendation for ophthalmology hospitals.
The third module is about surgical risks
There are also complications
including preoperative precautions
postoperative care
care and follow-up
and lifestyle considerations
as well as the consequences of delayed surgery and other questions
This basically covers everything
It includes all the issues I mentioned
and even addresses some additional questions that might interest me
Quark’s response
After reading it carefully
After a thorough understanding
I immediately forwarded it to my mom
To help her with some issues regarding this illness
And the daily life concerns as well as pre-surgery preparations
Kuake will soon be rolling out Deep Search Pro
So what exactly is Deep Search Pro?
You can think of it as a deep research feature
It essentially treats your question
As a research project
Treat it as a project
In the end, it will generate a comprehensive project report
It is particularly suitable for those with extensive depth
Research questions with in-depth studies
So I look forward to Quark launching this feature soon
Next, let me show you a demonstration
Many people in the AI industry are saying
That 2025 is the Year of A-town
What I mean by that is the concept of an agent
It is very likely to evolve with the development of the AI industry
gradually becoming less ambiguous
and boundaries may completely disappear
it's highly likely that this agent thing will, in the coming years
move from specialized applications
I clearly know what an AI agent is
from such a state
it will merge into other AI tools
becoming a front-end feature
for example, it can be used in searches like this
including breaking down problems in AIGC
Go ahead and streamline the workflow in advance
turning it into a preliminary step
Regarding this update of Quark
it has introduced deep search for the first time in China
I think it's a very interesting and valuable exploration
The key is, it's also very practical
I recommend everyone give this feature a try.
I'm Lao Jiang
I'm someone who enjoys figuring things out
enjoys sharing their knowledge and insights
There's also an UPloader who thinks deeply like this.
This year, there will be many updates on the AI industry.
We'll explore industry trends.
Including some insightful thoughts.
And practical feature reviews and explanations.
If you find this episode useful,
inspiring,
Please give me a Triple Combo.
And follow me
See you in the next episode.