This year's theme is like this
Let me summarize
After watching it, it resonates with the widespread anxiety among young people.
A pervasive sense of anxiety.
And he mentioned a very scary term.
A state of being erased.
When it evolves to its extreme, it will be erased.
This video has also given me a lot of inspiration
Because at the beginning of the year, I actually did an episode on
Observations in Mid-2024.
Some of the points align with this.
However, that video discussed it from the perspective of society and the community.
I understand the generational dilemmas of young people.
Today, I want to shift the perspective.
I will discuss this issue entirely from an individual psychological viewpoint.
I've always believed that humans have two internal motivational systems.
One is desire or craving.
The other is fear.
Based on my observations over the years,
Actually, for our society,
Most people are actually driven by fear.
We live and act because of it.
There are so many things in life that are worth being afraid of, right?
We fear disappointing our teachers and parents.
We fear losing face.
We fear being blamed at work.
We fear losing our jobs.
We fear being alone and aging without companionship.
We fear being looked down upon.
fear of not being able to pay the mortgage and so on
both specific and vague ones exist
this kind of fear
has seeped deep into one's being
it becomes a pattern
an invisible tension that keeps people on edge
whispering in your ear constantly
to the point where you don’t even know what you’re afraid of anymore
but you just seem to fear yourself
The surroundings and the lifestyle
You can hardly describe
I don't have a deep understanding of this
Because I'm not the anxious type
But I do have a severe case of procrastination
Often, I don't even know what I'm putting off
You might say I often procrastinate when writing
But I dislike writing.
Dislike expressing yourself?
It's not that I don't love expressing myself
but I'm afraid I won't write well
I'm afraid I won't be able to write anything at all
so I keep putting it off and not doing it
putting it off
and thus the bad outcome never comes to light, right?
it will never come to pass
this fear of fear creates anxiety
and anxiety silently drains us
I
drain myself
lose my drive and independence
then it's toxic
many people are the same
I believe a lot of people can resonate with this
when you're in such an anxious predicament
you're not really doing much
but you feel exhausted
Many people's lives are like this
living in a vague and unfounded fear
and worry
constantly with a frown
so I've always felt that being driven by desire
might be better
at least that's what I thought 34 years ago
being driven by desire seems healthier
you develop a desire to take action
Then you go and satisfy that desire
And generate new desires
Create new cravings
Satisfying them forms a positive cycle
This is generally a good thing
But it's not always so simple
For example, in the show 'In the Name of the People'
The corrupt official in the first episode, right
His life could also be seen as driven by cravings
Why not?
He embezzled so much money.
But you're talking about this rampant, uncontrolled desire.
What did it bring him?
Definitely not something good.
So, overall,
Actually, both desire and fear can create positive feedback.
They are our biological instincts, after all.
They are our treasures.
One is seeking benefits
The other is avoiding harm
When they are specific
There's not much of an issue
But when desires and fears become abstract
That's when it becomes a problem
When I'm not afraid of the act of writing itself
But rather the abstract fear of possibly failing at writing
Or even being afraid of the fear itself
One hum is one, two is the second level
Fear of writing
One is the third level, fear of writing
This is a kind of abstract fear
Similarly, abstract desires are not good either
Like those corrupt officials who embezzled hundreds of millions
As they go further down that path
What does money mean to them?
They are officials themselves
He can't even spend it
Then it's no longer about specific desires
rather than a conceptulization of a thirst for numbers
When someone tries to bribe him
You should ask specifically
You embezzled this million
What are you going to do with it
What do you plan to do with this money
He doesn't know either
This turns into an abstract inertia.
Whether it's desire or fear that drives your motivation,
your drive becomes ineffective if it’s not concrete,
you’re more likely to be alienated,
you become a slave to some concept, right?
You’re not craving the material things money can buy,
you’re not aiming to improve your life,
you’re craving money itself,
and money becomes the subject.
And you become the object, right?
Or you don’t crave intimate relationships
You don’t crave companionship
You don’t crave the response from the person you love
You simply can’t accept yourself
The failure that not being able to get married implies
Then you become a slave to marriage
So neither desire nor fear is the issue
The issue is to be specific, not abstract
Don't abstract it
But unfortunately
the motivations of Chinese youth are indeed very prone to abstraction
we have to admit this
First, they are instilled from a young age in an extremely isolated environment
You must win
the notion that you must be exceptionally outstanding
It's hard to experience concrete happiness
concrete joy
Your motivation
has been almost entirely external from a young age
imposed on you
demanded of you
I mentioned this in my year-end reflection last year
many people end up as hollow individuals due to such experiences during their growth
becoming hollow people
I have real-life friends who are like this
I have a very close friend who
A male classmate I've been in touch with all along
He's been a top student from childhood to adulthood
After graduation, he got a pretty good job
But he's never been truly happy
He wants to change his environment
So
At 35, he applied to a school in the Netherlands and went abroad to study
Because his learning ability is really strong
He's actually a very capable person
So it was only natural that
he made it to the Netherlands without any issues
and in theory, his dream had come true
But when I spoke to him last year
he mentioned that he had achieved the top score in one of his courses
among all students from all countries
and his overall GPA was also among the top
However, even with that
he still felt that he wasn't good enough
Why
Because he didn't come first in every subject
I find this utterly absurd
So I asked him
I said, do you think this is fair?
Don't you find it absurd?
He said rationally he knows he did well enough
But rationality doesn't help
Because of the momentum he's always had
He just feels that he's not good enough
No matter what
As long as there's a better possibility
He feels that he's not good enough
He sees himself as inadequate
This is a deeply ingrained way of thinking
I know quite a few people like this
Sometimes I think these friends might be lucky
Because I've indeed been in key middle schools from a young age
They might just be lucky, my friends around me.
But they are all very capable.
And they do tend to achieve better outcomes.
These are the people who can manage to succeed.
So for them,
it's a cyclical process of self-doubt and self-affirmation,
this kind of loop.
But some people, when faced with such PUA,
might end up falling into complete darkness.
Abstract fear
is actually two sides of the same coin with abstract desire
I don't know what I want
What should we do then?
I can only want to win, right?
I want to win
So I also fear losing
I'm afraid I won't be able to win
I can't be someone worthy of everyone's approval
So I became worthless.
So at this point,
abstract desire and abstract fear are one and the same.
Another part is brought about by the internet media.
Abstract fear,
we are already overwhelmed with information.
the media amplifies,
amplifies too much information,
it gives you a lot of what seems like too many dark secrets.
Too many extreme cases
If young people don't have enough exposure to the real world
Without a counterbalance of information and understanding of society
The world in their eyes becomes a vast and mysterious
Dangerous
A deeply incomprehensible and unpredictable dark place
In such an environment
An ordinary person feels like a small boat in a storm
It seems like there's no way out no matter which path they take
No matter what choice we make, it seems to be the wrong one.
So let's look at it from the perspective of motivation.
The Dilemma of the New Generation
It's just like what we mentioned earlier.
Desires and fears have become abstract concepts.
There's a phrase I've been thinking about a lot lately.
Oh, this must be something a Bilibili UPloader often says.
And it has become a commonly used meme.
It's called 'a straight line turning into a dead end on both sides'.
Up and down
we shouldn’t be caught between a rock and a hard place
For young people
I think it’s quite realistic that a straightforward approach can lead to being blocked on both ends
Our generation
A new generation
Their biological instinct for survival pressure is almost gone
No matter whether you think society is good or bad
Whether you think your life is good or bad
But you have to admit
in such a society
in our country
it's not easy to starve to death, right?
What about those higher pursuits?
they're not so easy to attain
you can't quite reach them
these are two deer
and then let's talk about the growing environment
This sense of joy in living
This relaxation is ruined by the education system
It's destroyed by the environment from a young age
But the opportunity for upward social mobility, the chance to succeed
The opportunity to live better than others is rapidly shrinking
The odds of winning are decreasing
This is a double-edged sword
And from a historical perspective
The PUA tactics from pre-modern times haven't disappeared, right
There are still many people urging you to get married
Many tell you how to be a man
How can one become a woman?
These pre-modern notions haven't vanished
While the benefits and diversity of modern life are gradually shrinking
the sense of oppression and emptiness associated with modernity
The hypocrisy and nihilism are sweeping in
We have to face them
And they come in the form of abstract negative emotions
You don’t even know who to blame.
So this is a double-edged sword.
This is a convergence of pre-modern and modern elements.
Last year’s year-end observations.
I’ve also discussed similar structures.
But I can elaborate further.
Because it’s a core question of our time.
This mental framework.
I believe it will impact the spirit and vitality of a generation.
What does this kind of deadlock bring?
It brings a sense of constant unease,
a feeling of not knowing where one truly belongs,
who one really is,
where one stands,
and which path to take in life’s confusion.
It’s a state of being both chaotic and dispirited,
appearing chaotic on the surface,
but fundamentally disheartened in spirit.
I think the current generational conflict is between two or several generations
The conflict in the public opinion field is so intense.
they can hardly understand each other
and a significant reason for this is
the older generation
really can't grasp this kind of manic and depressive mental state
they can't understand this black hole in young people's hearts
this void
and the accompanying aimlessness
It feels really tough
because if you don't truly understand from the perspective of young people
if you don't really observe and immerse yourself in their lives
if you just look from the outside
of course, you might think they're just whining, right?
because the material conditions are indeed better
and the education is better too
but you guys still complain about more things
and the older generation might wonder what's really wrong with you
You don’t just come out and say it
and you don’t communicate with them properly
but what they don’t know is
it’s precisely because you can’t express it that it hurts
so when faced with such personal struggles
there are actually different choices people can make
some choose to just give up
if you don’t take action
action won’t go to waste, right?
If you don’t choose, will you never choose wrong?
You can’t face the problem.
The problem can be temporarily kept at bay, right?
It’s hard to say this is a rational and effective way of thinking.
But it does align with human nature.
It fits emotional patterns.
What’s another option?
Since I can’t obtain a value I can endorse,
I’ll destroy all value.
I deconstruct everything
I mock everything
I see through everything
I ridicule everything
I pretend as if I don't exist in this world
the things that matter and are worth pursuing
that's also a choice
then the other choice is even more dangerous
which is that I can't find any value
So I compensate with a sense of power
to fill the void of value
if you can't find value, seek power
So what is the most direct form of power?
Harming others is the most efficient way to prove one's strength
This is what I've mentioned
the psychological mechanism behind the community of hatred
And when we look back at history
We can also observe the changes in each cycle.
When society reaches a point where values become hollow,
it is also a time when the public desperately seeks a sense of power.
a sense of empowerment.
So we can see many phenomena in the public opinion field now.
Many hot topics, at their core,
are a mix of the three choices mentioned above.
Many issues are not about right or wrong,
nor are they about
The matter itself is about hunting games.
Everyone focuses on
issues that are almost devoid of public interest.
Using the majority's correctness to ostracize the minority.
And this minority isn't necessarily wrong.
They might just be unpopular.
Or they happen to represent
something that reflects widespread dissatisfaction.
I'm not talking about the 4+4 at Xiehe here.
Or the Shanxi case, such a hot topic
Such incidents are rare
Truly, some events have public value
Actually, there are many
What am I talking about?
I'm referring to whether He Classmate refused to give a positive review for a taxi ride
Fang Qi's disrespect towards Ye Tong
How Xiao Ming and his wife manage to live their lives with modeling
These kinds of trivial matters
This kind of thing happens in similar situations
People rely on moral judgments of others
on these targets of criticism
by shaming their character to inflict what they call righteous harm
and then by observing the harm being inflicted
seeing their fear or cries
or the cries of people from the other side
they achieve a kind of inner climax, right?
This climax, in their view, might be seen as punishing evil and promoting good
But how much is actually included in this?
I see the harm I cause.
So I exist.
So I have strength.
Such a highly damp positive feedback
I think there's quite a bit.
Sure.
You can interpret the above as my analysis of the situation.
Or a causal logic.
I admit it's a form of criticism
but if you happen to be the type mentioned
someone who compensates for a sense of value with a sense of power
how can I provide you with a solution?
offering a solution isn't easy
because the approach to avoid abstracting your motivation
seems pretty straightforward, right?
it's just a matter of saying it
it's about making yourself and your life more concrete
But it's not about having a certain attitude
It's about having a certain ability
You need to have something concrete
You need to have something tangible
You need to be sensitive enough
You need to have experienced truly great things
You need to see yourself and others
Only then can you become specific
And it's crucial
You need to have enough mental space
You need to have a kind of psychological energy
Only then can you live well
You can't be someone who is completely drained
Depleted and exhausted
Then, as mentioned in the video Bilibili released for Youth Day this year,
A very terrifying term
It refers to someone who has been erased
In such a state, you cannot be specific
So what should we do?
The solution I came up with might not be right.
Just try to be an unrefined egoist.
Or to put it more bluntly,
don't be too selfless.
Don't keep trying to meet others' expectations.
Don't keep trying to meet society's expectations.
Don't keep trying to meet your parents' expectations.
Don't keep condemning things in the name of justice.
To speak up for the weak
and constantly fight against what you perceive as
ugly social phenomena
I think what's more important is
you seem to be caught in this emotional storm
this storm of righteousness
when you have this urge to fight
then you're browsing Bilibili
or Douyin
While browsing Zhihu,
think about it,
what exactly have I gained from this process?
Don't just focus on the positive energy in society.
You focus on your positive energy
I believe in the face of such a historical cycle,
we should be more sparing with our emotions and how we expend them,
don’t force yourself to do things for others,
or to fight against so-called evil forces.
Stop suppressing what makes you unhappy
what angers you
what makes you feel helpless
the pain and confusion
but instead, stay away from them
stay away from these issues
think about what you really need
how to make yourself happier and more relaxed
at this level
meaningless entertainment
going overboard with absurdity
meaningless consumption are not issues
as long as they replenish you
nourish you
rather than drain you
I don't think it's really that hard to judge
after you do these things
are you more exhausted
more empty
more sleepless
unable to sleep
more numb
or do you feel some satisfaction
more energized
you sleep better
your mind is more active
and you are more perceptive of yourself and others
I think we can actually feel it
if you really want to feel it
So my answer is that this world might not be all that great.
but we should be kinder to ourselves
be kinder to yourself
so you can be kinder to society
so you can create a positive feedback loop
take better care of yourself
worry less about trivial matters
because humans are very limited beings
our emotions
our attention
our goodwill are all very limited
Then, make sure to leave more space for your mental world.
so you can accommodate real people
and the real world
otherwise, everything becomes abstract concern
otherwise, your motivation system will become abstract
and your concern will become abstract
the road to hell
is paved with such abstract goodwill
I quite like a phrase that has been often repeated in recent years
it's called respecting others' destinies
letting go of the savior complex
So, at the end of this video
I wish all the young people could truly see their concrete selves
thanks a lot, everyone
wish you a happy holiday
friends
we believe that the hardships of 100 years ago have not been erased
Chinese youth
Chinese youth will never be erased by anxiety